<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Aeropedia</string>
    <string name="manufacturers">Aircraft Gallery</string>
    <string name="ask_alexa">Ask Alexa</string>
    <string name="flight_tracker">Flight Tracker</string>
    <string name="firebase">Community</string>
    <string name="airbus">Airbus</string>
    <string name="boeing">Boeing</string>
    <string name="embraer">Embraer</string>
    <string name="bombardier">Bombardier</string>
    <string name="cessna">Cessna</string>
    <string name="gulfstream">Gulfstream</string>
    <string name="antonov">Antonov</string>
    <string name="a350">A350</string>
    <string name="a380">A380</string>
    <string name="a320">A320</string>
    <string name="a319">A319</string>
    <string name="a318">A318</string>
    <string name="a300">A300</string>
    <string name="a310">A310</string>
    <string name="a340">A340</string>
    <string name="a321">A321</string>
    <string name="a330">A330</string>
    <string name="a330neo">A330neo</string>
    <string name="a320neofamily">A320neo Family</string>
    <string name="a220">A220</string>
    <string name="beluga">Beluga</string>
    <string name="an124">An-124 Ruslan</string>
    <string name="an72">An-72 Cheburashka</string>
    <string name="an22">An-22 Antei</string>
    <string name="an225">An-225 Mriya</string>
    <string name="b787">787</string>
    <string name="b737">737</string>
    <string name="b757">757</string>
    <string name="b747">747</string>
    <string name="b767">767</string>
    <string name="b777">777</string>
    <string name="learjet75">Learjet 75</string>
    <string name="challenger650">Challenger 650</string>
    <string name="global7500">Global 7500</string>
    <string name="crj_100_200">CRJ100/200</string>
    <string name="erj_family">ERJ Family</string>
    <string name="ejet_e2_family">E-Jet E2 Family</string>
    <string name="lineage1000">Lineage 1000</string>
    <string name="phenom300">Phenom 300</string>
    <string name="citation_longitude">Citation Longtitude</string>
    <string name="citation_latitude">Citation Latitude</string>
    <string name="caravan">208 Caravan</string>
    <string name="skylane">182 Skylane</string>
    <string name="g650">G650</string>
    <string name="g280">G280</string>
    <string name="gulfstream_iv">G-IV</string>
    <string name="language"><b>FR</b></string>


    <!--BASICS-->
    <string name="type">Type</string>
    <string name="engine">Engine</string>
    <string name="first_flight">First flight</string>
    <string name="intro">Introduction</string>
    <string name="customer">Largest operator</string>
    <string name="variants">Variants</string>

    <string name="specs">Specifications</string>
    <string name="cockpit_crew">Cockpit crew</string>
    <string name="wingspan">Wing span</string>
    <string name="length">Length</string>
    <string name="height">Height</string>
    <string name="fuselage">Fuselage</string>
    <string name="cabin">Cabin</string>
    <string name="gross_weight">Gross weight</string>
    <string name="mtow">Max. take-off weight</string>
    <string name="cruise_speed">Cruise speed</string>
    <string name="range">Range</string>
    <string name="thrust1">Thrust (1x)</string>
    <string name="thrust2">Thrust (2x)</string>
    <string name="thrust4">Thrust (4x)</string>
    <string name="thrust6">Thrust (6x)</string>
    <string name="propellers">Propellers</string>
    <string name="numbers">Numbers built</string>
    <string name="shaft_horse_power">Shaft Horse Power</string>
    <!--BASICS-->

    <!--AIRBUS A350-->
    <string name="a350_type_value">Wide-body\nairliner</string>
    <string name="a350_engine_value">Rolls-Royce Trent XWB (2)</string>
    <string name="a350_first_flight_value">14 June 2013</string>
    <string name="a350_intro_value">15 January 2015\nwith Qatar Airways</string>
    <string name="a350_customer_value">Singapore Airlines</string>
    <string name="a350_variants_value">2 (active)</string>


    <string name="a350_desc1" formatted="false">The Airbus A350 is a long-range, wide-body jet airliner. The first A350 design proposed by Airbus in 2004,
        in response to Boeing\'s 787 Dreamliner, would have been a development of the A330 (hence A330-Lite) with composite wings and new engines. However,
        market support was inadequate at the time and in 2006, Airbus switched to a clean-sheet XWB (eXtra Wide Body) design, powered by Rolls-Royce Trent XWB
        turbofan engines. The A350 is the first aircraft of the Airbus family that is largely made of carbon fibre reinforced polymer. It features a new fuselage designed around a
        nine-abreast economy cross-section, up from the eight-abreast A330/A340. The A350 has been in production since 2010 and in total 425 A350s have been built as of
        31 May 2021.\n\nThe A350 XWB airframe is made out of 53% composites: carbon fibre reinforced plastic for the outer and centre wing box (covers, stringers, spars),
        fuselage (skin, frame, keel beam, and rear fuselage) and the empennage (horizontal and vertical tailplanes); 19% aluminium and aluminium–lithium alloy for ribs,
        floor beams, and gear bays; 14% titanium for landing gears, pylons, and attachments; 6% steel; and 8% miscellaneous. For the wings, those mark a 31.9° sweep angle for a
        Mach 0.85 cruise speed and has a maximum operating speed of Mach 0.89, with the wingtip device curving upwards over the final 4.4 m (14 ft) - reducing air resistance and
        subsequently increasing the aircraft’s range whilst restricting fuel consumption to minimum.\n</string>

    <string name="a350_desc2" formatted="false">For the deck and avionics design,
        the design strategy for Airbus\' own A380 was used as a base. The focus of the company was to evolve technology for A350 further than the advances already made
        by the A380. It is one of three aircraft to feature avionics manufacturer Honeywell\’s Aircraft Environmental Surveillance System (AESS) which integrates weather, traffic and
        terrain awareness capabilities reducing as many as eight avionics boxes down to just two. It also features On-Board Airport Navigation System (OANS) which first debuted with
        the A380. This system provides real-time directions around airports and improves navigation on the ground. The system is especially useful in poor visibility conditions
        and helps to reduce errors in airport navigation by warning the pilots if they are going the wrong way. To help the pilots further, Airbus equipped the aircraft
        with External and Taxiing Aid Camera System (ETACS) for better navigation and aircraft positioning on the ground. digital cameras provide the pilots with views
        from outside with one positioned behind the nose wheel and the other in the vertical tail. The views from the cameras can be displayed in the A350 cockpit on displays
        and as well as on the passenger in-flight entertainment screens.\n\nThe Airbus A350 consumes 25% less fuel and emits 25% less emissions than previous generations and according to Airbus it is the quietest two aisle plane
        on the planet. Australia\'s Qantas chose A350 over Boeing\'s 787 Dreamliner for \"Project Sunrise\" – a codename for proposed nonstop flights between Australia
        and several international destinations that include London, New York and Paris.\n
    </string>

    <string name="a350_desc3">\nAirbus A350\'s variants include A350-800, A350-900, A350-ULR, ACJ350, A350 Regional, A350-950 F, A350-1000, although some of
        these were discontinued or did not make it past the early stages.\n</string>

    <string name="a350_specs_constraint">(-900 and -1000 variants compared in order)\n</string>

    <string name="a350_wingspan_value">64.75 m</string>
    <string name="a350_length_value">66.8 / 73.79 m</string>
    <string name="a350_height_value">17.05 / 17.08 m</string>
    <string name="a350_fuselage_value">5.96 m (W) / 6.09 m (H)</string>
    <string name="a350_mtow_value">280 / 316 t</string>
    <string name="a350_cruise_speed_value">903 km/h (typical),\n950 km/h (max.)</string>
    <string name="a350_range_value">8100 / 8700 nmi</string>
    <string name="a350_thrust_value">374.5 / 431.5 kN</string>

    <string name="a350_identify">How to identify Airbus A350?</string>
    <string name="a350_identify_ans">The unique 6-piece round-edged windscreen configuration with black border, distinctive nose, smoothly curved sharklets like those on A330neo.</string>
    <!--AIRBUS A350-->

    <!--AIRBUS A380-->
    <string name="a380_type_value">Wide-body\nairliner</string>
    <string name="a380_engine_value">Rolls-Royce Trent 900 (4) /\nEngine Alliance GP7000(4)</string>
    <string name="a380_first_flight_value">27 April 2005</string>
    <string name="a380_intro_value">25 October 2007\nwith Singapore Airlines</string>
    <string name="a380_customer_value">Emirates</string>
    <string name="a380_variants_value">4 (active)</string>

    <string name="a380_desc1" formatted="false">The Airbus A380 is the world\'s largest passenger airliner. Airbus studies started in 1988, and the project was announced in
        1990 to challenge the dominance of the Boeing 747 in the long haul market. The then-designated A3XX project was presented in 1994. Airbus launched
        the €9.5 billion ($10.7 billion) A380 programme on 19 December 2000. As of 31 December 2020, 246 A380s have been built, most of which went to
        the fleet family of Emirates. The aircraft still remains in service for many airlines but is no longer in production on Airbus\' side.\n\nThe A380\'s upper and
        lower decks are connected by two stairways, one fore and one aft, with both being wide enough to accommodate two passengers side by side. This cabin arrangement
        allows multiple seat configurations. The maximum certified carrying capacity is 853 passengers in an all-economy-class layout, Airbus lists the \"typical\"
        three-class layout as accommodating 525 passengers, with 10 first, 76 business, and 439 economy class seats. Airline configurations range from Korean Air\'s
        407 passengers to Emirates\' two-class 615 seats and average around 480–490 seats.
        \n\nWhile most of
        the fuselage is made of aluminium alloys, composite materials comprise more than 20% of the A380\'s airframe. Carbon-fibre reinforced plastic, glass-fibre
        reinforced plastic and quartz-fibre reinforced plastic are used extensively in wings, fuselage sections (such as the undercarriage and rear end of fuselage),
        tail surfaces, and doors. The A380, often nicknamed the superjumbo, is the first commercial airliner to have a central wing box made of carbon–fibre reinforced plastic. It is
        also the first to have a smoothly contoured wing cross–section. The wings of other commercial airliners are partitioned span-wise into sections. This flowing
        continuous cross section reduces aerodynamic drag. Thermoplastics are used in the leading edges of the slats. The hybrid fibre metal laminate material GLARE
        (glass laminate aluminium reinforced epoxy) is used in the upper fuselage and on the stabilisers\' leading edges. This aluminium-glass-fibre laminate is
        lighter and has better corrosion and impact resistance than conventional aluminium alloys used in aviation. Unlike earlier composite materials, GLARE can be
        repaired using conventional aluminium repair techniques.\n</string>

    <string name="a380_desc2" formatted="false">Due to its modern engines and aerodynamic improvements, Lufthansa\'s A380s produce half the noise of the
        Boeing 747-200 while carrying 160 more passengers. In 2012, the A380 received an award from the Noise Abatement Society.The A380 employs an integrated
        modular avionics (IMA) architecture, first used in advanced military aircraft, such as the Lockheed Martin F-22 Raptor, Lockheed Martin F-35 Lightning II,
        and Dassault Rafale. Designed and developed by Airbus, Thales and Diehl Aerospace, the IMA suite was first used on the A380. The suite is a technological
        innovation, with networked computing modules to support different applications.The data networks use Avionics Full-Duplex Switched Ethernet. These are switched,
        full-duplex, star-topology and based on 100baseTX fast-Ethernet. This reduces the amount of wiring required and minimises latency.\n\nThe Network Systems Server (NSS) is
        the heart of A380\'s paperless cockpit; it eliminates bulky manuals and traditional charts. The NSS has enough inbuilt robustness to eliminate onboard backup
        paper documents. The A380s network and server system stores data and offers electronic documentation, providing a required equipment list, navigation charts,
        performance calculations, and an aircraft logbook.\n\nIn February 2019, Airbus announced it would end A380 production by 2021, after its main customer,
        Emirates, agreed to drop an order for 39 of the aircraft, replacing it with 40 A330-900s and 30 A350-900s. At the time of the announcement, Airbus had 17
        more A380s on its order book to complete before closing the production line – 14 for Emirates and 3 for All Nippon Airways – taking the total number of
        expected deliveries of the aircraft type to 251.\n
    </string>

    <string name="a380_desc3">\nAirbus A380\'s active variants include A380-800, A380-841, A380-842, A380-861. Airbus also proposed a handful of new variants that included
    a cargo variant of the A380, the A380F. The freighter would have been a rival for Boeing 747 and Antonov An-225 Mriya. A380F was postponed after 2005 and was
        never built. Other proposed variants included A380plus, A380neo, A380 Stretch with improvements regarding efficiency, capacity, and engine tweaks.\n</string>

    <string name="a380_specs_constraint">(-800, Trent engines)\n</string>

    <string name="a380_identify">How to identify Airbus A380?</string>
    <string name="a380_identify_ans">A380 is an aircraft that is easily recognizable. The characteristic ovoid fuselage, 4 engines, distinctive "bulbous" nose, and of course,
        2 passenger decks stretching across the length of the fuselage.</string>

    <string name="a380_cockpit_value">2</string>
    <string name="a380_wingspan_value">79.75 m</string>
    <string name="a380_length_value">72.72 m</string>
    <string name="a380_height_value">24.09 m</string>
    <string name="a380_fuselage_value">7.1 m (W) / ~7.3 m (H)</string>
    <string name="a380_mtow_value">575 t</string>
    <string name="a380_cruise_speed_value">903 km/h (typical),\n945 km/h (max.)</string>
    <string name="a380_range_value">8,000 nmi</string>
    <string name="a380_thrust_value">348 kN</string>
    <!--AIRBUS A380-->

    <!--AIRBUS A340-->
    <string name="a340_type_value">Wide-body\nairliner</string>
    <string name="a340_engine_value">CFM56-5C /\nRR Trent 553/556 (4)</string>
    <string name="a340_first_flight_value">25 October 1991</string>
    <string name="a340_intro_value">15 March 1993 with\nLufthansa &amp; Air France</string>
    <string name="a340_customer_value">Lufthansa</string>
    <string name="a340_variants_value">4</string>

    <string name="a340_desc1" formatted="false">In the mid-1970s, Airbus conceived several derivatives of the A300, its first airliner, and developed the A340 quadjet
        in parallel with the A330 twinjet. Keeping the eight-abreast economy cross-section of the A300, the early A340-200/300 has a similar airframe to the A330.
        Differences include four 151 kN CFM56s instead of two high-thrust turbofans to bypass ETOPS restrictions on trans-oceanic routes, and a three-leg
        main landing gear instead of two for a heavier 276 t MTOW. Both airliners have fly-by-wire controls, which was first introduced on the A320, as well
        as a similar glass cockpit. A total of 380 A340s have been built before its production ended in 2011.\n\nIts features and improvements were usually shared with the A330.
        The four engines configuration avoided the ETOPS constraints such as more frequent inspections. The A340 has a low cantilever wing; the A340-200/300 wing is virtually
        identical to that of the A330, with both engine pylons used while only the inboard one is used on the A330. The two engines for each wing provide a more distributed
        weight; and a more outboard engine weight for a lower wing root bending moment at equal TOW, allowing a higher wing limited MTOW for more range. The wings were
        designed and manufactured by BAe, which developed a long slender wing with a high aspect ratio for a higher aerodynamic efficiency. The wing is swept back at
        30 degrees, allowing a maximum operating Mach number of 0.86. To reach a long span and high aspect ratio without a large weight penalty, the wing has
        relatively high Thickness-to-chord ratio of 11.8% or 12.8%. Each wing also has a 2.74 m tall winglet instead of the wingtip fences found on earlier Airbus aircraft. The failure
        of the ultra-high-bypass IAE SuperFan, promising around 15% better fuel burn, led to wing upgrades to compensate. Originally designed with a 56 m
        span, the wing was later extended to 58.6 m and finally to 60.3 m. This wingspan is similar to that of the larger Boeing 747-200, but with
        35% less wing area.\n</string>

    <string name="a340_desc2" formatted="false">The A340 uses a modified A320 glass cockpit, with side-stick controls instead of a conventional yoke. The main instrument
        panel is dominated by six displays, cathode ray tube monitors initially then liquid crystal displays. Flight information is directed via the Electronic Flight
        Instrument System (EFIS) and systems information through the Electronic Centralised Aircraft Monitor (ECAM). The aircraft monitors various sensors and
        automatically alerts the crew to any parameters outside of their normal range; pilots can also inspect individual systems. Electronic manuals are used
        instead of paper ones, with optional web-based updates. Maintenance difficulty and cost were reduced to half of that of the earlier and smaller Airbus A310.
        Improved engine control and monitoring improved time on wing. The centralised maintenance computer can transmit real-time information to ground facilities via
        the onboard satellite-based ACARS datalink. Heavy maintenance like structural changes remained unchanged, while cabin sophistications, like the in-flight
        entertainment, were increased over preceding airliners.\n\nOn 16 June 1993, an A340-200 dubbed the World Ranger flew from the Paris Air Show to Auckland,
        New Zealand in 21 hours 32 minutes and back in 21 hours 46 minutes after a five-hour stop; this was the first non-stop flight between Europe and New Zealand
        and the longest non-stop flight by an airliner at the time. The 19,277 km (10,409 nmi) flight from Paris to Auckland broke six world records with 22 persons
        and five center tanks. Taking off at 11:58 local time, it arrived back in Paris 48 hours and 22 minutes later, at 12:20. This record held until
        1997 when a Boeing 777-200ER flew 20,044 km (10,823 nmi) from Seattle to Kuala Lumpur. The McDonnell Douglas MD-11 and the Boeing 777 were
        its main competitors. The A340 was coping up well with its competitors and in some cases, even better as Singapore Airlines cancelled its 20-aircraft MD-11
        order on 2 August 1991, and ordered 20 A340-300s instead. However, as improving engine reliability allowed ETOPS operations for almost all routes,
        more economical twin-jets have replaced quad-jets on many routes. On 10 November 2011, Airbus announced that the production reached its end, after 380
        orders had been placed and 377 delivered from Toulouse, France. Later, the A350 XWB was announced its successor.\n</string>

    <string name="a340_desc3">\nAirbus A340\'s variants include A340-200, A340-300, A340-500, A340-600. The -600 variant is the longest in the A340 family. It is even
        longer than most Boeing 747s and the A380.\n</string>

    <string name="a340_specs_constraint">(-200, -300, -500, -600 variants compared in order)\n</string>

    <string name="a340_identify">How to identify Airbus A340?</string>
    <string name="a340_identify_ans">The A340 is one of the few quad-jets in the world. The single passenger deck stretching the length of the fuselage with
        4 engines, centre-line wheel bogie, wings with straight, sharp-angled, short wingtips like A330\'s should catch the eyes of most aviation enthusiasts.</string>

    <string name="a340_cockpit_value">2</string>
    <string name="a340_wingspan_value">60.3 m (-200 &amp; -300) /\n63.45 m (-500 &amp; -600)</string>
    <string name="a340_length_value">59.39 / 63.69 /\n67.93 / 75.36 m</string>
    <string name="a340_height_value">17.03 / 16.99 /\n17.53 / 17.93 m</string>
    <string name="a340_fuselage_value">5.64 m (W) / ~5.7 m (H)</string>
    <string name="a340_mtow_value">275 t (-200) / 276.5 t (-300) / 380 t (-500 &amp; -600)</string>
    <string name="a340_cruise_speed_value">871 km/h (typical),\n914 km/h (max.)</string>
    <string name="a340_range_value">6,700 / 7,300 / 9,000 / 7,800 nmi</string>
    <string name="a340_thrust_value">138.78–151.24 kN\n(-200 &amp; -300) /\n248.12–275.35 kN\n(-500 &amp; -600)</string>
    <!--AIRBUS A340-->

    <!--AIRBUS A330-->
    <string name="a330_type_value">Wide-body\nairliner</string>
    <string name="a330_engine_value">GE CF6 /\nPratt &amp; Whitney PW4000 /\nRR Trent 700 (2)</string>
    <string name="a330_first_flight_value">2 November 1992</string>
    <string name="a330_intro_value">17 January 1994\nwith Air Inter</string>
    <string name="a330_customer_value">Turkish Airlines</string>
    <string name="a330_variants_value">11 (active)</string>

    <string name="a330_desc1" formatted="false">Airbus began development on the A330 (now known as A330ceo - \"ceo\" for \"Current Engine Option\" - after the introduction of A330neo - \"neo\" for "New Engine Option" in 2014) twin-jet in parallel with the A340 quad-jet and launched both designs with their first
        orders in June 1987. The A330 shares its airframe with the early A340 variants, having two main landing gear legs instead of three, lower weights, and slightly
        different lengths. Both airliners have fly-by-wire controls as well as a similar glass cockpit to increase the commonality. The A330 was Airbus\'s first
        airliner to offer a choice of three engines: the General Electric CF6, Pratt &amp; Whitney PW4000, or the Rolls-Royce Trent 700. The A330 was the
        first Airbus aircraft for which Rolls-Royce supplied engines. It is the third most delivered wide-body airliner after the Boeing 777 and Boeing 747. As of 30 June 2021,
        1518 A330s have been built and this figure will continue to increase as the aircraft is still in production.\n\nThe A330 is a medium-size, wide-body aircraft,
        with two engines suspended on pylons under the wings. A two-wheel nose undercarriage and two four-wheel bogie main legs built by Messier-Dowty support the
        aeroplane on the ground. The airframe of the A330 features a low-wing lever monoplane with a wing virtually identical to that of the A340-200/300. On the
        A330-300, one engine is installed at the inboard pylon while the outboard pylon position is not used; for the A340-300, both engine pylons are used, which
        allows the A340-300 wing to sustain a higher (wing limited) MTOW. This is as the A340\'s two engines at each wing provide a more equal force distribution
        (engine weight) over the wing, while also the total engine weight counteracting moment is located more outboard with more engine weight located further
        outboard on the wing, hence the wing root bending moment with equal TOW is less on the A340-300 than on the A330-300. The wings were designed and manufactured
        by BAe, which developed a long slender wing with a very high aspect ratio to provide high aerodynamic efficiency. The wing is swept back at 30 degrees and,
        along with other design features, allows a maximum operating Mach number of 0.86.\n</string>

    <string name="a330_desc2" formatted="false">The A330 and A340 fuselage is based on that of the Airbus A300-600, with many common parts, and has the same external
        and cabin width: 5.64 m and 5.26 m. Typical seating arrangements are 2–2–2 six-abreast in business class and 2–4–2 eight-abreast in economy class. The fin, rudder,
        elevators, horizontal tail plane are used as fuel tank, flaps, ailerons and spoilers; they are made of composite materials, making 10% of the structure weight.
        When necessary, the A330 uses the Honeywell 331–350C auxiliary power unit (APU) to provide pneumatics and electrical power.\n\nThe A330 shares the same glass
        cockpit flight deck layout as the A320 and the A340, featuring electronic instrument
        displays rather than mechanical gauges. Instead of a conventional control yoke, the flight deck features side-stick controls, six main displays, and the
        Electronic Flight Instrument System (EFIS), which covers navigation and flight displays, as well as the Electronic Centralised Aircraft Monitor (ECAM).
        Apart from the flight deck, the A330 also has the fly-by-wire system common to the A320 family, the A340, the A350, and the A380. It also features three
        primary and two secondary flight control systems, as well as a flight envelope limit protection system which prevents maneuvers from exceeding the aircraft\'s
        aerodynamic and structural limits.\n</string>


    <string name="a330_desc3">\nAirbus A330\'s variants include A330-300, A330-300HGW, A330 Regional, A330-200, A330-200F, A330P2F, A330neo equipped with new engines, Beluga XL (large cargo freighter), ACJ330 (corporate jet),
        Airbus A330 MRTT and EADS/Northrop Grumman KC-45 (military jets). Many other variants
    such as A330-400/600, A330-100/-500, A330-200Lite were proposed. However, in the end these variants did not make it into the production phase.\n</string>

    <string name="a330_specs_constraint">(-200, -200F, and -300 variants compared in order)\n</string>


    <string name="a330_identify">How to identify Airbus A330?</string>
    <string name="a330_identify_ans">Bulged central section of the lower fuselage, 2 engines attached to wings with straight, sharp-angled, short wingtips like A340\'s.</string>

    <string name="a330_cockpit_value">2</string>
    <string name="a330_wingspan_value">60.3 m</string>
    <string name="a330_length_value">58.82 m (-200 &amp; -200F) / 63.67 m (-300)</string>
    <string name="a330_height_value">17.39 / 16.9 / 16.79 m</string>
    <string name="a330_fuselage_value">5.64 m (W) / ~5.7 m (H)</string>
    <string name="a330_mtow_value">242 / 233 / 242 t</string>
    <string name="a330_cruise_speed_value">871 km/h (typical)</string>
    <string name="a330_range_value">7,250 / 4,000 / 6,350 nmi</string>
    <string name="a330_thrust_value">287–316 kN</string>
    <!--AIRBUS A330-->


    <!--AIRBUS A330neo-->
    <string name="a330neo_type_value">Wide-body\nairliner</string>
    <string name="a330neo_engine_value">Rolls-Royce Trent 7000 (2)</string>
    <string name="a330neo_first_flight_value">19 October 2017</string>
    <string name="a330neo_intro_value">15 December 2018\nwith TAP Air Portugal</string>
    <string name="a330neo_customer_value">TAP Air Portugal</string>
    <string name="a330neo_variants_value">2</string>

    <string name="a330neo_desc1" formatted="false">The A330neo, \"neo\" for "New Engine Option", is a development comprising A330-800/900 from the initial A330 (-200/200F freighter/300/MRTT military tanker), now A330ceo — \"Current Engine Option\". A new
        version with modern engines developed for the Boeing 787 was called for by owners of the current A330. It was launched in July 2014 at the Farnborough Airshow,
        promising 14% better fuel economy per seat, thanks to Airbus\' decision that lead to the aircraft being exclusively powered by the Rolls-Royce Trent 7000 (as opposed to Trent 700 of A330ceo) with double bypass ratio, as opposed to its predecessor and other aerodynamic improvements including
        A350 inspired sharklets. Its two versions are based on the A330-200 and -300: Its two versions are based on the A330-200 and -300: the -800 has a range of 8,150 nmi
        (15,090 km) with 257 passengers while the -900 covers 7,200 nmi (13,330 km) with 287 passengers. The -900 made its maiden flight on 19 October 2017 and received its EASA type certificate on 26 September 2018; it was first delivered to TAP
        Air Portugal on 26 November 2018 and entered service on 15 December. The -800 made its first flight on 6 November 2018 and received EASA type certification on 13
        February 2020; the first two -800s were delivered to Kuwait Airways on 29 October 2020. As of 30 June 2021, 63 A330neos have been built.\n</string>

    <string name="a330neo_desc2" formatted="false">The larger 112-inch Trent 7000 is 11% more efficient than the 97.5-inch Trent 700 engine, with a 2% loss due to
        increased weight and 1% due to additional drag from the larger engine, but the sharklets and aero optimization regains 4% for a 12% fuel advantage per trip.
        Furthermore, fuel consumption per seat is improved by 2% due to the rearranged cabin (Space-Flex and Smart-Lav) with increased seating, offering a 14% fuel
        burn reduction per seat for the new −900 compared to the previous 235-tonne −300 version.\n\nThe A330neo offers a distinctive cockpit windscreen, similar to that on the A350, and a new interior concept focusing on
        better passenger experience. Since the fan is enlarged from 250 to 280 cm, the nacelles are mounted higher, necessitating extensive
        CFD (Computational Fluid Dynamics) analysis to avoid supersonic shock wave interference drag, as is the first slat\'s dog-tooth. The wing twist and belly fairings are tweaked to
        approach the lowest drag elliptical span-wise pressure distribution changed by the larger sharklets, like the flap track fairings shape to lower form drag.\n\nAs
        far the as the engine is concerned, the Rolls-Royce Trent 7000 is an electronic controlled bleed air variant of the Trent
        1000 used on the Boeing 787-10. It has a 284 cm diameter fan and a 10:1 bypass ratio delivering a thrust of 300 to 320 kN. The decision to offer the aircraft with only one engine option is not unique to Airbus; the Boeing 777X is also expected to come equipped
        exclusively with General Electric GE9X engines.\n</string>


    <string name="a330neo_desc3">\nThe A330neo is comprised of 2 variants, the A330-800 and the A330-900.\n</string>

    <string name="a330neo_specs_constraint">(-800 and -900 variants compared in order)\n</string>


    <string name="a330neo_identify">How to identify Airbus A330neo?</string>
    <string name="a330neo_identify_ans">The A330neo has a different 6-piece window design, with black border (\‘raccoon\’ style) and has bulged central section of the lower fuselage. It
        also has smoothly curved wing-tips, often referred to as sharklets, similar to those on the A350 but with less curvature.</string>

    <string name="a330neo_cockpit_value">2</string>
    <string name="a330neo_wingspan_value">64 m</string>
    <string name="a330neo_length_value">58.82 / 63.66 m</string>
    <string name="a330neo_height_value">17.39 / 16.79 m</string>
    <string name="a330neo_fuselage_value">5.64 m (W) / ~5.7 m (H)</string>
    <string name="a330neo_mtow_value">251 t</string>
    <string name="a330neo_cruise_speed_value">918 km/h (max.)</string>
    <string name="a330neo_range_value">8,150 / 7,200 nmi</string>
    <string name="a330neo_thrust_value">324 kN</string>
    <!--AIRBUS A330neo-->


    <!--AIRBUS A321-->
    <string name="a321_type_value">Narrow-body\nairliner</string>
    <string name="a321_engine_value">CFM56 /\nIAE V2500 (2)</string>
    <string name="a321_first_flight_value">11 March 1993</string>
    <string name="a321_intro_value">1994 with\nLufthansa</string>
    <string name="a321_customer_value">American Airlines</string>
    <string name="a321_variants_value">3</string>

    <string name="a321_desc1" formatted="false">The Airbus A321 is a member of the Airbus A320 family of short to medium range, narrow-body, commercial passenger
        twin engine jet airliners. This Airbus A320 family was renamed to A320ceo, for \"current engine option\" after the introduction of A320neo (neo for new engine option) in 2014. It has a stretched fuselage which was the first derivative of the baseline A320 and entered service in 1994 about six years after
        the original A320. The aircraft shares a common type rating with all other Airbus A320-family variants, allowing previous A320-family pilots to fly the aircraft
        without the need for further training. As of 30 June 2021, 2,340 A321s have been built.\n\nThe Airbus A321 was the first derivative of the A320, also known
        as the Stretched A320, A320-500 and A325. Its launch came on 24 November 1988, around the same time as the A320 entered service, after commitments for 183
        aircraft from 10 customers were secured. The maiden flight of the Airbus A321 came on 11 March 1993, when the prototype, registration F-WWIA, flew with IAE
        V2500 engines; the second prototype, equipped with CFM56-5B turbofans, flew in May 1993. Lufthansa and Alitalia were the first to order the stretched
        Airbuses, with 20 and 40 aircraft requested, respectively. The first of Lufthansa\'s V2500-A5-powered A321s arrived on 27 January 1994, while Alitalia
        received its first CFM56-5B-powered aircraft on 22 March 1994. The A321-100 entered service in January 1994 with Lufthansa.\n</string>

    <string name="a321_desc2" formatted="false">A321 is the largest variant of the A320 family. The A321-200\'s length exceeds 44.5m, increasing maximum takeoff
        weight to 93,000 kg. Wingspan remained unchanged, supplementing various wingtip devices. Two suppliers provided turbofan engines for the A321:
        CFM International with its CFM56 and International Aero Engines with the V2500 engine, both in the thrust range of 133–147 kN. Over 30
        years since launch, the A321 Maximum takeoff weight (MTOW) grew by 20% from the 83t -100 until the 101t A321XLR, seating is 10% more dense with 244 seats,
        up by 24, and range doubled from 2,300 nmi to 4,700 nmi. By 2019, 4,200 have been ordered—one-quarter of all Airbus single-aisles—including 2,400 neos,
        one-third of all A320neo orders.\n\nThe narrow-body (single-aisle) aircraft from Airbus is a low-wing cantilever monoplane with a conventional tail unit having a single vertical stabilizer and rudder.
        Changes from the A320 include a fuselage stretch and some modifications to the wing. The fuselage was lengthened by a 4.27 m plug ahead of the wing and a
        2.67 m plug behind it, so that the A321 is 6.94 metres longer than the A320. The length increase required the overwing window exits of the A320 to be
        converted into door exits and repositioned in front of and behind the wings. To maintain performance, double-slotted flaps and minor trailing edge
        modifications were included, increasing the wing area from 124 m<sup><small><small>2</small></small></sup> to 128 m<sup><small><small>2</small></small></sup>. The centre fuselage and undercarriage were
        reinforced to accommodate the increase in maximum takeoff weight of 9,600 kg, taking it to 83,000 kg.\n</string>


    <string name="a321_desc3">\nAirbus A321 variants include A321-100, A321-200 and A321neo equipped with new engines.\n</string>

    <string name="a321_specs_constraint">(-100 and -200 variants compared in order)\n</string>


    <string name="a321_identify">How to identify Airbus A321?</string>
    <string name="a321_identify_ans">\"Notched\" window design, \"bulbous\" nose, 2 dual-wheel main landing gears, engine nacelle with no trailing extensions,
        4 exits spread evenly across the fuselage, and either small triangular wingtips (wingtip fence) similar to those on A380 or large L-shaped sharklets.</string>

    <string name="a321_cockpit_value">2</string>
    <string name="a321_wingspan_value">35.80 m</string>
    <string name="a321_length_value">44.51 m</string>
    <string name="a321_height_value">11.76 m</string>
    <string name="a321_fuselage_value">3.95 m (W) / 4.14 m (H)</string>
    <string name="a321_mtow_value">83 / 93.5 t</string>
    <string name="a321_cruise_speed_value">829 km/h (typical),\n871 km/h (max.)</string>
    <string name="a321_range_value">2,350 / 3,200 nmi</string>
    <string name="a321_thrust_value">133–147 kN</string>
    <!--AIRBUS A321-->


    <!--AIRBUS A320-->
    <string name="a320_type_value">Narrow-body\nairliner</string>
    <string name="a320_engine_value">CFM56 /\nIAE V2500 (2)</string>
    <string name="a320_first_flight_value">22 February 1987</string>
    <string name="a320_intro_value">18 April 1988\nwith Air France</string>
    <string name="a320_customer_value">China Eastern Airlines</string>
    <string name="a320_variants_value">2</string>

    <string name="a320_desc1" formatted="false">The Airbus A320 is a member of the Airbus A320 family of short to medium range, narrow-body, commercial passenger
        twin engine jet airliners. This Airbus A320 family was renamed to A320ceo, for \"current engine option\" after the introduction of A320neo (neo for new engine option) in 2014.
        It is a narrow-body (single-aisle) aircraft with a retractable tricycle landing gear and are powered by two wing pylon-mounted turbofan engines. After the oil
        price rises of the 1970s, Airbus needed to minimise the trip fuel costs of the A320. To that end, it adopted composite primary structures, centre-of-gravity
        control using fuel, glass cockpit (Electronic Flight Instrument System, EFIS) and a two-crew flight deck. Airbus claimed the 737-300 burns 35% more fuel and has a 16% higher operating cost per
        seat than the V2500-powered A320. A 150-seat A320 burns 11,608 kg of jet fuel over 3,984 km (2,151 nmi) (between Los Angeles and New York City),
        or 2.43 L/100 km per seat with a 0.8 kg/L fuel. Its wing is long and thin, offering better aerodynamic efficiency because of the higher aspect
        ratio than the competing 737 and MD-80.\n\nThe A320 is a low-wing cantilever monoplane with a conventional empennage with a single vertical stabilizer and
        rudder. Its wing sweep is 25 degrees. Compared to other airliners of the same class, the A320 features a wider single-aisle cabin of 3.95 metres
        outside diameter, compared to 3.8 m of the Boeing 737 or 757, and larger overhead bins. The A320 airframe includes composite materials and aluminium
        alloys to save weight and reduce the total number of parts to decrease the maintenance costs. Its tail assembly is made almost entirely of such composites by
        CASA (Construcciones Aeronáuticas SA of Spain), who also builds the elevators, main landing gear doors, and rear fuselage parts.\n</string>

    <string name="a320_desc2" formatted="false">It includes a full glass cockpit rather than the hybrid versions found in previous airliners. The A320\'s flight deck
        is equipped with EFIS with side-stick controllers. The A320 features an Electronic Centralised Aircraft Monitor (ECAM)
        which gives the flight crew information about all the systems of the aircraft. The only analogue instruments were the radio-magnetic indicator and brake
        pressure indicator. Since 2003, the A320 features liquid crystal display (LCD) units in its flight deck instead of the original cathode ray tube (CRT)
        displays. These include the main displays and the backup artificial horizon, which was previously an analog display. Airbus offers an avionics upgrade for
        older A320 aircraft, the In-Service Enhancement Package, to keep them updated.\n\nThe A320 is the world\'s first airliner with digital fly-by-wire (FBW)
        flight control system: input commands through the side-stick are interpreted by flight control computers and transmitted to flight control surfaces within
        the flight envelope protection; in the 1980s the computer-controlled dynamic system of the Dassault Mirage 2000 fighter cross-fertilised the Airbus team
        which tested FBW on an A300. At its introduction, fly-by-wire and flight envelope protection was a new experience for many pilots.\n</string>

    <string name="a320_desc3">\nThe A320 series has two variants, the A320-100 and A320-200. Only 21 A320-100s were produced. The primary changes of the -200 over the
        -100 are wingtip fences and increased fuel capacity for increased range.\n</string>

    <string name="a320_specs_constraint">()\n</string>


    <string name="a320_identify">How to identify Airbus A320?</string>
    <string name="a320_identify_ans">\"Notched\" window design, \"bulbous\" nose, 2 dual-wheel main landing gears, engine nacelle with no trailing extensions,
        4 exits - 2 over the wing and 2 near either ends of the fuselage, and either small triangular wingtips (wingtip fence) similar to those on A380 or large L-shaped sharklets.</string>

    <string name="a320_cockpit_value">2</string>
    <string name="a320_wingspan_value">35.80 m</string>
    <string name="a320_length_value">37.57 m</string>
    <string name="a320_height_value">11.76 m</string>
    <string name="a320_fuselage_value">3.95 m (W) / 4.14 m (H)</string>
    <string name="a320_mtow_value">78 t</string>
    <string name="a320_cruise_speed_value">829 km/h (typical),\n871 km/h (max.)</string>
    <string name="a320_range_value">3,300 nmi</string>
    <string name="a320_thrust_value">98–120 kN</string>
    <!--AIRBUS A320-->


    <!--AIRBUS A319-->
    <string name="a319_type_value">Narrow-body\nairliner</string>
    <string name="a319_engine_value">CFM56 /\nIAE V2500 (2)</string>
    <string name="a319_first_flight_value">25 August 1995</string>
    <string name="a319_intro_value">1996 with\nSwissair</string>
    <string name="a319_customer_value">American Airlines</string>
    <string name="a319_variants_value">4</string>

    <string name="a319_desc1" formatted="false">The Airbus A319 is a member of the Airbus A320 family of short- to medium-range, narrow-body, commercial
        passenger twin-engine jet airliners. This Airbus A320 family was renamed to A320ceo, for \"current engine option\" after the introduction of A320neo
        (neo for new engine option) in 2014. It is a shortened-fuselage variant of the Airbus A320 and entered service in April 1996 with Swissair, around
        two years after the stretched Airbus A321 and eight years after the original A320. The aircraft shares a common type rating with all other Airbus A320
        family variants, allowing existing A320 family pilots to fly the aircraft without the need for further training. As of August 2019, a total of 1,480
        Airbus A319 aircraft have been delivered, of which 1,436 are in service.\n\nThe first member of the A320 family was the A320 which was launched in March
        1984 and first flew on 22 February 1987. The family was extended to include the stretched A321 (first delivered 1994), the shortened A319 (1996), and
        the further shortened A318 (2003). The A320 family pioneered the use of digital fly-by-wire flight control systems, as well as side stick controls,
        in commercial aircraft. The A319 was developed at the request of Steven Udvar-Hazy, the former president and CEO of ILFC according to The New York Times.\n</string>

    <string name="a319_desc2" formatted="false">The A319 design is a shortened fuselage, minimum change derivative of the A320 with its origins in the 130- to 140-seat
        SA1, part of the Single-Aisle studies. The SA1 was shelved as the consortium concentrated on its bigger siblings. After healthy sales of the A320/A321,
        Airbus re-focused on what was then known as the A320M-7, meaning A320 minus seven fuselage frames. It would provide direct competition for the 737-300/-700.
        The shrink was achieved through the removal of four fuselage frames fore and three aft the wing, cutting the overall length by 3.73 metres.
        Consequently, the number of overwing exits was reduced from four to two.\n\nHigh-density A319s, such as 156-seat aircraft used by easyJet, retain four overwing exits. The bulk-cargo door was replaced by an aft container door, which
        can take in reduced height LD3-45 containers. Minor software changes were made to accommodate the different handling characteristics; otherwise the aircraft
        is largely unchanged. Power is provided by the CFM56-5A or V2500-A5, derated to 98 kN, with option for 105 kN thrust. With virtually
        the same fuel capacity as the A320-200 and fewer passengers, the range with 124 passengers in a two-class configuration extends to 6,650 km (3,590 nmi), or
        6,850 km (3,700 nmi) with the \"sharklets\". The A319\'s wingspan is wider than the aircraft\'s overall length.\n</string>

    <string name="a319_desc3">\nThe A319 variants include the corporate jet version A319CJ (rebranded ACJ319), A319neo equipped with new engines,
        A319 MPA (Maritime Patrol Aircraft) - military derivative of the A319, and A319LR - the longer-range version of the A319.\n</string>

    <string name="a319_specs_constraint">()\n</string>


    <string name="a319_identify">How to identify Airbus A319?</string>
    <string name="a319_identify_ans">\"Notched\" window design, \"bulbous\" nose, 2 dual-wheel main landing gears, engine nacelle with no trailing extensions,
        3 exits - 1 over the wing and 2 near either ends of the fuselage, and either small triangular wingtips (wingtip fence) similar to those on A380 or large L-shaped sharklets.</string>

    <string name="a319_cockpit_value">2</string>
    <string name="a319_wingspan_value">35.80 m</string>
    <string name="a319_length_value">33.84 m</string>
    <string name="a319_height_value">11.76 m</string>
    <string name="a319_fuselage_value">3.95 m (W) / 4.14 m (H)</string>
    <string name="a319_mtow_value">75.5 t</string>
    <string name="a319_cruise_speed_value">829 km/h (typical),\n871 km/h (max.)</string>
    <string name="a319_range_value">3,750 nmi</string>
    <string name="a319_thrust_value">98–120 kN</string>
    <!--AIRBUS A319-->


    <!--AIRBUS A318-->
    <string name="a318_type_value">Narrow-body\nairliner</string>
    <string name="a318_engine_value">CFM56 /\nP&amp;W PW6000 (2)</string>
    <string name="a318_first_flight_value">15 January 2002</string>
    <string name="a318_intro_value">2003 with\nFrontier Airlines</string>
    <string name="a318_customer_value">Air France</string>
    <string name="a318_variants_value">1</string>

    <string name="a318_desc1" formatted="false">The Airbus A318 is the smallest and least numerous variant airliner of the Airbus A320 family. The A318 carries
        107 to 132 passengers and has a maximum range of 5,700 km (3,100 nmi). It is intended primarily for short-range service. The aircraft shares a common type rating
        with all other Airbus A320 family variants, allowing existing A320 family pilots to fly the aircraft without the need for further training. It is the largest
        commercial aircraft certified by the European Aviation Safety Agency for steep approach operations, allowing flights at airports such as London City. A total of 80
        A318s were been built during its production phase from 2001 to 2013.\n\nDuring the design process, the A318 encountered several problems. The first one was the
        decline in demand for new aircraft following the September 11 attacks.
        Another was the new Pratt &amp; Whitney turbofan engines, which burned more fuel than expected. By the time CFM International (CFM) had a more efficient engine
        ready for market, many A318 customers had already backed out, including Air China and British Airways. America West Airlines, which had selected the Pratt &amp;
        Whitney engines, amended its A318 orders, opting instead for A319 or A320 aircraft. Trans World Airlines cancelled a significant order for fifty A318s after being
        acquired by American Airlines, which did not operate any A320 family aircraft at the time (although neither did TWA when the order was originally placed).
        While Airbus was hoping to market the A318 as a regional jet alternative, laws in both the U.S. and Europe have kept it in the same class as larger aircraft
        for calculating charges such as landing fees, limiting the type\'s market potential.\n</string>

    <string name="a318_desc2" formatted="false">Orders for the A318 have been relatively slow, but slightly better than for its direct competitor the Boeing 737-600. By
        30 September 2017, Airbus had received 80 orders for this model compared to 69 for the 737-600. The sales pace has been influenced by the strong sales of
        the Bombardier CRJ900 and Embraer E-Jets series.\n\nThe narrow-body (single-aisle) aircraft is a low-wing cantilever monoplane with a conventional tail unit
        having a single vertical stabilizer and rudder. Overall, the A318 is over six metres shorter and around 3 t lighter than the A320. To compensate
        for the reduced moment arm, it has a larger vertical stabiliser. While initial concepts depicted the aircraft with a Boeing 737-300-style dorsal fin extension,
        the final design incorporated a fin tip extension, making it 75 centimetres taller than the other A320 variants. Pilots who are trained on the other
        variants may fly the A318 with no further certification, since it features a common flight deck and the same type rating as its sister aircraft.\n\nIn March 2006, the European Aviation Safety Agency (EASA) certified a modified control software enhancement to the Airbus A318 designed to allow the aircraft
        to perform steep approaches. The aircraft is the largest commercial aircraft certified by EASA for steep approach operations. The software modifies the
        control laws of the aircraft when the steep approach function is selected by the crew, by automatically deploying some of the spoiler panels to provide
        additional drag when the aircraft is in the landing configuration. It also provides alternative aural alerts to the crew and modifies spoiler deployment
        automatically below 37 m on landing. The A318 steep approach procedure allows the aircraft to perform approaches at descent angles of up to
        5.5°, as opposed to the standard 3° for a normal approach.\n</string>

    <string name="a318_desc3">\nThe A318 comes in only one variant, A318-100. Unlike the other aircraft in the family (A319, A320, A321), A318 does not
        have A318neo variant. Thus, it is not included in the Airbus A320neo family.\n</string>

    <string name="a318_specs_constraint">()\n</string>


    <string name="a318_identify">How to identify Airbus A318?</string>
    <string name="a318_identify_ans">Stubby fuselage, tall tail, \"notched\" window design, \"bulbous\" nose, 2 dual-wheel main landing gears, engine nacelle with no trailing extensions,
        3 exits - 1 over the wing and 2 near either ends of the fuselage, 11 windows between fore cabin door and emergency exit over the wing, and small triangular wingtips (wingtip fence) similar to those on A380.</string>

    <string name="a318_cockpit_value">2</string>
    <string name="a318_wingspan_value">34.10 m</string>
    <string name="a318_length_value">31.44 m</string>
    <string name="a318_height_value">12.56 m</string>
    <string name="a318_fuselage_value">3.95 m (W) / 4.14 m (H)</string>
    <string name="a318_mtow_value">68 t</string>
    <string name="a318_cruise_speed_value">829 km/h (typical),\n871 km/h (max.)</string>
    <string name="a318_range_value">3,100 nmi</string>
    <string name="a318_thrust_value">96–106 kN</string>
    <!--AIRBUS A318-->

    <!--AIRBUS A310-->
    <string name="a310_type_value">Wide-body\nairliner</string>
    <string name="a310_engine_value">GE CF6 /\nP&amp;W JT9D / PW4000 (2)</string>
    <string name="a310_first_flight_value">3 April 1982</string>
    <string name="a310_intro_value">April 1983\nwith Swissair</string>
    <string name="a310_customer_value">FedEx Express</string>
    <string name="a310_variants_value">4</string>

    <string name="a310_desc1" formatted="false">Airbus had demand for an aircraft smaller than the A300, the first twin-jet wide-body. On 7 July 1978, the A310
        (initially the A300B10) was launched with orders from Swissair and Lufthansa. On 3 April 1982, the first prototype conducted its maiden flight, and it
        received its type certification on 11 March 1983. Keeping the same eight-abreast cross-section, the A310 is 6.95 m shorter than the initial A300
        variants, and has a smaller wing, down from 260 to 219 m<sup><small><small>2</small></small></sup>. The A310 introduced a two-crew glass cockpit, later adopted for the A300-600
        with a common type rating. It was powered by the same General Electric CF6-80 or Pratt &amp; Whitney JT9D then PW4000 turbofan jet engines. During its production phase
        from 1981 to 1998, a total of 255 A310s were built.\n\nIn April 1983, the aircraft entered revenue service with Swissair, and competed with the Boeing 767-200,
        introduced six months before. Its longer range and ETOPS regulations allowed it to be operated on transatlantic flights. Until the last delivery in June 1998,
        255 aircraft were produced, as it was succeeded by the larger Airbus A330-200. It was available as a cargo aircraft version, and was also developed into a
        military variant, the A310 MRTT multi-role transport, then tanker.\n</string>

    <string name="a310_desc2" formatted="false">The Airbus A310 was a medium- to long-range twin-engined wide-body jet airliner. Initially a derivative of the A300,
        the aircraft had originally been designated the A300B10. It was essentially a shortened variant of the A300; however, there were considerable differences
        between the two aircraft. Specifically, the fuselage possessed the same cross-section, but being shorter than the A300, it provided capacity for a typical
        maximum of 200 passengers. The rear fuselage was heavily re-designed, featuring altered tapering, while involved a move aft of the rear bulkhead to create
        additional capacity; this same design change was later transferred back to later variants of the A300, such as the A300-600 and A330/A340 fuselages.\n\nThe
        wing of the A310 was redesigned, possessing a reduced span and wing area, and incorporating simpler single-slotted Fowler flaps designed by British Aerospace
        shortly following its decision to join the Airbus consortium. Other changes to the wing included the elimination of the outer ailerons, which were occasionally
        referred to by the manufacturer as being \"low speed ailerons\", and the addition of electrically actuated spoilers. The wing also featured common pylons,
        which were able to support all types of engines that were offered to customers to power the airliner. From 1985 onwards, later-built production A310s were
        equipped with wingtip fences for the purpose of reducing lift-induced drag. A limited number of alternations were also performed to the airliner\'s tail unit,
        such as the adoption of smaller horizontal tail surfaces. The A310 was furnished with a two-crew glass cockpit configuration as standard, removing the
        requirement for a flight engineer; Airbus referred to this concept as the Forward-Facing Crew Cockpit. The A310 was equipped with a modified undercarriage,
        derived from the A300; the landing gear were outfitted with carbon brakes, which were fitted as standard. The structure of the airliner featured a high
        level of composite materials throughout both primary and secondary structures, increased beyond that of the earlier A300. The A310 is outfitted with integrated
        drive electrical generators along with auxiliary power unit, which were improved versions of those used on the A300.\n</string>

    <string name="a310_desc3">\nThe A310 is available in two basic versions, the medium range −200 and the longer range −300. The first version of the aircraft to be
        developed was the −200, but this was later joined by the −300, which then became the standard production version of the aircraft. The short range −100 variant
        was never developed due to low demand. Other variants include A310 MRT/MRTT (Multi-Role Tanker Transport), A310 Zero G, the reduced-gravity aircraft used to
        realise parabolas, allowing performance of twenty-two seconds of weightlessness.\n</string>

    <string name="a310_specs_constraint">(-200 and -300 variants compared in order)\n</string>


    <string name="a310_identify">How to identify Airbus A310?</string>
    <string name="a310_identify_ans">Smooth central section of the lower fuselage (curved fuselage with no prominent wing flaring), \"notched\" window design, twin ram air intakes on the curved belly of the aircraft, 2 cabin doors and 1 overwing exit, with/without wingtip fences.</string>

    <string name="a310_cockpit_value">2</string>
    <string name="a310_wingspan_value">43.9 m</string>
    <string name="a310_length_value">46.66 m</string>
    <string name="a310_height_value">15.8 m</string>
    <string name="a310_fuselage_value">5.64 m (W) / ~5.9 m (H)</string>
    <string name="a310_mtow_value">144 / 164 t</string>
    <string name="a310_cruise_speed_value">850 km/h (typical),\n892 km/h (max.)</string>
    <string name="a310_range_value">3,500 / 5,150 nmi</string>
    <string name="a310_thrust_value">203.8–257.4 kN</string>
    <!--AIRBUS A310-->


    <!--AIRBUS A300-->
    <string name="a300_type_value">Wide-body\nairliner</string>
    <string name="a300_engine_value">GE CF6 / P&amp;W JT9D (-B4-200),\nGE CF6 / P&amp;W PW4158 (-600R/F) (2)</string>
    <string name="a300_first_flight_value">28 October 1972</string>
    <string name="a300_intro_value">23 May 1974\nwith Air France</string>
    <string name="a300_customer_value">FedEx Express</string>
    <string name="a300_variants_value">6</string>

    <string name="a300_desc1" formatted="false">The Airbus A300 is a wide-body airliner developed and manufactured by Airbus. In September 1967, aircraft manufacturers
        in the United Kingdom, France, and West Germany signed a memorandum of understanding to develop a large airliner. West Germany and France reached an agreement
        on 29 May 1969 after the British withdrew from the project on 10 April 1969. European collaborative aerospace manufacturer Airbus Industrie was formally created
        on 18 December 1970 to develop and produce it. The prototype first flew on 28 October 1972. During its production phase from 1971 to 2007, a total of 561 A300s were built.\n\nThe wide-body medium-to-long range airliner has the distinction of
        being the first twin-engine wide-body aircraft in the world. In 1977, the A300 became the first Extended Range Twin Operations
        (ETOPS)-compliant aircraft, due to its high performance and safety standards. Another world-first of the A300 is the use of composite materials on a
        commercial aircraft, which was used on both secondary and later primary airframe structures, decreasing overall weight and improving cost-effectiveness. Other
        firsts included the pioneering use of center-of-gravity control, achieved by transferring fuel between various locations across the aircraft, and electrically
        signaled secondary flight controls.\n\nThe A300 is powered by a pair of underwing turbofan engines, either General Electric CF6 or Pratt &amp; Whitney JT9D
        engines; the sole use of underwing engine pods allowed for any suitable turbofan engine to be more readily used. The lack of a third tail-mounted engine,
        as per the trijet configuration used by some competing airliners, allowed for the wings to be located further forwards and to reduce the size of the vertical
        stabilizer and elevator, which had the effect of increasing the aircraft\'s flight performance and fuel efficiency. Airbus partners had employed the latest
        technology, some of which having been derived from Concorde, on the A300. According to Airbus, new technologies adopted for the airliner were selected
        principally for increased safety, operational capability, and profitability.\n\nUpon entry into service in 1974, the A300 was a very advanced plane, which
        went on to influence later airliner designs. The technological highlights include advanced wings by de Havilland (later BAE Systems) with supercritical airfoil
        sections for economical performance and advanced aerodynamically efficient flight control surfaces. The 5.64 m diameter circular fuselage section allows
        an eight-abreast passenger seating and is wide enough for 2 LD3 cargo containers side by side. Structures are made from metal billets, reducing weight. It is
        the first airliner to be fitted with wind shear protection. Its advanced autopilots are capable of flying the aircraft from climb-out to landing, and it has an
        electrically controlled braking system.\n</string>

    <string name="a300_desc2" formatted="false">Later A300s incorporated other advanced features such as the Forward-Facing Crew Cockpit, which enabled a
        two-pilot flight crew to fly the aircraft alone without the need for a flight engineer, the functions of which were automated; this two-man cockpit concept
        was a world-first for a wide-body aircraft. Glass cockpit flight instrumentation, which used cathode ray tube (CRT) monitors to display flight, navigation,
        and warning information, along with fully digital dual autopilots and digital flight control computers for controlling the spoilers, flaps, and leading-edge
        slats, were also adopted upon later-built models. Additional composites were also made use of, such as carbon-fiber-reinforced polymer (CFRP), as well
        as their presence in an increasing proportion of the aircraft\'s components, including the spoilers, rudder, air brakes, and landing gear doors.\n\nAnother
        feature of later aircraft were the addition of wingtip fences, which generated greater aerodynamic performance (first introduced on the A310-300). In addition
        to passenger duties, the A300 became widely used by air freight operators; according to Airbus, it is the best selling freight aircraft of all time. Various
        variants of the A300 were built to meet customer demands, often for diverse roles such as aerial refueling tankers, freighter models (new-build and
        conversions), combi aircraft, military airlifter, and VIP transport. Perhaps the most visually unique of the variants is the A300-600ST Beluga, an oversize
        cargo-carrying model operated by Airbus to carry aircraft sections between their manufacturing facilities. The A300 was the basis for, and retained a high
        level of commonality with, the second airliner produced by Airbus, the smaller Airbus A310.\n</string>

    <string name="a300_desc3">\nAirbus A300 variants include A300B1, A300B2, A300B4, A300-600, A300B10 (A310), A300-600ST (often referred to as Airbus Beluga
        or Airbus Super Transporter)\n</string>

    <string name="a300_specs_constraint">(-B4-200, -600R, and -600F variants compared in order)\n</string>


    <string name="a300_identify">How to identify Airbus A300?</string>
    <string name="a300_identify_ans">Smooth central section of the lower fuselage (curved fuselage with no prominent wing flaring), \"notched\" window design, twin ram air intakes on the curved belly of the aircraft, 3 cabin doors and 1 exit along the length of the fuselage, short wingtip fences.</string>

    <string name="a300_cockpit_value">3 / 2 / 2</string>
    <string name="a300_wingspan_value">44.84 m</string>
    <string name="a300_length_value">53.61 m (-B4-200) /\n54.1 m (-600R / -600F)</string>
    <string name="a300_height_value">16.72 m (-B4-200) /\n16.66 m (-600R / -600F)</string>
    <string name="a300_fuselage_value">5.64 m (W) / ~5.9 m (H)</string>
    <string name="a300_mtow_value">165 / 171.7 / 170.5 t</string>
    <string name="a300_cruise_speed_value">833 km/h (typical),\n871 km/h (max.)</string>
    <string name="a300_range_value">2,900 nmi (-B4-200) /\n4,050 m (-600R / -600F)</string>
    <string name="a300_thrust_value">230 kN(-B4-200) /\n249–270 kN (-600R / -600F)</string>
    <!--AIRBUS A300-->


    <!--AIRBUS A220-->
    <string name="a220_type_value">Narrow-body\nairliner</string>
    <string name="a220_engine_value">Pratt &amp; Whitney\nPW1500G (2)</string>
    <string name="a220_first_flight_value">16 September 2013</string>
    <string name="a220_intro_value">15 July 2016 with\nSwiss International Air Lines</string>
    <string name="a220_customer_value">Delta Air Lines</string>
    <string name="a220_variants_value">3</string>

    <string name="a220_desc1" formatted="false">The Airbus A220 is a family of narrow-body airliner designed by Bombardier Aerospace as the Bombardier CSeries. In
        July 2018, the aircraft was rebranded as the A220 after Airbus acquired 50.01% of the program through a joint venture with Bombardier, which was later renamed Airbus Canada
        Limited Partnership. The Bombardier CSeries was meant to be a game-changing aircraft. Produced by the Canadian aircraft manufacturer Bombardier, it was its first foray in
        the 100-to-150-seat market. Though initially successful with sales to major airlines, the program was turned upside following a trade dispute with Boeing. The
        aircraft program was taken over by Airbus as a result, with the aircraft renamed. Bombardier pulled out of the venture entirely, leaving it
        to Airbus. Thus, in February 2020, Airbus increased its share to 75%, while the provincial government\'s Investissement Québec held the 25% balance. Powered by Pratt
        &amp; Whitney PW1500G geared turbofans, the twinjet has fly-by-wire flight controls, a carbon composite wing and an aluminium-lithium fuselage. Early operators,
        Swiss and airBaltic, recorded better-than-expected fuel burn and dispatch reliability, as well as positive feedback from passengers and crew. Delta Air Lines is
        currently the largest operator with 50 airplanes in its fleet. As of June 2021, a total of 648 aircraft had been ordered of which 164 had been delivered. The
        A220 family complements the A319neo in the Airbus range and competes with the largest variants of the Embraer E-Jet E2 family and the smaller Boeing 737 MAX-7
        variant. As of 30 June 2021, a total of 164 A220s have been built.\n\nThe Airbus A220 family of narrow-body aircraft was originally designed by Bombardier
        under the CSeries programme. The high efficient engines and extensive use of composite materials, like the wide-body Boeing 787 Dreamliner and Airbus A350 XWB,
        contribute together to the 12–15% better cash operating costs. Bombardier claimed at the time that the engine and the wings would save up to 20% fuel,
        a 25% reduction in maintenance costs and four-fold reduction in the noise footprint compared with the Airbus A320neo and the Boeing 737NG with which it competed.
        The larger CS300 (now A220-300), was 6 tonnes lighter than the Airbus A319neo and nearly 8 tons lighter than the Boeing 737 MAX 7, helping it to achieve up
        to 12% operating costs savings and 15% with the current models. The cabin cross section of the aircraft family was designed to give enhanced seating comfort
        for passengers, with features like broader seats and armrests for the middle passenger and larger windows at every seat to give every passenger the physical
        and psychological advantages of ample natural light. The cabin featured large, rotating overhead storage bins, allowing each passenger to stow a sizeable
        carry-on bag overhead. Bombardier claimed that compared to the cabins of current in-service narrow-body aircraft, the aircraft family would provide airlines
        with the highest overhead bin volume per passenger and a wider aisle that allows for faster boarding and disembarkation of passengers.\n</string>

    <string name="a220_desc2" formatted="false">The cockpit features the Rockwell Collins Pro Line Fusion avionics suite, which incorporates 15 in (380 mm) displays
        along with comprehensive navigation, communications, surveillance, engine-indicating and crew-alerting system (EICAS), and aircraft maintenance systems.
        Other elements of the avionics and other subsystems include Parker Hannifin\'s flight control, fuel and hydraulics systems, Liebherr Aerospace\'s air
        management system, and United Technologies Corporation\'s air data system, flap and slat actuation systems. The centre fuselage of the A220-300 is 3.4
        meter longer than the -100 and structurally reinforced for higher loads. The fuselage and many components incorporate a high proportion of composite
        materials. The overall aircraft consists of 70% advanced lightweight materials, comprising 46% composite materials and 24% aluminium–lithium. Bombardier
        has claimed that the type can achieve an overall 15% lower seat-mile cost, 20% lower fuel burn and a CO<sub><small><small>2</small></small></sub> emissions advantage.
        The new Pratt &amp; Whitney PW1000G engine yields 12% better fuel economy than existing jets while being quieter, with further efficiency stemming from
        enhanced aerodynamics and advanced lightweight materials.\n\nThe composite wings were manufactured and assembled at a purpose built factory at the Bombardier Aerostructures
        and Engineering Services (BAES) site in Belfast, Northern Ireland. Meanwhile, the aft fuselage and cockpit were built in Bombardier\'s Manufacturing Centre in
        Saint-Laurent, Quebec, with final assembly occurring at Mirabel, Quebec. While several major elements of the aircraft, such as the centre wing box and doors,
        were manufactured internally, many other components have been contracted out, namely: Liebherr for the landing gear and pneumatics; UTC Aerospace for the
        electrical system and lighting; Goodrich for the nacelle; Meggitt for the wheels and brakes, Michelin for the tires; Spirit for the pylons; Honeywell
        for the APU; and PPG supplies the windows. In 2010, Ghafari Associates was retained to develop the Montreal manufacturing site to accommodate the aircraft production.\n</string>

    <string name="a220_desc3">\nAirbus A220 variants include A220-100, A220-300, and ACJ TwoTwenty business jet. Their commonality over 99% allows a common spare part
        inventory, reducing investment and maintenance costs.\n</string>

    <string name="a220_specs_constraint">(-100 and -300 variants compared in order)\n</string>


    <string name="a220_identify">How to identify Airbus A220?</string>
    <string name="a220_identify_ans">Sleek pointed nose with 4-piece windshield, 2 dual-wheel main landing gear, swept wings with sharp-angled winglets, fore
        and aft cabin doors with an emergency exit over the wing.</string>

    <string name="a220_cockpit_value">2</string>
    <string name="a220_wingspan_value">35.10 m</string>
    <string name="a220_length_value">35.0 / 38.70 m</string>
    <string name="a220_height_value">11.50 m</string>
    <string name="a220_fuselage_value">3.5 m (W) / ~3.7 m (H)</string>
    <string name="a220_mtow_value">63.1 / 70.9 t</string>
    <string name="a220_cruise_speed_value">829 km/h (typical),\n871 km/h (max.)</string>
    <string name="a220_range_value">3,450 / 3,600 nmi</string>
    <string name="a220_thrust_value">84.1–103.6 kN /\n93.4–103.6 kN</string>
    <!--AIRBUS A220-->


    <!--AIRBUS BELUGA-->
    <string name="beluga_type_value">Outsize cargo freight</string>
    <string name="beluga_engine_value">General Electric CF6 (2)</string>
    <string name="beluga_first_flight_value">13 September 1994</string>
    <string name="beluga_intro_value">September 1995</string>
    <string name="beluga_variants_value">1</string>

    <string name="beluga_desc1" formatted="false">The Airbus A300-600ST (Super Transporter), or Beluga, is a version of the standard A300-600 wide-body airliner
        modified to carry aircraft parts and outsize cargo. It received the official name of Super Transporter early on; however, the name Beluga, a whale it
        resembles, gained popularity and has since been officially adopted. During its production phase from 1992 to 1998, only 5 Belugas were built in order to meet demands for transportation. Several major aircraft manufacturers are multinational, and it is not unusual for them to
        have plants in widely separated locations. Airbus is unique in that although it is today a standalone multinational corporation, it was originally a consortium
        formed by the major British, French, German, and Spanish aerospace companies. The geographic location of Airbus manufacturing is not only influenced by cost
        and convenience; it is also a matter of aviation history and national interest.\n\nHistorically, each of the Airbus partners makes an entire aircraft section,
        which would then be transported to a central location for final assembly; even after the integration of Airbus into a single firm, the arrangement remained
        largely the same, with Airbus partners becoming subsidiaries or contractors of the multinational pan-European company. The details vary from one model to
        another, but the general arrangement is for the wings and landing gear to be made in the UK, the tail and doors in Spain, the fuselage in Germany, and the
        nose and centre-section in France, with final assembly in either Toulouse, France, Hamburg, Germany, or Seville, Spain.\n\nWhen Airbus started in 1970, road vehicles were initially used for the movement of components and sections; however, growth in production volume soon
        necessitated a switch to air transport. From 1972 onwards, a fleet of four highly modified \"Super Guppies\" took over. These were former Boeing Stratocruisers
        from the 1940s that had been converted with custom fuselages and the adoption of turbine engines to carry large volume loads for NASA\'s space program in the
        1960s. Airbus\' use of the Super Guppies led to the jest that \"every Airbus is delivered on the wings of a Boeing\". As time went on, the Super Guppies grew
        increasingly unsatisfactory for Airbus\'s ferrying needs: their age meant that operating expenses were high and ever-increasing, and growing Airbus production
        required greater capacity than could be provided by the existing fleet.\n\nVarious options were studied to serve as a replacement transport medium for the Super
        Guppies, including methods of surface transportation by road, rail, and sea; these alternatives were discarded in favor of a principally air-based solution
        as they were considered to have reliability concerns and were time-consuming in operation; in addition, the assembly line in Toulouse was not conveniently
        accessible by any of the surface methods. A key requirement of the new air transporter was the need to accommodate every major component being manufactured
        by Airbus, including the then-heaviest planned part, that being the wing of the larger variants of the Airbus A340.\n\nSeveral different types of aircraft were examined for potential use, including the Antonov An-124, Antonov An-225, Ilyushin Il-86, Boeing 747, Boeing 767,
        Lockheed C-5 Galaxy, and McDonnell Douglas C-17 Globemaster III; the use of any existing aircraft was eventually discounted due to a lack of internal space
        to accommodate the desired components, the use of a piggyback arrangement was also dismissed as impractical. Boeing made their own offer to convert several
        Boeing 767s for the requirement, but this was viewed as inferior to developing a purpose-built aircraft using Airbus\' existing wide-body twin-engined Airbus
        A300-600R instead. In August 1991, Aérospatiale and DASA, two of the major Airbus partners, formed a 50/50 joint venture company, Super Airbus Transport International (SATIC),
        based in Toulouse, France, to develop a new-build replacement for the Super Guppy fleet which eventually led to the development of the Airbus Beluga.\n</string>

    <string name="beluga_desc2" formatted="false">The A300-600ST Beluga shares many design similarities, although substantially differing in appearance, to the Airbus
        A300 upon which it was based. The wings, engines, landing gear, and the lower part of the fuselage remain identical to those used on the conventional A300,
        while the upper part of the fuselage forms an enormous horseshoe-shaped structure 7.7 m in diameter. In comparison with the Super Guppy, the
        payload was more than doubled and the volume increased by more than 30% The General Electric CF6-80C2 turbofan engines used are slightly uprated from
        those used on the standard A300 as well. The vertical stabilizer uses a modified Airbus A340 fin with a 1.12 m base extension while the tailplane was
        strengthened and fitted with auxiliary fins to maintain directional stability. The tailplane trim tank was also deleted.\n\nTo provide access to the cargo area
        from the front without having to disconnect all electrical, hydraulic and flight control connections (and also avoiding the lengthy recalibrations before
        each flight that reconnection entailed), the standard A300 cockpit was relocated down below the cargo-floor level. By relocating the cockpit in this
        manner, loading times were reportedly halved from those encountered using the Super Guppy, which had needed to disconnect and reconnect such systems. Another
        reason for faster loading times was the adoption of a roll-on/roll-off loading system, as well as the ability to unload the aircraft in
        winds of up to 40 knots.\n\nThe cockpit of the Beluga is pressurized but the cargo deck is not, making it inaccessible during flight and unsuitable for cargoes that require a
        pressurized environment, such as live animals. However, the cargo deck is fitted with a heating module to keep the cargo within an appropriate temperature
        range. On at least one occasion, a pressurized container has been used for cargo. The aircraft is operated by a crew of three – two
        pilots and a loadmaster. The main deck cargo volume of the Beluga is greater than that of the C-5 Galaxy or the Antonov An-124 but still smaller
        than Antonov An-225. However, it is restricted by cargo-weight capacity of 47 tonnes, compared to 122.5 tonnes for the C-5 Galaxy and 150 tonnes for
        the An-124. Despite this width, the Beluga cannot carry most fuselage parts of the Airbus A380, which are instead normally transported by ship and road. The
        Beluga has been used to transport some A380 components.\n</string>


    <string name="beluga_specs_constraint">(A300-600ST)\n</string>


    <string name="beluga_identify">How to identify Airbus Beluga?</string>
    <string name="beluga_identify_ans">The Beluga does not need bells and whistles to get attention, it is one of its kind. The Airbus livery gives it away too.</string>

    <string name="beluga_cockpit_value">2</string>
    <string name="beluga_wingspan_value">44.84 m</string>
    <string name="beluga_length_value">56.15 m</string>
    <string name="beluga_height_value">17.24 m</string>
    <string name="beluga_fuselage_value">7.31 m (W) / ~7.45 m (H)</string>
    <string name="beluga_mtow_value">155 t</string>
    <string name="beluga_cruise_speed_value">778 km/h (typical)</string>
    <string name="beluga_range_value">1,501 nmi with 40 t payload /\n2,501 nmi with 26 t payload</string>
    <string name="beluga_thrust_value">257 kN</string>
    <!--AIRBUS BELUGA-->


    <!--AIRBUS A320neo FAMILY-->
    <string name="a320neo_type_value">Narrow-body\nairliner</string>
    <string name="a320neo_engine_value">CFM LEAP-1A /\nPratt &amp; Whitney PW1100G (2)</string>
    <string name="a320neo_first_flight_value">25 September 2014</string>
    <string name="a320neo_intro_value">25 January 2016\nwith Lufthansa</string>
    <string name="a320neo_customer_value">IndiGo</string>
    <string name="a320neo_variants_value">7 (active)</string>

    <string name="a320neo_desc1" formatted="false">The Airbus A320neo family (neo for new engine option) is a development of the A320 family of narrow-body airliners.
        The A320neo family is based on the previous A319, A320 and A321, which was renamed to A320ceo, for \"current engine option\". Re-engined with CFM LEAP-1A or
        Pratt &amp; Whitney PW1000G engines and fitted with sharklets as standard, it is 15% to 20% more fuel efficient than the A320ceo family. It was launched on
        1 December 2010, made its first flight on 25 September 2014 and was introduced by Lufthansa on 25 January 2016. By 2019, the A320neo had a 60% market share
        against the competing Boeing 737 MAX. As of June 2021, a total of 7,469 A320neo family aircraft had been ordered by more than 115 airlines,
        of which 1,838 aircraft had been delivered.\n\nAirbus launched the sharklet blended wingtip device during the November 2009 Dubai Airshow. The installation
        adds 200 kilograms but offers a 3.5% fuel burn reduction on flights over 2,800 km (1,500 nmi). The neo is 1.8 t heavier than the ceo, but take-off
        and landing performance is the same with a modified rotation law, adjusted wing flap and wing slat angles and rudder deflection increased by 5° to cope with
        the higher thrust. It is also is half as loud as an A320 at take-off, with an 85 decibel noise footprint. The LEAP-powered A321neo has 83.3 dB flyover noise,
        substantially lower than the older CFM56 and V2500 used for most A320ceo family aircraft.\n</string>


    <string name="a320neo_desc2" formatted="false">Compared to the re-engine improvement of 15%, an all-new single-aisle would have brought only 3% more gain while
        high volume manufacturing in carbon fibre could be much more expensive. At the February 2010 Singapore Air Show, Airbus said its decision to launch was scheduled
        for the July 2010 Farnborough Air Show. The decision had still not been taken by August, but the engine choice included the CFM International LEAP-1A and the
        Pratt &amp; Whitney PW1000G, with 20% lower maintenance cost than current A320 engines. The new engines burn 16% less fuel, though the actual gain is slightly less
        as 1–2% is typically lost when installed on an existing aircraft.\n\nThe aircraft family features new \"Space-Flex\" optional cabin configuration increases
        space-efficiency with a new rear galley configuration and a \"Smart-Lav\" modular lavatory design – allowing an in-flight change of two lavatories into one
        accessible toilet. The rearranged cabin allows up to 20 more passengers for the A321neo without \"putting more sardines in the can\" with the larger \"Cabin-Flex\"
        modified exits described below. Total fuel consumption per seat is reduced by over 20%, while the rearranged cabin allows up to nine more passengers
        for the A320neo. After a year in service, Lufthansa confirmed the 20% efficiency gain per passenger with up to 180 seats, along with reduced noise and CO<sub><small><small>2</small></small></sub>
        emissions. Operators confirm the 15% per seat fuel-burn savings even counterbalanced by the added weight on short sectors, which can rise to 16–17% on longer
        routes and to 20% or more for Lufthansa with 180 passengers up from 168 with two more seat rows. It was Lufthansa again that confirmed the 16% fuel savings
        but had to block the last seating row due to centre-of-gravity concerns.\n</string>

    <string name="a320neo_desc3">\nAirbus offers three variants of the A320neo family: the A319neo, A320neo and A321neo. A neo variant for the Airbus A318 was not
        proposed but could be developed should demand arise. Other variants include A321LR, A321XLR (officially launched at the Paris Air Show on 17 June 2019,
        with deliveries expected from 2023), ACJ319neo and the ACJ320neo as the corporate variants.\n</string>

    <string name="a320neo_specs_constraint">(A319neo, A320neo, A321neo compared in order)\n</string>


    <string name="a320neo_identify">How to identify Airbus A320neo family aircraft?</string>
    <string name="a320neo_identify_ans">\"Notched\" window design, \"bulbous\" nose, 2 dual-wheel main landing gears, engine nacelle with small top/bottom trailing extensions, large L-shaped sharklets.</string>

    <string name="a320neo_cockpit_value">2</string>
    <string name="a320neo_wingspan_value">35.80 m</string>
    <string name="a320neo_length_value">33.84 / 37.57 / 44.51 m</string>
    <string name="a320neo_height_value">11.76 m</string>
    <string name="a320neo_fuselage_value">3.95 m (W) / 4.14 m (H)</string>
    <string name="a320neo_mtow_value">75.5 / 79 / 97 t</string>
    <string name="a320neo_cruise_speed_value">833 km/h (typical),\n876 km/h (max.)</string>
    <string name="a320neo_range_value">3,750 / 3,500 / 4,000 nmi</string>
    <string name="a320neo_thrust_value">107 / 120.6 / 147.3 kN</string>
    <!--AIRBUS A320neo FAMILY-->


    <!--ANTONOV AN-124 RUSLAN-->
    <string name="an124_type_value">Heavy transport</string>
    <string name="an124_engine_value">Motor Sich\nProgress D-18T (4)</string>
    <string name="an124_first_flight_value">24 December 1982</string>
    <string name="an124_intro_value">1986</string>
    <string name="an124_customer_value">Russian Air Force</string>
    <string name="an124_variants_value">8 (active)</string>

    <string name="an124_desc1" formatted="false">The Antonov An-124 Ruslan (NATO reporting name: Condor) is a large, strategic airlift, four-engined aircraft that was designed in the 1980s by
        the Antonov design bureau in the Ukrainian SSR, then part of the Soviet Union (USSR). Until the Boeing 747-8F, the An-124 was, for thirty years, the world\'s
        heaviest gross weight production cargo airplane and second heaviest operating cargo aircraft, behind the one-off Antonov An-225 Mriya (a greatly enlarged
        design based on the An-124). The An-124 remains the largest military transport aircraft in service. During development it was known as Izdeliye 400 (Product #400)
        in house, and An-40 in the West. First flown in 1982, civil certification was issued on 30 December 1992. In July 2013, 26 An-124s were in commercial service with 10 on order. During its production phase from 1982 to 2004, 55 An-124s were built.\n\nDuring the 1970s, the Military Transport Aviation Command
        (Komandovaniye voyenno-transportnoy aviatsii or VTA) arm of the Soviet Air Forces had a shortfall in strategic heavy airlift capacity. Its largest planes
        consisted of about 50 Antonov An-22 turboprops, which were used heavily for tactical roles. A declassified 1975 CIA analysis concluded that the USSR
        did \"…not match the US in ability to provide long-range heavy lift support.\" The An-124 was manufactured in parallel by two plants: the company Aviastar-SP
        (ex. Ulyanovsk Aviation Industrial Complex) in Ulyanovsk, Russia and by the Kyiv Aviation Plant AVIANT, in Ukraine. Design work started in 1971 and construction
        of facilities began in 1973. Manufacturing on the first airframe began in 1979. Ultimately this project brought together over 100 factories contracted to
        produce systems and parts. In the early 2000s, Volga-Dnepr upgraded its freighters with engine improvements to meet Chapter 4 noise regulations, structural
        improvements to increase service life, and avionics and systems changes for four persons operations down from six or seven.\n</string>

    <string name="an124_desc2" formatted="false">Externally, the An-124 is similar to the American Lockheed C-5 Galaxy, having a double fuselage to allow for a rear
        cargo door (on the lower fuselage) that can open in flight without affecting structural integrity. It is slightly shorter, with a slightly greater wingspan,
        and a 17% larger payload. Instead of the Galaxy\'s T-tail, the An-124 uses a conventional empennage, similar in design to that of the Boeing 747.
        The An-124\'s main engine is the Lotarev D-18 (238–250 kN). The aircraft uses oleo strut suspension for its 24 wheels. The suspension has been calibrated to
        allow landing on rough terrain and is able to kneel to allow easier front loading. The plane has an onboard overhead crane capable of lifting up to 30
        tonnes of cargo, and items up to 120 tonnes can be winched on board.\n\nUp to 150 tonnes (150 long tons; 170 short tons) of cargo can be carried in a military
        An-124; it can also carry 88 passengers in an upper deck behind the wing centre section. The cargo compartment of An-124 is 36×6.4×4.4 m, ca.
        20% larger than the main cargo compartment of the C-5 Galaxy, which is 36.91×5.79×4.09 m. Due to limited pressurisation in the
        main cargo compartment (24.6 kPa, 3.57 psi), it seldom carries paratroopers. Pilots have stated that the An-124 is light on the controls and easy to
        handle for an aircraft of its size. Some airports require pavement protection from the heat and blast effects of the An-124\'s 2 TA18-200-124
        auxiliary power units.\n\nAt MAKS Air Show in 2017, the TsAGI announced its An-124-102 Slon (elephant) design to replace the similar An-124-100. The design was
        detailed in January 2019 before wind tunnel testing scheduled for August–September. It is intended to be produced at the Aviastar-SP factory in Ulyanovsk. It
        should transport 150 t over 3,800 nmi (7,000 km) (up from 1,675 nmi, 3,102 km), or 180 t over 2,650 nmi (4,910 km) at 460 kn (850 km/h). The
        Russian MoD wants a range of 4,100 nmi (7,600 km) with five Sprut-SDM-1 light tanks, their 100 crew and 300 armed soldiers. The planned An-124-102 is larger at
        82.3 m long from 69 m, with a 87–88 m span versus 73.3 m and 24.0 m high compared with 21.0 m.\n\nA
        new higher aspect ratio, composite wing and a 214–222 t airframe would allow a 490–500 t gross weight. It should
        be powered by Russian PD-35s developed for the CR929 widebody, producing 35 tf up from 23 tf. Two fuselages are planned, one for
        Volga-Dnepr with a width of 5.3 m from the An-124\'s 4.4 m, and one for the Russian MoD of 6.4 m wide to carry vehicles in two lines. By
        November 2019, the TsAGI had shown a 1.63 m long and 1.75 m wide model, ahead of windtunnel testing.\n</string>

    <string name="an124_desc3">\nAntonov An-124 variants include An-124 Ruslan (strategic heavy airlift transport aircraft), An-124-100 (commercial transport aircraft),
        An-124-100M-150, An-124-102, An-124-115M, An-124-130 (proposed), An-124-135, An-124-150, An-124-200 (proposed), An-124-210 (joint proposal with Air Foyle), and
        An-124-300.\n</string>

    <string name="an124_specs_constraint">(-100M variant)\n</string>


    <string name="an124_identify">How to identify Antonov An-124 Ruslan?</string>
    <string name="an124_identify_ans">4 engines, wings attached to top part of the fuselage, no wingtips, single vertical stabilizer arrangement.</string>

    <string name="an124_cockpit_value">6</string>
    <string name="an124_wingspan_value">73.3 m</string>
    <string name="an124_length_value">69.1 m</string>
    <string name="an124_height_value">21.08 m</string>
    <string name="an124_gross_weight_value">214 t with max. fuel</string>
    <string name="an124_mtow_value">402 t</string>
    <string name="an124_cruise_speed_value">800–850 km/h (typical),\n865 km/h (max.)</string>
    <string name="an124_range_value">2,000 nmi (max. payload) /\n6,200 nmi (40 t payload)</string>
    <string name="an124_thrust_value">229 kN</string>
    <!--ANTONOV AN-124 RUSLAN-->


    <!--ANTONOV AN-72 CHEBURASHKA-->
    <string name="an72_type_value">Transport aircraft</string>
    <string name="an72_engine_value">Ivchenko-Progress\nMotor Sich Lotarev D-36 (2)</string>
    <string name="an72_first_flight_value">31 August 1977</string>
    <string name="an72_customer_value">Russian Air Force</string>
    <string name="an72_variants_value">6</string>

    <string name="an72_desc1" formatted="false">The Antonov An-72 (NATO reporting name: Coaler) is a Soviet/Ukrainian transport aircraft, developed by Antonov. It
        was designed as an STOL (short takeoff and landing) transport and intended as a replacement for the Antonov An-26, but variants have found success as commercial
        freighters. The An-72 and the related An-74 get their nickname, Cheburashka, from the large engine intake ducts, which resemble the oversized ears of the
        popular Soviet animated character of the same name. The aircraft is still in production and a total of 195 (its variants included) have been built so far. The
        An-72 first flew in December 1977. Produced in tandem with the An-72, the An-74 variant adds the ability to operate in harsh weather conditions in polar
        regions, because it can be fitted with wheel-skis landing gear, de-icing equipment and a number of other upgrades, allowing the aircraft to support
        operations in Arctic or Antarctic environments. Other An-72 versions include the An-72S VIP transport and An-72P maritime patrol aircraft.\n\nAn unusual design feature
        of the An-72 is the use of the Coandă effect to improve STOL performance, utilizing engine exhaust gases blown over the wing\'s upper surface to boost lift. The
        first flight was made on 31 August 1977, but it was only in the 1980s that production started. The powerplant used is the Lotarev D-36 turbofan engine. The
        An-72 bears some resemblance to the unsuccessful Boeing YC-14, a prototype design from the early 1970s (design submitted to the Air Force in February 1972) which
        had also used overwing engines and the Coandă effect.\n</string>

    <string name="an72_desc2" formatted="false">The rear fuselage of the aircraft has a hinged loading ramp with a rear fairing that slides backwards and up to clear the
        opening. Up to 7.5 tons can be airdropped while there are folding side seats for 52 passengers. In 2018, it was reported that six An-72 aircraft will be
        upgraded for the Russian Aerospace Forces and Navy to carry more fuel and payload for Arctic operations. The An-72 has STOL capabilities; its takeoff roll
        is 620 metres and its landing run is 420 metres. This aircraft was designed to be used on unprepared surfaces: its robust undercarriage
        and high-flotation tyres allow operations on sand, grass, or other unpaved surfaces. In January 1997 and 1998, the Paris-Dakar rally was assisted by two
        An-72 aircraft. In 1999, a total of four aircraft of this type joined the rally.\n</string>

    <string name="an72_desc3">\nAntonov An-72 variants include An-72 (Coaler-A), An-72A (Coaler-C), An-72AT (Coaler-C), An-72S (Coaler-C), An-72P, and An-74.\n</string>

    <string name="an72_specs_constraint">(-72 variant)\n</string>


    <string name="an72_identify">How to identify Antonov An-72 Cheburashka?</string>
    <string name="an72_identify_ans">Large engine intake ducts that resemble the oversized ears of the popular Soviet animated character Cheburashka, 2 engines
        attached above the wings, pointed nose, no wingtips, horizontal stabilizers attached to the top part of the tail with a pointed extension attached
        to the front section of the tail on the same axis as the horizontal stabilizers.</string>

    <string name="an72_cockpit_value">5</string>
    <string name="an72_wingspan_value">31.89 m</string>
    <string name="an72_length_value">28.07 m</string>
    <string name="an72_height_value">8.65 m</string>
    <string name="an72_gross_weight_value">34.5 t</string>
    <string name="an72_cruise_speed_value">540 km/h (typical),\n700 km/h (max.)</string>
    <string name="an72_range_value">2,336 nmi</string>
    <string name="an72_thrust_value">62.75 kN</string>
    <!--ANTONOV AN-72 CHEBURASHKA-->


    <!--ANTONOV AN-22 ANTEI-->
    <string name="an22_type_value">Strategic airlifter</string>
    <string name="an22_engine_value">Kuznetsov NK-12MA\nturboprop (4)</string>
    <string name="an22_first_flight_value">27 February 1965</string>
    <string name="an22_intro_value">1967</string>
    <string name="an22_customer_value">Soviet Air Force</string>
    <string name="an22_variants_value">4 (active)</string>

    <string name="an22_desc1" formatted="false">The Antonov An-22 Antei (NATO reporting name: Cock),the world’s largest turboprop aircraft, is a heavy military transport aircraft designed by the
        Antonov Design Bureau in the Soviet Union. Powered by four turboprop engines each driving a pair of contra-rotating propellers, the design was the first
        wide-body transport aircraft and remains the world\'s largest turboprop-powered aircraft to date. The An-22 first appeared publicly outside the Soviet Union
        at the 1965 Paris Air Show. Thereafter, the model saw extensive use in major military and humanitarian airlifts for the Soviet Union, and is still in service
        with the Russian Air Force. During its production phase from 1966 to 1976, a total of 68 An-22s were built.\n\nIn the late 1950s, the Soviet Union required a
        large military transport aircraft to supplement the Antonov An-8 and An-12s then entering service. Originally known as the An-20, the model is a conventional
        multi-engined high-wing design. In the early 1960s, the Antonov bureau produced a wooden mock up at its Kyiv, Ukraine, workshops of what was designated the
        Model 100. The prototype, now designated the An-22, was rolled out on 18 August 1964 and first flew on 27 February 1965. The prototype was given the name
        Antaeus (sometimes misspelled Antheus) and, after four-months of test flying, was displayed at the 1965 Paris Air Show. All aircraft were built at the
        Tashkent State Aircraft Factory and the first military delivery was made to the Air Transport Wing at Ivanovo Airbase in 1969. The aircraft was designed as a
        strategic airlifter, designed specifically to expand the Soviet Airborne Troops\' capability to land with their then-new BMD-1 armoured vehicles. The An-22
        cargo hold can accommodate four BMD-1s compared to only one in the An-12.\n</string>

    <string name="an22_desc2" formatted="false">It has the capability to takeoff from austere, unpaved, and short airstrips, allowing airborne troops to perform
        air-landing operations. This is achieved by four pairs of contra-rotating propellers, similar to those on the Tupolev Tu-114. The propellers and exhaust
        from the engines produce a slipstream over the wings and large double-slotted flaps. The landing gear is ruggedized for rough airstrips. In early versions
        tire pressures could be adjusted in flight for optimum landing performance. That feature was removed in later models. The An-22 follows traditional cargo
        transport design with a high-mounted wing allowing a large cargo space of 33 m in length and a usable volume of 639 m³. The forward fuselage is fully
        pressurized and provides space for 5 to 8 crew and up to 28 passengers, but the cargo space is pressurized to only 3.55 PSI / 0.245 bar allowing for a
        lighter airframe. A door equipped with pressure bulkhead is located at frame 14, separating the cargo attendant\'s compartment from the main cargo compartment. This
        allows the rear cargo doors to be opened during flight for paratroops and equipment drop. Like the An-12, the aircraft has a circular fuselage section. The
        An-22 has set a number of payload and payload-to-height world records.\n\nThe An-22 has the general appearance of an enlarged version of the earlier Antonov
        An-12 except that it is fitted with a twin tail. This gives the An-22 better engine-out performance, and reduces height restrictions for hangars. Also of
        note are large anti-flutter masses on the top of each tail. Only one production variant was built, the standard An-22. Prototypes, such as the one first
        featured at the 1965 Paris Air Show had fully glazed noses that lacked the nose-mounted radar of production models. Those aircraft had the radar mounted below
        the right wheel well fairing, forward of the wheels. Antonov designated a variant with a modified electrical system and an additional augmented flight control
        system the An-22A but the designation was not used by the military.\n</string>

    <string name="an22_desc3">\nAntonov An-22 variants include An-22 (the original prototype), another An-22 with external start system, Amphibious An-22 - an amphibian
        version of the An-22 that did not progress past the scale model phase, An-22A, and An-22PZ.\n</string>

    <string name="an22_specs_constraint">(-22)\n</string>


    <string name="an22_identify">How to identify Antonov An-22 Antei?</string>
    <string name="an22_identify_ans">4 turboprop engines, glass nose, no wingtips, twin tails with pointed extensions at the top, wings attached to the top part of fuselage.</string>

    <string name="an22_cockpit_value">5-6</string>
    <string name="an22_wingspan_value">64.4 m</string>
    <string name="an22_length_value">57.92 m approx.\n(dependent on nose config.)</string>
    <string name="an22_height_value">12.53 m</string>
    <string name="an22_propellers_value">8-bladed contra-rotating constant-\nspeed reversible-pitch propeller</string>
    <string name="an22_mtow_value">250 t</string>
    <string name="an22_cruise_speed_value">580 km/h (typical),\n740 km/h (max.)</string>
    <string name="an22_range_value">2,700 nmi with max. payload\n5,910 nmi with max. fuel, 45 t payload</string>
    <string name="an22_shaft_horse_power_value">15,000 shp</string>
    <!--ANTONOV AN-22 ANTEI-->


    <!--ANTONOV AN-225 MRIYA-->
    <string name="an225_type_value">Outsize cargo freight</string>
    <string name="an225_engine_value">Motor Sich\nProgress D-18T (6)</string>
    <string name="an225_first_flight_value">21 December 1988</string>
    <string name="an225_customer_value">Antonov Airlines</string>
    <string name="an225_variants_value">1</string>

    <string name="an225_desc1" formatted="false">The Antonov An-225 Mriya (NATO reporting name: Cossack) is a strategic airlift cargo aircraft that was designed by
        the Antonov Design Bureau in the Ukrainian SSR within the Soviet Union during the 1980s. It is powered by six turbofan engines and is the heaviest aircraft
        ever built, with a maximum takeoff weight of 640 tonnes (705 short tons). It also has the largest wingspan of any aircraft in operational service. The
        single example built in 1985 has the Ukrainian civil registration UR-82060. A second airframe with a slightly different configuration was partially built. Its
        construction was halted in 1994 because of lack of funding and interest, but revived briefly in 2009, bringing it to 60–70% completion. On 30 August 2016,
        Antonov agreed to complete the second airframe for Airspace Industry Corporation of China (not Aviation Industry Corporation of China) as a
        prelude to commencing series production.\n\nThe Antonov An-225 was designed to airlift the Energia rocket\'s boosters and the Buran-class orbiters for the
        Soviet space program. It was developed as a replacement for the Myasishchev VM-T. The An-225\'s original mission and objectives are almost identical to that
        of the United States\' Shuttle Carrier Aircraft. The lead designer of the An-225 (and the An-124) was Viktor Tolmachev. The An-225 first flew on 21 December
        1988. It was on static display at the Paris Air Show in 1989, and it flew during the public days at the Farnborough Air Show in 1990. Two aircraft were
        ordered, but only one An-225, (registration CCCP-82060, later UR-82060) was finished. It can carry ultra-heavy and oversized freight weighing up
        to 250,000 kg internally or 200,000 kg on the upper fuselage. Cargo on the upper fuselage can be 70 m long. The second An-225
        was partially built during the late 1980s for the Soviet space program. Following the collapse of the Soviet Union in 1991 and the cancellation of the
        Buran program, the lone operational An-225 was placed in storage in 1994. The six Ivchenko-Progress engines were removed for use on An-124s, and the second
        uncompleted An-225 airframe was also stored. In the 1990s, a cargoliner bigger than the An-124 was clearly needed. The first An-225 was restored
        by 2001.\n\nBy 2000, the need for additional An-225 capacity had become apparent, so the decision was made in September 2006 to complete the second An-225. That
        second airframe was scheduled for completion around 2008, then delayed. By August 2009, the aircraft had not been completed and work had been abandoned. In May
        2011, the Antonov CEO reportedly said that the completion of a second An-225 Mriya transport aircraft with a carrying capacity of 250 tons requires at least
        $300 million, but if the financing is provided, its completion could be achieved in three years. According to different sources, the second aircraft
        is 60–70% complete.\n</string>

    <string name="an225_desc2" formatted="false">Based on Antonov\'s earlier An-124, the An-225 has fuselage barrel extensions added fore and aft of the wings. The
        wings also received root extensions to increase span. The wings are anhedral. The flight control surfaces are controlled via fly-by-wire and triple-redundant
        hydraulics. Two more Progress D-18T turbofan engines were added to the new wing roots, bringing the total to six. An increased-capacity landing gear system
        with 32 wheels was designed, some of which are steerable, enabling the aircraft to turn within a 60-metre-wide runway. Like its An-124 predecessor, the
        An-225 has nose gear designed to "kneel" so cargo can be more easily loaded and unloaded. Unlike the An-124, which has a rear cargo door and ramp, the
        An-225 design left these off to save weight, and the empennage design was changed from a single vertical stabilizer to a twin tail with an oversized, swept-back
        horizontal stabilizer. The twin tail was essential to enable the plane to carry large, heavy external loads that would disturb the airflow around a conventional
        tail. Unlike the An-124, the An-225 was not intended for tactical airlifting and is not designed for short-field operation.\n\nInitially, the An-225 had a
        maximum gross weight of 600 t (660 short tons; 590 long tons), but from 2000 to 2001, the aircraft underwent modifications at a cost of US$20M such as
        the addition of a reinforced floor, which increased the maximum gross weight to 640 t (710 short tons; 630 long tons). Both the earlier and later takeoff
        weights establish the An-225 as the world\'s heaviest aircraft, being heavier than the double-deck Airbus A380. It is surpassed in other size-related
        categories, but Airbus claims to have improved upon the An-225\'s maximum landing weight by landing an A380 at 591.7 tonnes during tests, and
        the Hughes H-4 Hercules, known as the Spruce Goose, has a greater wingspan and a greater overall height, but the Spruce Goose is 20% shorter and overall
        lighter, due to the materials used in its construction. In addition, the H-4 only flew once and for less than a minute, making the An-225 the largest
        aircraft in the world to fly multiple times.\n</string>

    <string name="an225_desc3">\n</string>

    <string name="an225_specs_constraint">()\n</string>


    <string name="an225_identify">How to identify Antonov An-225 Mriya?</string>
    <string name="an225_identify_ans">The world’s largest cargo aircraft with 6 engines, twin tails, massive fuselage and no wingtips doesn\'t need anything
        extra to be recognized.</string>

    <string name="an225_cockpit_value">6</string>
    <string name="an225_wingspan_value">88.4 m</string>
    <string name="an225_length_value">84.0 m</string>
    <string name="an225_height_value">18.1 m</string>
    <string name="an225_mtow_value">640 t</string>
    <string name="an225_cruise_speed_value">800 km/h (typical),\n850 km/h (max.)</string>
    <string name="an225_range_value">8,300 nmi with maximum fuel</string>
    <string name="an225_thrust_value">229.5 kN</string>
    <!--ANTONOV AN-225 MRIYA-->


    <!--BOEING 737-->
    <string name="b737_type_value">Narrow-body\nairliner</string>
    <string name="b737_engine_value">Pratt &amp; Whitney JT8D /\nCFM56 / CFM LEAP-1B (2)</string>
    <string name="b737_first_flight_value">9 April 1967</string>
    <string name="b737_intro_value">10 February 1968\nwith Lufthansa</string>
    <string name="b737_customer_value">Southwest Airlines</string>
    <string name="b737_variants_value">13</string>

    <string name="b737_desc1" formatted="false">The Boeing 737 is a narrow-body airliner produced by Boeing at its Renton Factory in Washington. Developed to
        supplement the Boeing 727 on short and thin routes, the twinjet retains the 707 fuselage cross-section and nose with two underwing turbofans. Envisioned
        in 1964, the initial 737-100 made its first flight in April 1967 and entered service in February 1968 with Lufthansa. The lengthened 737-200 entered service
        in April 1968. It evolved through four generations, offering several variants for 85 to 215 passengers. The 737-100/200 original variants were powered by
        Pratt &amp; Whitney JT8D low-bypass engines and offered seating for 85 to 130 passengers. Launched in 1980 and introduced in 1984, the 737 Classic -300/400/500
        variants were upgraded with CFM56-3 turbofans and offered 110 to 168 seats.\n\nIntroduced in 1997, the 737 Next Generation (NG) -600/700/800/900 variants have
        updated CFM56-7s, a larger wing and an upgraded glass cockpit, and seat 108 to 215 passengers. The latest generation, the 737 MAX, 737-7/8/9/10 MAX, powered
        by improved CFM LEAP-1B high bypass turbofans and accommodating 138 to 204 people, entered service in 2017. Boeing Business Jet versions are produced since the
        737NG, as well as military models. As of December 2019, 15,156 Boeing 737s have been ordered and 10,571 delivered. Initially, its main competitor was the
        McDonnell Douglas DC-9, followed by its MD-80/MD-90 derivatives. It was the highest-selling commercial aircraft until being surpassed by the competing Airbus
        A320 family in October 2019, but maintains the record in total deliveries.\n\nThe fuselage cross section and nose is derived from that of the Boeing 707 and
        Boeing 727. Early 737 cockpits also inherited the \"eyebrow windows\" positioned above the main glareshield, which were a feature of the original 707 and 727
        to allow for better crew visibility. Contrary to popular belief, these windows were not intended for celestial navigation (only the military T-43A had a
        sextant port for star navigation, which the civilian models lacked). With modern avionics, the windows became redundant, and many pilots actually placed
        newspapers or other objects in them to block out sun glare. They were eliminated from the 737 cockpit design in 2004, although they are still installed on
        customer request. The eyebrow windows were sometimes removed and plugged, usually during maintenance overhauls, and can be distinguished by the metal plug
        which differs from the smooth metal in later aircraft that were not originally fitted with the windows. The 737\'s main landing gear, under the wings at
        mid-cabin, rotates into wheel wells in the aircraft\'s belly. The legs are covered by partial doors, and \"brush-like\" seals aerodynamically smooth (or \"fair\")
        the wheels in the wells. The sides of the tires are exposed to the air in flight. \"Hub caps\" complete the aerodynamic profile of the wheels. It is forbidden
        to operate without the caps, because they are linked to the ground speed sensor that interfaces with the anti-skid brake system. The dark circles of the tires
        are clearly visible when a 737 takes off, or is at low altitude.\n\nFrom July 2008 the steel landing gear brakes on new NGs were replaced by
        Messier-Bugatti carbon brakes, achieving weight savings up to 250–320 kg depending on whether standard or high-capacity brakes. On a 737-800 this gives a
        0.5% improvement in fuel efficiency. 737s are not equipped with fuel dump systems. The original design was too small to require this, and adding a fuel dump
        system to the later, larger variants would have incurred a large weight penalty. Boeing instead demonstrated an \"equivalent level of safety\". Depending upon
        the nature of the emergency, 737s either circle to burn off fuel or land overweight. If the latter is the case, the aircraft is inspected by maintenance
        personnel for damage and then returned to service if none is found.\n</string>

    <string name="b737_desc2" formatted="false">Engines on the 737 Classic series (-300, -400, -500) and Next-Generation series (-600, -700, -800, -900) do not
        have circular inlets like most aircraft but rather a planform on the lower side, which has been dictated largely by the need to accommodate ever larger engine
        diameters. The 737 Classic series featured CFM56 high bypass turbofan engines, which were 25% more efficient and also reduced noise significantly over JT8D
        low bypass engines used on the 737 Original series (-100 and -200), but also posed an engineering challenge given the low ground clearance of the Boeing 737
        family. Boeing and engine supplier CFM International (CFMI) solved the problem by placing the engine ahead of (rather than below) the wing, and by moving
        engine accessories to the sides (rather than the bottom) of the engine pod, giving the 737 Classic and later generations a distinctive non-circular air intake. The
        wing also incorporated changes for improved aerodynamics. The engines\' accessory gearbox was moved from the 6 o\'clock position under the engine to the 4 o\'clock
        position (from a front/forward looking aft perspective). This side-mounted gearbox gives the engine a somewhat rounded triangular shape. Because the engine is
        close to the ground, 737-300s and later models are more prone to engine foreign object damage (FOD). The improved, higher pressure ratio CFM56-7 turbofan engine
        on the 737 Next Generation is 7% more fuel-efficient than the previous CFM56-3 on the 737 Classic with the same bypass ratio. The newest 737 variants, the
        737 MAX series, feature LEAP-1B engines from CFMI with a 1.73 m fan diameter. These engines were expected to be 10-12% more efficient than the CFM56-7B
        engines on the 737 Next Generation series.\n\nThe 737 is unusual in that it still uses a hydro-mechanical flight control system, similar to the Boeing 707
        and typical of the period, that transmits pilot commands to control surfaces by steel cables run through the fuselage and wings rather than by an electrical
        fly-by-wire system as used in all of the Airbus fleet and all later Boeing models. This has been raised as a safety issue because of the impracticality of
        duplicating such a mechanical cable-based system in the way that an electrical or electronic system can be. This leaves the flight controls as a single point
        of failure, for example by metal fragments from an uncontained engine failure penetrating the wings or fuselage. The primary flight controls have mechanical
        backups. In the event of total hydraulic system failure or double engine failure, they will automatically and seamlessly revert to control via servo tab. In
        this mode, the servo tabs aerodynamically control the elevators and ailerons; these servo tabs are in turn controlled by cables running to the control yoke. The
        pilot\'s muscle forces alone control the tabs.\n\nThe Original -100 and -200 series were built without wingtip devices but these were later introduced to improve
        fuel efficiency. The 737 has evolved four winglet types: the 737-200 Mini-winglet, 737 Classic/NG Blended Winglet, 737 Split Scimitar Winglet, and 737 MAX Advanced
        Technology Winglet. The 737-200 Mini-winglets are part of the Quiet Wing Corp modification kit that received certification in 2005. Blended winglets
        were standard on the 737 NG and are available for retrofit on 737 Classic models. These winglets stand approximately 2.4 m tall and are installed at the
        wing tips. They improve fuel efficiency by up to 5% through lift-induced drag reduction achieved by moderating wingtip vortices. Split Scimitar winglets
        became available in 2014 for the 737-800, 737-900ER, BBJ2 and BBJ3, and in 2015 for the 737-700, 737-900 and BBJ1. Split Scimitar winglets were developed
        by Aviation Partners, the same Seattle-based corporation that developed the blended winglets; the Split Scimitar winglets produce up to a 5.5% fuel savings
        per aircraft compared to 3.3% savings for the blended winglets. Southwest Airlines flew their first flight of a 737-800 with Split Scimitar winglets on April
        14, 2014. The next generation 737, 737 MAX, will feature an Advanced Technology (AT) Winglet that is produced by Boeing. The Boeing AT Winglet resembles a
        cross between the Blended Winglet and the Split Scimitar Winglet.\n</string>

    <string name="b737_desc3">\nBoeing 737 variants include 737 Original (first generation) - 737-100, 737-200, 737 Classic (second generation) - 737-300, 737-400,
        737-500, 737 NG (third generation) - 737-600, 737-700, 737-800, 737-900, and 737 MAX (fourth generation) - 737 MAX-7, 737 MAX-8, 737 MAX-9, 737 MAX-10.\n</string>

    <string name="b737_specs_constraint">(-100, -200, -300/-400/-500, -600/-700/-800/-900, MAX-7/-8/-9/-10 compared in order)\n</string>


    <string name="b737_identify">How to identify Boeing 737?</string>
    <string name="b737_identify_ans">\"Pointed\" nose, triangular dorsal-fin section in front of the tail, \"V\" shaped side windshield, retracted main landing gear not enclosed in the
        fuselage, winglets: none / large L-shaped / \">\" shaped with upward and downward aerofoils (split winglets); cowling design engines / ovoid \"hamster pouch\" inlet / 787-derived engine chevron-toothed pattern on the rim of the nacelles
        of both the engines of MAX variants.</string>

    <string name="b737_cockpit_value">2</string>
    <string name="b737_wingspan_value">28 m (Original) / 28.88 / 34.32 / 35.92 m</string>
    <string name="b737_length_value">29 / 30.53 / 31–37 / 31–42 / 35.56–43.8 m</string>
    <string name="b737_height_value">11 m (Original) / 11.13 / 12 / 12.29 m</string>
    <string name="b737_fuselage_value">3.8 m (W) / ~4.0 m (H)</string>
    <string name="b737_mtow_value">50 / 58.1 / 60.6-68 / 65.5-85.1 / 80.3-88.3 t</string>
    <string name="b737_cruise_speed_value">796 km/h (typical),\n876 km/h (max.)\n(Original &amp; Classic) /\n838 km/h (NG &amp; MAX)</string>
    <string name="b737_range_value">1,540 / 2,600 / 2,060–2,375 / 2,935–3,010 / 3,300–3,850 nmi</string>
    <string name="b737_thrust_value">62 / 64–73 / 89–105 / 89–120 / 130 kN</string>
    <!--BOEING 737-->


    <!--BOEING 747-->
    <string name="b747_type_value">Wide-body\nairliner</string>
    <string name="b747_engine_value">P&amp;W JT9D/PW4000 /\nRR RB211 / GE CF6/GEnx-2B67 (4)</string>
    <string name="b747_first_flight_value">9 February 1969</string>
    <string name="b747_intro_value">22 January 1970\nwith Pan Am</string>
    <string name="b747_customer_value">Atlas Air</string>
    <string name="b747_variants_value">22 (active)</string>

    <string name="b747_desc1" formatted="false">The Boeing 747 is a large, long-range wide-body airliner manufactured by Boeing Commercial Airplanes in the
        United States. The 747 is a quadjet, initially powered by JT9D turbofan engines, then GE CF6 and Rolls-Royce RB211 engines for the original variants. With a
        ten-abreast economy seating, it typically accommodates 366 passengers in three travel classes. It has a pronounced 37.5° wing sweep, allowing a Mach
        0.85 (490 kn; 900 km/h) cruise speed, and its heavy weight is supported by four main landing gear legs with four-wheel bogies each. The partial double-deck
        aircraft was designed with a raised cockpit so it could be converted to a freighter airplane by installing a front cargo door, as it was initially thought
        that it would eventually be superseded by supersonic transports. As of May 2021, 1,564 747s have been built.\n\nThe original design included a full-length double-deck
        fuselage with eight-across seating and two aisles on the lower deck and seven-across seating and two aisles on the upper deck. However, concern over evacuation
        routes and limited cargo-carrying capability caused this idea to be scrapped in early 1966 in favor of a wider single deck design. The cockpit was, therefore,
        placed on a shortened upper deck so that a freight-loading door could be included in the nose cone; this design feature produced the 747\'s distinctive \"hump\". In early
        models it was not clear what to do with the small space in the pod behind the cockpit, and this was initially specified as a \"lounge\" area with no permanent seating. A different configuration that had been considered in order to keep the flight deck out of the way for freight loading had the pilots
        below the passengers, and was dubbed the \"anteater\". One of the principal technologies that enabled an aircraft as large as the 747 to be drawn up was the
        high-bypass turbofan engine. The engine technology was thought to be capable of delivering double the power of the earlier turbojets while consuming one-third
        less fuel. General Electric had pioneered the concept but was committed to developing the engine for the C-5 Galaxy and did not enter the commercial market
        until later. Pratt &amp; Whitney was also working on the same principle and, by late 1966, Boeing, Pan Am and Pratt &amp; Whitney agreed to develop a new engine,
        designated the JT9D to power the 747.\n\nThe project was designed with a new methodology called fault tree analysis, which allowed the effects of a failure of a
        single part to be studied to determine its impact on other systems. To address concerns about safety and flyability, the 747\'s design included structural
        redundancy, redundant hydraulic systems, quadruple main landing gear and dual control surfaces. Additionally, some of the most advanced high-lift devices
        used in the industry were included in the new design, to allow it to operate from existing airports. These included Krueger flaps running almost the entire
        length of the wings leading edge, as well as complex three-part slotted flaps along the trailing edge of the wing. The wing\'s complex three-part flaps increase
        wing area by 21 percent and lift by 90 percent when fully deployed compared to their non-deployed configuration.\n</string>


    <string name="b747_desc2" formatted="false">The 747 is a large, wide-body (two-aisle) airliner with four wing-mounted engines. Its wings have a high sweep angle of
        37.5 degrees for a fast, efficient cruise speed of Mach 0.84 to 0.88, depending on the variant. The sweep also reduces the wingspan, allowing the 747 to use
        existing hangars. Its seating capacity is over 366 with a 3–4–3 seat arrangement (a cross section of 3 seats, an aisle, 4 seats, another aisle, and 3 seats) in
        economy class and a 2–3–2 layout in first class on the main deck. The upper deck has a 3–3 seat arrangement in economy class and a 2–2 layout in
        first class. Raised above the main deck, the cockpit creates the hump. This raised cockpit allows front loading of cargo on freight variants. The upper deck behind
        the cockpit provides space for a lounge and/or extra seating. The \"stretched upper deck\" became available as an alternative on the 747-100B variant and
        later as standard beginning on the 747-300. The upper deck was stretched more on the 747-8. The 747 cockpit roof section also has an escape hatch from which
        crew can exit during the events of an emergency if they cannot do so through the cabin.\n\nThe 747 has redundant structures along with four redundant hydraulic
        systems and four main landing gears each with four wheels; these provide a good spread of support on the ground and safety in case of tire blow-outs. The main
        gear are redundant so that landing can be performed on two opposing landing gears if the others are not functioning properly. The 747 also has split control
        surfaces and was designed with sophisticated triple-slotted flaps that minimize landing speeds and allow the 747 to use standard-length runways. For transportation
        of spare engines, the 747 can accommodate a non-functioning fifth-pod engine under the aircraft\'s port wing between the inner functioning engine and the
        fuselage. This fifth engine mount point is also used by Virgin Orbit\'s LauncherOne program. Virgin Orbit\'s 747-400, dubbed Cosmic Girl, carries the
        orbital-class rocket to cruise altitude, where the rocket is deployed and then carries its small satellite payload the rest of the way to orbit.\n\nIt
        is this 747 that carried over 1000 people during the Operation Solomon evacuation, beating Quantas\' 747 evacuation record of 674. During the
        flight, 2 babies were born on the 747. It can also be stated that the 747 has flown more than 3.5 billion people by now, which is almost half the
        planet\'s population.\n</string>

    <string name="b747_desc3">\nBoeing 747 variants include 747-100, 747SR, 7474-100B, 747SP, 747-200, 747-300, 747-400, 747 LCF Dreamlifter, 747-8. Its
        government, military, and other variants are C-19, VC-25, E-4B, YAL-1, C-33, KC-33A, 747-100 Tanker, 747 CMCA, 747 AAC, Evergreen 747 Supertanker, Stratospheric
        Observatory for Infrared Astronomy (SOFIA), VIP transports. Undeveloped variants include 747 trijet, 747-500, 747 ASB, 747-500X, -600X, and -700X, 747X
        and 747X Stretch, 747-400XQLR.\n</string>

    <string name="b747_specs_constraint">(SP, -100, -200B, -300, -400, and -8 compared in order)\n</string>


    <string name="b747_identify">How to identify Boeing 747?</string>
    <string name="b747_identify_ans">There is nothing quite like it with 4 engines and the \"hump\".</string>

    <string name="b747_cockpit_value">3 / 2 (-400/-8)</string>
    <string name="b747_wingspan_value">59.6 m / 64.4 m (-400) /\n68.4 m (-8)</string>
    <string name="b747_length_value">56.3 m (SP) / 70.66 m /\n76.25 m (-8)</string>
    <string name="b747_height_value">19.9 m (SP) / 19.3 m /\n19.4 m (-400/-8)</string>
    <string name="b747_fuselage_value">~6.1 (W) / ~6.2 m (H)</string>
    <string name="b747_mtow_value">317.5 / 333.4 / 377.8 (-200B/-300) /\n412.8 / 447.7 t</string>
    <string name="b747_cruise_speed_value">907 km/h (typical),\n939 km/h (max.)</string>
    <string name="b747_range_value">5,830 / 4,620 / 6,560 /\n6,330 / 7,670 / 7,730</string>
    <string name="b747_thrust_value">206–253 / 193–230 / 206–243.5 /\n206–253 / 276–282 / 296 kN</string>
    <!--BOEING 747-->


    <!--BOEING 757-->
    <string name="b757_type_value">Narrow-body\nairliner</string>
    <string name="b757_engine_value">Pratt &amp; Whitney PW2000 /\nRolls-Royce RB211 (2)</string>
    <string name="b757_first_flight_value">19 February 1982</string>
    <string name="b757_intro_value">1 January 1983 with\nEastern Air Lines</string>
    <string name="b757_customer_value">Delta Air Lines</string>
    <string name="b757_variants_value">12 (active)</string>

    <string name="b757_desc1" formatted="false">The Boeing 757 is an American narrow-body airliner that was designed and built by Boeing Commercial Airplanes. The
        then-named 7N7, a twinjet successor for the 727 (a trijet), received its first orders in August 1978. The prototype completed its maiden flight on February
        19, 1982 and it was FAA certified on December 21, 1982. Eastern Air Lines placed the original 757-200 in commercial service on January 1, 1983. A package
        freighter (PF) variant entered service in September 1987 and a combi model in September 1988. The stretched 757-300 was launched in September 1996 and began
        service in March 1999. After 1,050 had been built for 54 customers, production ended in October 2004, while Boeing offered the largest 737 NG variants as
        a successor. During its production phase from 1981 to 2004, a total of 1,050 757s were built.\n\nThe 757 was intended to be more capable and more efficient
        than the preceding 727. The focus on fuel efficiency reflected airline concerns over operating costs, which had grown amid rising oil prices during the Yom
        Kippur War of 1973. Design targets included a 20 percent reduction in fuel consumption from new engines, plus 10 percent from aerodynamic improvements, versus
        preceding aircraft. Lighter materials and new wings were also expected to improve efficiency. The maximum take-off weight (MTOW) was set at 99,800 kg, which
        was 4,540 kg more than the 727. The 757\'s higher thrust-to-weight ratio allowed it to take off from short runways and serve airports in hot and high
        conditions with higher ambient temperatures and thinner air, offering better takeoff performance than that offered by competing aircraft. Competitors needed
        longer takeoff runs for these hot and high conditions. Boeing also offered options for higher payload capability.\n\nBoeing 757 is a low-wing cantilever monoplane
        with a conventional tail unit featuring a single fin and rudder. Each wing features a supercritical cross-section and is equipped with five-panel leading edge
        slats, single- and double-slotted flaps, an outboard aileron, and six spoilers. The wings are largely identical across all 757 variants, swept at 25
        degrees. The reduced wing sweep eliminates the need for inboard ailerons, yet incurs
        little drag penalty on short and medium length routes, during which most of the flight is spent climbing or descending. The airframe further incorporates
        carbon-fiber reinforced plastic wing surfaces, Kevlar fairings and access panels, plus improved aluminum alloys, which together reduce overall weight
        by 950 kg. To distribute the aircraft\'s weight on the ground, the 757 has a retractable tricycle landing gear with four wheels on each main gear and two
        for the nose gear. The landing gear was purposely designed to be taller than the company\'s previous narrow-body aircraft to provide ground clearance for
        stretched models. In 1982, the 757-200 became the first subsonic jetliner to offer longer lasting carbon brakes as a factory option, supplied by Dunlop. The
        stretched 757-300 features a retractable tailskid on its aft fuselage to prevent damage if the tail section contacts the runway surface during takeoff.\n</string>


    <string name="b757_desc2" formatted="false">The longest narrow-body airliner\'s flight deck uses six Rockwell Collins CRT screens to display flight instrumentation, as well as an
        electronic flight instrument system (EFIS) and an engine indication and crew alerting system (EICAS). These systems allow the pilots to handle monitoring
        tasks previously performed by the flight engineer. An enhanced flight management system, improved over versions used on early 747s, automates navigation
        and other functions, while an automatic landing system facilitates CAT IIIb instrument landings in 150 m low visibility conditions. The inertial
        reference system (IRS) which debuted with the 757-200 was the first to feature laser-light gyros. On the 757-300, the upgraded flight deck features a Honeywell
        Pegasus flight management computer, enhanced EICAS, and updated software systems.\n\nThree independent hydraulic systems are installed on the 757, one powered
        by each engine, and the third using electric pumps. A ram air turbine is fitted to provide power for essential controls in the event of an emergency. A basic
        form of fly-by-wire facilitates spoiler operation, utilizing electric signaling instead of traditional control cables. The fly-by-wire system, shared with the
        767, reduces weight and provides for the independent operation of individual spoilers. When equipped for extended-range operations, the 757 features a backup
        hydraulic motor generator and an additional cooling fan in the aircraft\'s electronics bay. The 757 interior allows seat arrangements of up to six per row with a
        single center aisle. Originally optimized for flights averaging two hours, the 757 features interior lighting and cabin architecture designs aimed at a more
        spacious impression. As on the 767, garment-bag-length overhead bins and a rear economy-class galley are standard equipment. The bins have twice the capacity
        as those on the preceding 727. To save weight, honeycomb sandwich is used for interior paneling and bins. Unlike previous evacuation slide designs which are not
        equipped for water landings, the 757\'s main exits feature combination slide rafts similar to those found on the 747. In the 1980s, Boeing altered the interior
        designs of its other narrow-body aircraft to be similar to that of the 757.\n</string>

    <string name="b757_desc3">\nThe Boeing 757 variants include 757-100 (dropped), 757-200, 757-200PF, 757-200M, 757-200 SF/PCF, 757-300, Airborne Research Integrated Experiments
        System (ARIES) for air safety and operational research, C-32 - The United States Air Force (USAF) operates four VIP-configured 757-200s under
        the designation C-32A for missions including transporting the President of the United States and/or the Vice President of the United States, F-22 Flying
        Testbed, one for Krueger flap and Natural Laminar Flow Insect Mitigation Test Program, one for Active Flow Control System, Royal New Zealand Air Force 757 Combi, and
        VIP Transports.\n</string>

    <string name="b757_specs_constraint">(-200, -200F, -300 compared in order)\n</string>


    <string name="b757_identify">How to identify Boeing 757?</string>
    <string name="b757_identify_ans">Pointed \"dolphin\" nose, tall landing gears, \"V\" shaped side windshield, 3 cabin doors and either 1 emergency exit aft of wing
        or 2 over-wing exits (-200) / 4 cabin doors and 2 over-wing emergency exits (-300), winglets: none (-200), blended large L-shaped (-300).</string>

    <string name="b757_cockpit_value">2</string>
    <string name="b757_wingspan_value">38.0 m</string>
    <string name="b757_length_value">47.3 m (-200 / -200F) / 54.4 m</string>
    <string name="b757_height_value">13.6 m</string>
    <string name="b757_fuselage_value">3.76 m (W) / ~3.8 m (H)</string>
    <string name="b757_mtow_value">115.66 t (-200/-200F) /\n123.83 t</string>
    <string name="b757_cruise_speed_value">854 km/h (typical),\n918 km/h (max.)</string>
    <string name="b757_range_value">3,915 / 2,935 / 3,400 nmi</string>
    <string name="b757_thrust_value">179–193 kN (RR RB211) /\n163–189 kN (P &amp; W PW2000)</string>
    <!--BOEING 757-->


    <!--BOEING 767-->
    <string name="b767_type_value">Wide-body\nairliner</string>
    <string name="b767_engine_value">P&amp;W JT9D / PW4000 /\nGE CF6 / RR RB211 (2)</string>
    <string name="b767_first_flight_value">26 September 1981</string>
    <string name="b767_intro_value">8 September 1982\nwith United Airlines</string>
    <string name="b767_customer_value">Delta Air Lines</string>
    <string name="b767_variants_value">14 (active)</string>

    <string name="b767_desc1" formatted="false">Boeing 767 was launched as the 7X7 project on July 14, 1978, the prototype first flew on September 26, 1981, and it was
        certified on July 30, 1982. The original 767-200 entered service on September 8, 1982 with United Airlines, and the extended-range 767-200ER in 1984. It was
        stretched into the 767-300 in October 1986, followed by the 767-300ER in 1988, the most popular variant. The 767-300F, a production freighter version, debuted
        in October 1995. It was stretched again into the 767-400ER from September 2000. In the late 1970s, operating cost replaced capacity as the primary factor in
        airliner purchases. As a result, the 767\'s design process emphasized fuel efficiency from the outset. Boeing targeted a 20 to 30 percent cost saving over
        earlier aircraft, mainly through new engine and wing technology. As development progressed, engineers used computer-aided design for over a third of the
        767\'s design drawings, and performed 26,000 hours of wind tunnel tests. Design work occurred concurrently with the 757 twinjet, leading Boeing to treat both as
        almost one program to reduce risk and cost. Both aircraft would ultimately receive shared design features, including avionics, flight management systems,
        instruments, and handling characteristics. Combined development costs were estimated at $3.5 to $4 billion. As of June 2021, a total of 1219 767s have been
        built.\n\nThe 767 was the first Boeing wide-body to be designed with a two-crew digital glass cockpit. Cathode ray tube (CRT) color displays and new
        electronics replaced the role of the flight engineer by enabling the pilot and co-pilot to monitor aircraft systems directly. Despite the promise of reduced
        crew costs, United Airlines initially demanded a conventional three-person cockpit, citing concerns about the risks associated with introducing a new
        aircraft. The carrier maintained this position until July 1981, when a US presidential task force determined that a crew of two was safe for operating
        wide-body jets. A three-crew cockpit remained as an option and was fitted to the first production models. Ansett Australia ordered 767s with three-crew cockpits
        due to union demands; it was the only airline to operate 767s so configured. The 767\'s two-crew cockpit was also applied to the 757, allowing pilots to operate
        both aircraft after a short conversion course, and adding incentive for airlines to purchase both types.\n</string>


    <string name="b767_desc2" formatted="false">The 767 is a low-wing cantilever monoplane with a conventional tail unit featuring a single fin and rudder. The wings
        are swept at 31.5 degrees and optimized for a cruising speed of Mach 0.8 (858 km/h). Each wing features a supercritical airfoil cross-section and is equipped
        with six-panel leading edge slats, single- and double-slotted flaps, inboard and outboard ailerons, and six spoilers. The airframe further incorporates
        carbon-fiber-reinforced polymer composite material wing surfaces, Kevlar fairings and access panels, plus improved aluminum alloys, which together reduce
        overall weight by 860 kg versus preceding aircraft. To distribute the aircraft\'s weight on the ground, the 767 has a retractable tricycle landing gear with
        four wheels on each main gear and two for the nose gear. The original wing and gear design accommodated the stretched 767-300 without major changes. The
        767-400ER features a larger, more widely spaced main gear with 777 wheels, tires, and brakes. To prevent damage if the tail section contacts the runway surface
        during takeoff, 767-300 and 767-400ER models are fitted with a retractable tailskid.\n\nIn addition to shared avionics and computer technology, the 767 uses the same auxiliary power unit, electric power systems, and hydraulic parts as
        the 757. A raised cockpit floor and the same forward cockpit windows result in similar pilot viewing angles. Related design and functionality allows 767
        pilots to obtain a common type rating to operate the 757 and share the same seniority roster with pilots of either aircraft. The original 767 flight deck uses
        six Rockwell Collins CRT screens to display Electronic flight instrument system (EFIS) and engine indication and crew alerting system (EICAS) information,
        allowing pilots to handle monitoring tasks previously performed by the flight engineer. The CRTs replace conventional electromechanical instruments found on
        earlier aircraft. An enhanced flight management system, improved over versions used on early 747s, automates navigation and other functions, while
        an automatic landing system facilitates CAT IIIb instrument landings in low visibility situations. The 767 became the first aircraft to receive CAT IIIb
        certification from the FAA for landings with 300 m minimum visibility in 1984. On the 767-400ER, the cockpit layout is simplified further with six Rockwell
        Collins liquid crystal display (LCD) screens, and adapted for similarities with the 777 and the Next Generation 737.\n\nTo retain operational commonality, the
        LCD screens can be programmed to display information in the same manner as earlier 767s. In 2012, Boeing and Rockwell Collins launched a further 787-based cockpit
        upgrade for the 767, featuring three landscape-format LCD screens that can display two windows each. The 767 is equipped with three redundant hydraulic systems
        for operation of control surfaces, landing gear, and utility actuation systems. Each engine powers a separate hydraulic system, and the third system uses
        electric pumps. A ram air turbine provides power for basic controls in the event of an emergency. An early form of fly-by-wire is employed for spoiler operation,
        utilizing electric signaling instead of traditional control cables. The fly-by-wire system reduces weight and allows independent operation of
        individual spoilers.\n</string>

    <string name="b767_desc3">\n767 variants include 767-200, 767-2C, 767-200ER, 767-300, 767-300ER, 767-300F, 767-400ER. Military and government variants are comprised
        of Airborne Surveillance Testbed, E-767, KC-767 Tanker Transport, KC-767 Advanced Tanker, KC-46, 767 MMTT, E-10 MC2A. Other variants once considered by
        Boeing that did not make into the production phase include 767-X and 767-400ERX. Boeing is also studying a re-engined 767-XF for around 2025, based on the
        767-400ER with an extended landing gear to accommodate larger General Electric GEnx turbofan engines. The cargo market is the main target, but a passenger
        version could be a cheaper alternative to the proposed New Midsize Airplane.\n</string>

    <string name="b767_specs_constraint">(-200, -200ER, -300, -300ER/F, -400ER compared in order)\n</string>


    <string name="b767_identify">How to identify Boeing 767?</string>
    <string name="b767_identify_ans">\"V\" shaped side windshield, The 767-300 and -400 have emergency exit doors before the wing and after the wing, 4-wheel main landing gear. The -200
        has one emergency exit above the wing. The 767-300 and -400 each come with a retractable tailskid added to protect the tail of
        these longer versions from damaging tail strikes on takeoff. Added bonus for -400, it has blended large L-shaped wingtips, while other variants don\'t.</string>

    <string name="b767_cockpit_value">2</string>
    <string name="b767_wingspan_value">47.57 m / 51.92 m (-400ER)</string>
    <string name="b767_length_value">48.51 m (-200/ER) / 54.94 m (-300/ER) /\n61.37 m</string>
    <string name="b767_height_value">15.85 m / 16.87 m (-400ER)</string>
    <string name="b767_fuselage_value">5.03 m (W) / 5.41 m (H)</string>
    <string name="b767_mtow_value">142.9 / 179.2 / 158.8 /\n 186.9 / 204.1 t</string>
    <string name="b767_cruise_speed_value">850 km/h (typical),\n900 km/h (max.)</string>
    <string name="b767_range_value">3,900 / 6,590 / 3,900 /\n5,980 / 5,625 nmi</string>
    <string name="b767_thrust_value">214–234 / 214–270 / 214–270 /\n252–274 / 270 kN</string>
    <!--BOEING 767-->


    <!--BOEING 777-->
    <string name="b777_type_value">Wide-body\nairliner</string>
    <string name="b777_engine_value">P&amp;W PW4000 / GE GE90 /\nRR Trent 800 (2)</string>
    <string name="b777_first_flight_value">12 June 1994</string>
    <string name="b777_intro_value">7 June 1995 with\nUnited Airlines</string>
    <string name="b777_customer_value">Emirates</string>
    <string name="b777_variants_value">9 (active)</string>

    <string name="b777_desc1" formatted="false">The Boeing 777, commonly referred to as the Triple Seven, is an American wide-body airliner developed and manufactured by
        Boeing Commercial Airplanes. It is the world\'s largest twinjet. The 777 was designed to bridge the gap between Boeing\'s 767 and 747, and to replace older
        DC-10s and L-1011s. Developed in consultation with eight major airlines, with a first meeting in January 1990, the program was launched on October 14, 1990, with
        an order from United Airlines. The prototype was rolled out on April 9, 1994, and first flew on June 12, 1994. The 777 entered service with the launch
        customer, United Airlines, on June 7, 1995. Longer range variants were launched on February 29, 2000, and were first delivered on April 29, 2004. As of June
        2021, a total of 1,667 777s have been built.\n\nIn the early 1970s, the Boeing 747, McDonnell Douglas DC-10, and the Lockheed L-1011 TriStar became the first
        generation of wide-body passenger airliners to enter service. In 1978, Boeing unveiled three new models: the twin-engine Boeing 757 to replace its 727, the
        twin-engine 767 to challenge the Airbus A300, and a trijet 777 concept to compete with the DC-10 and L-1011. The mid-size 757 and 767 launched to market success,
        due in part to 1980s\' extended-range twin-engine operational performance standards (ETOPS) regulations governing transoceanic twinjet operations. These
        regulations allowed twin-engine airliners to make ocean crossings at up to three hours\' distance from emergency diversionary airports. Under ETOPS rules,
        airlines began operating the 767 on long-distance overseas routes that did not require the capacity of larger airliners.\n\nThe trijet 777 was later dropped,
        following marketing studies that favored the 757 and 767 variants. Boeing was left with a size and range gap in its product line between the 767-300ER and
        the 747-400. Airline customers were uninterested in the 767-X proposals, and instead wanted an even wider fuselage cross-section, fully flexible interior
        configurations, short- to intercontinental-range capability, and an operating cost lower than that of any 767 stretch. Airline planners\' requirements for
        larger aircraft had become increasingly specific, adding to the heightened competition among aircraft manufacturers. By 1988, Boeing realized that the only
        answer was a new clean-sheet design, which became the 777 twin-jet. The company opted for the twin-engine configuration given past design successes, projected
        engine developments, and reduced-cost benefits. On December 8, 1989, Boeing began issuing offers to airlines for the 777.\n</string>


    <string name="b777_desc2" formatted="false">Boeing introduced a number of advanced technologies with the 777 design, including fully digital fly-by-wire controls,
        fully software-configurable avionics, Honeywell LCD glass cockpit flight displays, and the first use of a fiber optic avionics network on a commercial
        airliner. Boeing made use of work done on the cancelled Boeing 7J7 regional jet, which utilized similar versions of the chosen technologies. In 2003, Boeing
        began offering the option of cockpit electronic flight bag computer displays. In 2013, Boeing announced that the upgraded 777X models would incorporate
        airframe, systems, and interior technologies from the 787. In designing the 777 as its first fly-by-wire commercial aircraft, Boeing decided to retain
        conventional control yokes rather than change to sidestick controllers as used in many fly-by-wire fighter aircraft and in many Airbus airliners. Along with
        traditional yoke and rudder controls, the cockpit features a simplified layout that retains similarities to previous Boeing models. The fly-by-wire system
        also incorporates flight envelope protection, a system that guides pilot inputs within a computer-calculated framework of operating parameters, acting to
        prevent stalls, overspeeds, and excessively stressful maneuvers. This system can be overridden by the pilot if deemed necessary. The fly-by-wire system is
        supplemented by mechanical backup.\n\nThe wings on the 777 feature a supercritical airfoil design that is swept back at 31.6 degrees and optimized for cruising
        at Mach 0.83 (revised after flight tests up to Mach 0.84). The wings are designed with increased thickness and a longer span than previous airliners, resulting
        in greater payload and range, improved takeoff performance, and a higher cruising altitude. The wings also serve as fuel storage, with longer-range models able
        to carry up to 181,300 L of fuel. This capacity allows the 777-200LR to operate ultra-long-distance, trans-polar routes such as Toronto to Hong Kong. In 2013, a
        new wing made of composite materials was introduced for the upgraded 777X, with a wider span and design features based on the 787\'s wings. Unlike smaller
        airliners like the Boeing 737, no current 777 wings have winglets; instead, the exceptionally long raked wings of the 777 serve the same drag-reducing function.
        Large folding wingtips, 6.40 m long, were offered when the 777 was first launched, to appeal to airlines who might use gates made to accommodate smaller
        aircraft, but no airline purchased this option. Folding wingtips reemerged as a design feature at the announcement of the upgraded 777X in 2013. Smaller
        folding wingtips of 3.35 m in length will allow 777X models to use the same airport gates and taxiways as earlier 777s. These smaller folding wingtips are less
        complex than those proposed for earlier 777s, and internally only affect the wiring needed for wingtip lights.\n\nThe airframe incorporates the use of composite
        materials, which comprise nine percent of its original structural weight (all models outside the 777-8 and 777-9). Elements made from composite material include
        the cabin floor and rudder. The main fuselage cross-section is circular and tapers rearward into a blade-shaped tail cone with a port-facing auxiliary power
        unit. The aircraft also features the largest landing gear and the biggest tires ever used in a commercial jetliner. The six-wheel bogies are designed to spread
        the load of the aircraft over a wide area without requiring an additional centerline gear. This helps reduce weight and simplifies the aircraft\'s braking and
        hydraulic systems. Each tire of a 777-300ER six-wheel main landing gear can carry a load of 26,980 kg, which is heavier than other wide-bodies such as the
        747-400. The aircraft has triple redundant hydraulic systems with only one system required for landing. A ram air turbine - a small retractable device which can
        provide emergency power - is also fitted in the wing root fairing.\n</string>

    <string name="b777_desc3">\nBoeing 777 variants include 777-200, 777-200ER, 777-200LR, 777-300, 777-300ER, 777 Freighter, 777-300ER Special Freighter (SF), the
        upcoming 777X, 777 Business Jet (777 VIP), and 777 Tanker (KC-777).\n</string>

    <string name="b777_specs_constraint">(-200/200ER, -300, -300ER, -200LR/777F compared in order)\n</string>


    <string name="b777_identify">How to identify Boeing 777?</string>
    <string name="b777_identify_ans">\"V\" shaped side windshield, slightly flattened top \"slant\" of the fuselage, flat APU exhaust, no wingtips, 6-wheel main
        landing gear, 4-5 exit doors across the length of the fuselage.</string>

    <string name="b777_cockpit_value">2</string>
    <string name="b777_wingspan_value">60.93 m (-200/200ER/-300) /\n64.80 m</string>
    <string name="b777_length_value">63.73 m / 73.86 m (-300/-300ER) /\n63.73 m</string>
    <string name="b777_height_value">18.5 / 18.5 / 18.6 m</string>
    <string name="b777_fuselage_value">6.20 m (W) / ~6.30 m (H)</string>
    <string name="b777_mtow_value">247.2 – 297.55 / 299.37 /\n351.53 / 347.45 – 347.82 t</string>
    <string name="b777_cruise_speed_value">892 km/h (typical),\n924–945 km/h (max.)</string>
    <string name="b777_range_value">5,240 – 7,065 / 6,030 /\n4,650 – 7,370 / 4,980 – 10,450 nmi</string>
    <string name="b777_thrust_value">343 – 417 / 440 / 513 / 489 – 513 kN</string>
    <!--BOEING 777-->


    <!--BOEING 787-->
    <string name="b787_type_value">Wide-body\nairliner</string>
    <string name="b787_engine_value">General Electric GEnx-1B /\nRolls-Royce Trent 1000 (2)</string>
    <string name="b787_first_flight_value">15 December 2009</string>
    <string name="b787_intro_value">26 October 2011\nwith All Nippon Airways</string>
    <string name="b787_customer_value">All Nippon Airways</string>
    <string name="b787_variants_value">4 (active)</string>

    <string name="b787_desc1" formatted="false">The Boeing 787 Dreamliner is an American wide-body jet airliner manufactured by Boeing Commercial Airplanes. After
        dropping its Sonic Cruiser project, Boeing announced the conventional 7E7 on January 29, 2003, focused on efficiency. The program was launched on April 26,
        2004, with an order for 50 from All Nippon Airways (ANA), targeting a 2008 introduction. On July 8, 2007, the prototype was rolled out without major systems, and
        experienced multiple delays until its maiden flight on December 15, 2009. Type certification was received in August 2011 and the first 787-8 was delivered
        in September 2011 before entering commercial service on October 26, 2011, with ANA. As of June 2021, a total of 1,006 787s have been built.\n\nThe Boeing 787
        Dreamliner is a long-haul, widebody, twin-engine jetliner, which features light-weight construction. The aircraft is 80% composite by volume; Boeing lists its
        materials by weight as 50% composite, 20% aluminum, 15% titanium, 10% steel, and 5% other. Aluminum has been used throughout the wing and tail leading edges,
        titanium is predominantly present within the elements of the engines and fasteners, while various individual components are composed of steel. External
        features include a smooth nose contour, raked wingtips and engine nacelles with noise-reducing serrated edges (chevrons). The longest-range 787 variant can
        fly up to 7,635 nmi, or the even longer Qantas QF 9 flight between Perth Airport and London–Heathrow, over 7,828 nmi. The aircraft has a design life
        of 44,000 flight cycles. Among 787 flight systems, a key change from traditional airliners is the electrical architecture. The architecture is bleedless and
        replaces bleed air with electrically powered compressors and four of six hydraulic power sources with electrically driven pumps, while completely eliminating
        pneumatics and hydraulics from some subsystems, e.g. engine starters and brakes. Boeing says that this system extracts 35% less power from the engines, allowing
        increased thrust and improved fuel efficiency. The total available on-board electrical power is 1.45 megawatts, which is five times the power available on
        conventional pneumatic airliners; the most notable electrically powered systems include engine start, cabin pressurization, horizontal-stabilizer trim, and
        wheel brakes. Wing ice protection is another new system; it uses electro-thermal heater mats on the wing slats instead of traditional hot bleed air. An active
        gust alleviation system, similar to the system used on the B-2 bomber, improves ride quality during turbulence.\n\nThe 787 has a \"fly-by-wire\" control system
        similar in architecture to that of the Boeing 777. The flight deck features multi-function LCDs, which use an industry-standard graphical user interface
        widget toolkit (Cockpit Display System Interfaces to User Systems / ARINC 661). The 787 flight deck includes two head-up displays (HUDs) as a standard
        feature. Like other Boeing airliners, the 787 uses a yoke (as opposed to a side-stick). Under consideration is future integration of forward-looking infrared
        into the HUD for thermal sensing, allowing pilots to \"see\" through clouds. Lockheed Martin\'s Orion spacecraft will use a glass cockpit derived from
        Honeywell International\'s 787 flight deck systems. In 2016, Rolls-Royce began flight testing its new Trent 1000 TEN engine. It has a new compressor system
        based on the compressor in Rolls-Royce Trent XWB engine and a new turbine design for extra thrust, up to 350 kN. Rolls-Royce plans to offer the TEN on the 787-8,
        -9 and -10. In early 2020, of 1484 orders, 905 selected GE (61.0%), 476 selected RR (32.1%) and 103 were undecided (6.90%).\n</string>


    <string name="b787_desc2" formatted="false">787 Dreamliner is the first major commercial airplane to have a composite fuselage, composite wings, and use composites in
        most other airframe components. Each 787 contains approximately 35 metric tons of carbon fiber reinforced polymer (CFRP), made with 23 t of carbon fiber. Carbon
        fiber composites have a higher strength-to-weight ratio than conventional aircraft materials, and help make the 787 a lighter aircraft. Composites are used on
        fuselage, wings, tail, doors, and interior. Boeing had built and tested the first commercial aircraft composite section while studying the proposed Sonic Cruiser
        in the early 2000s. The first carbon/epoxy primary structure was put into service on the Boeing 737 Classic horizontal tail in 1984, and the largest use of
        composite structures is 60 percent in the Boeing–Sikorsky RAH-66 Comanche.\n\nCarbon fiber, unlike metal, does not visibly show cracks and fatigue, prompting
        concerns about the safety risks of widespread use of the material; the rival Airbus A350 XWB uses composite panels on a frame, a more conventional approach,
        which its contractors regarded as less risky. Although fired in 2006, Boeing engineer Vince Weldon complained to management, and later to the public: the
        composite fuselage was unsafe compared to conventional aluminum designs, and in a crash, was more likely to \"shatter too easily and burn with toxic fumes\". In
        addition, a potential issue is the porous nature of composite materials: collected moisture expanding with altitude can cause delamination. Boeing responded that
        composites have been used on wings and other passenger aircraft parts for many years without incident, and special defect detection procedures will be instituted
        for the 787 to detect any potential hidden damage.\n\nBoeing 787 is powered by two engines; these engines use all-electrical bleedless systems, eliminating the
        superheated air conduits normally used for aircraft power, de-icing, and other functions. As part of its \"Quiet Technology Demonstrator 2\" project, Boeing
        adopted several engine noise-reducing technologies for the 787. These include an air inlet containing sound-absorbing materials and exhaust duct cover with a
        chevron-toothed pattern on the rim for a quieter mixing of exhaust and outside air. Boeing expects these developments to make the 787 significantly quieter
        both inside and out. The noise-reducing measures prevent sounds above 85 decibels from leaving airport boundaries. The two different engine models compatible
        with the 787 use a standard electrical interface to allow an aircraft to be fitted with either Rolls-Royce Trent 1000 or General Electric GEnx-1B engines. This
        interchangeability aims to save time and cost when changing engine types; while previous aircraft could exchange engines for those of a different manufacturer,
        the high cost and time required made it rare. In 2006, Boeing addressed reports of an extended change period by stating that the 787 engine swap was intended to
        take 24 hours.\n</string>

    <string name="b787_desc3">\nBoeing 787 Dreamliner variants include 787-8, 787-9, 787-10, BBJ 787 (Boeing Business Jets). On top of these, Boeing expects to build, possibly
        in the 2018–2023 timeframe, a 787 freighter version, Boeing 787-3. Boeing also reportedly considered a 787 variant as a candidate to replace the 747-based
        Boeing VC-25 presidential transport in 2009. In 2018, two Boeing 747-8 aircraft were ordered to replace the two older 747-200-based VC-25A Air Force
        One aircraft.\n</string>

    <string name="b787_specs_constraint">(-8, -9, -10 compared in order)\n</string>


    <string name="b787_identify">How to identify Boeing 787?</string>
    <string name="b787_identify_ans">Distinctive sleek, \"pointed\" nose with 4-piece windshield, raked wingtips, chevron-toothed pattern on the rim of the nacelles
        of both the engines, much curved wings than most aircraft.</string>

    <string name="b787_cockpit_value">2</string>
    <string name="b787_wingspan_value">60.12 m</string>
    <string name="b787_length_value">56.72 / 62.81 / 68.28 m</string>
    <string name="b787_height_value">16.92 m / 17.02 m (-9/-10)</string>
    <string name="b787_fuselage_value">5.77 m (W) / 5.94 m (H)</string>
    <string name="b787_mtow_value">227.93 t / 254.01 t (-9/-10)</string>
    <string name="b787_cruise_speed_value">903 km/h (typical),\n956 km/h (max.)</string>
    <string name="b787_range_value">7,355 / 7,635 / 6,430 nmi</string>
    <string name="b787_thrust_value">280 / 320 / 340 kN</string>
    <!--BOEING 787-->


    <!--BOEING C-17 GLOBEMASTER III-->
    <string name="globemaster_type_value">Military transport aircraft</string>
    <string name="globemaster_engine_value">Pratt &amp; Whitney\nF117-PW-100 (4)</string>
    <string name="globemaster_first_flight_value">15 September 1991</string>
    <string name="globemaster_intro_value">17 January 1995</string>
    <string name="globemaster_customer_value">United States Air Force</string>
    <string name="globemaster_variants_value">4</string>

    <string name="globemaster_desc1" formatted="false">The C-17 Globemaster III is a large military transport aircraft that was developed for the United States Air Force
        (USAF) from the 1980s to the early 1990s by McDonnell Douglas. The C-17 carries forward the name of two previous piston-engined military cargo aircraft, the Douglas
        C-74 Globemaster and the Douglas C-124 Globemaster II. The C-17 commonly performs tactical and strategic airlift missions, transporting troops and cargo throughout
        the world; additional roles include medical evacuation and airdrop duties. It was designed to replace the Lockheed C-141 Starlifter, and also fulfill some of the
        duties of the Lockheed C-5 Galaxy. Boeing, which merged with McDonnell Douglas in 1997, continued to manufacture C-17 aircraft after the merger. The transport is
        in service with the U.S. Air Force along with air arms of India, the United Kingdom, Australia, Canada, Qatar, the United Arab Emirates, Kuwait, and the
        Europe-based multilateral organization Heavy Airlift Wing. During its production phase from 1991 to 2005, a total of 279 Globemasters were built. The final
        C-17 was completed at the Long Beach, California plant and flown on 29 November 2015.\n\nIn the 1970s, the U.S. Air Force began looking for a replacement for its
        Lockheed C-130 Hercules tactical cargo aircraft. The Advanced Medium STOL Transport (AMST) competition was held, with Boeing proposing the YC-14, and McDonnell
        Douglas proposing the YC-15. Though both entrants exceeded specified requirements, the AMST competition was canceled before a winner was selected. The Air Force
        started the C-X program in November 1979 to develop a larger AMST with longer range to augment its strategic airlift. By 1980, the USAF found itself with a large
        fleet of aging C-141 Starlifter cargo aircraft. Compounding matters, USAF needed increased strategic airlift capabilities to fulfill its rapid-deployment airlift
        requirements. The USAF set mission requirements and released a request for proposals (RFP) for C-X in October 1980. McDonnell Douglas elected to develop a new
        aircraft based on the YC-15. Boeing bid an enlarged three-engine version of its AMST YC-14. Lockheed submitted two designs, a C-5-based design and an enlarged
        C-141 design. On 28 August 1981, McDonnell Douglas was chosen to build its proposed aircraft, then designated C-17. Compared to the YC-15, the new aircraft differed
        in having swept wings, increased size, and more powerful engines. This would allow it to perform the work done by the C-141, and to fulfill some of the duties of
        the Lockheed C-5 Galaxy, freeing the C-5 fleet for outsize cargo.\n\nAlternative proposals were pursued to fill airlift needs after the C-X contest. These were
        lengthening of C-141As into C-141Bs, ordering more C-5s, continued purchases of KC-10s, and expansion of the Civil Reserve Air Fleet. Limited budgets reduced
        program funding, requiring a delay of four years. During this time contracts were awarded for preliminary design work and for the completion of engine
        certification. In December 1985, a full-scale development contract was awarded, under Program Manager Bob Clepper. At this time, first flight was planned for 1990.
        The Air Force had formed a requirement for 210 aircraft. Development problems and limited funding caused delays in the late 1980s. Criticisms were made of the
        developing aircraft and questions were raised about more cost-effective alternatives during this time. In April 1990, Secretary of Defense Dick Cheney reduced the
        order from 210 to 120 aircraft. The maiden flight of the C-17 took place on 15 September 1991 from the McDonnell Douglas\'s plant in Long Beach, California, about
        a year behind schedule. The first aircraft (T-1) and five more production models (P1-P5) participated in extensive flight testing and evaluation at Edwards Air
        Force Base. Two complete airframes were built for static and repeated load testing.\n</string>

    <string name="globemaster_desc2" formatted="false">The C-17 Globemaster III is a strategic transport aircraft, able to airlift cargo close to a battle area. The size
        and weight of U.S. mechanized firepower and equipment have grown in recent decades from increased air mobility requirements, particularly for large or heavy
        non-palletized outsize cargo. It has a length of 53 m and a wingspan of 51.77 m, and uses about 8% composite materials, mostly in
        secondary structure and control surfaces. The C-17 is powered by four Pratt &amp; Whitney F117-PW-100 turbofan engines, which are based on the commercial Pratt
        &amp; Whitney PW2040 used on the Boeing 757. Each engine is rated at 180 kN of thrust. The engine\'s thrust reversers direct engine exhaust air upwards and forward,
        reducing the chances of foreign object damage by ingestion of runway debris, and providing enough reverse thrust to back the aircraft up on the ground while
        taxiing. The thrust reversers can also be used in flight at idle-reverse for added drag in maximum-rate descents. In vortex surfing tests performed by two C-17s, up
        to 10% fuel savings were reported.\n\nFor cargo operations the C-17 requires a crew of three: pilot, copilot, and loadmaster. The cargo compartment is 27 m long
        by 5.5 m wide by 3.76 m high. The cargo floor has rollers for palletized cargo but it can be flipped to provide a flat floor suitable for vehicles and other
        rolling stock. Cargo is loaded through a large aft ramp that accommodates rolling stock, such as a 69-ton (63-metric ton) M1 Abrams main battle tank, other armored
        vehicles, trucks, and trailers, along with palletized cargo. Maximum payload of the C-17 is 77,500 kg, and its maximum takeoff weight is 265,000 kg. With a payload
        of 73,000 kg and an initial cruise altitude of 8,500 m, the C-17 has an unrefueled range of about 2,400 nautical miles (4,400 kilometres) on the first 71 aircraft,
        and 2,800 nautical miles (5,200 kilometres) on all subsequent extended-range models that include a sealed center wing bay as a fuel tank. Boeing informally calls
        these aircraft the C-17 ER. The C-17\'s cruise speed is about 450 knots (830 km/h) (Mach 0.74). It is designed to airdrop 102 paratroopers and their
        equipment.\n\nThe C-17 is designed to operate from runways as short as 1,100 m and as narrow as 27 m. In addition, the C-17 can operate from unpaved, unimproved
        runways (although with greater chance of damage to the aircraft). The thrust reversers can be used to move the aircraft backwards and reverse direction on narrow
        taxiways using a three- (or more) point turn. The plane is designed for 20 man-hours of maintenance per flight hour, and a 74% mission availability rate.\n</string>

    <string name="globemaster_desc3">\nThe Globemaster comes in 4 variants, C-17A, C-17A ER, C-17B, and MD-17.\n</string>

    <string name="globemaster_specs_constraint">(C-17A)\n</string>


    <string name="globemaster_identify">How to identify Boeing C-17 Globemaster III?</string>
    <string name="globemaster_identify_ans">4 engines, T-shape tail, blended L-shaped wingtips, wide fuselage, most aircraft come in grey livery.</string>

    <string name="globemaster_cockpit_value">3</string>
    <string name="globemaster_wingspan_value">51.76 m</string>
    <string name="globemaster_length_value">53 m</string>
    <string name="globemaster_height_value">16.79 m</string>
    <string name="globemaster_mtow_value">265.3 t</string>
    <string name="globemaster_cruise_speed_value">830 km/h (typical),\n1,080 km/h (max.)</string>
    <string name="globemaster_range_value">2,420 nmi with\n71.2 t payload</string>
    <string name="globemaster_thrust_value">179.9 kN</string>
    <!--BOEING C-17 GLOBEMASTER III-->


    <!--LEARJET 75-->
    <string name="learjet75_type_value">Business jet</string>
    <string name="learjet75_engine_value">Honeywell TFE731-40BR\n(2)</string>
    <string name="learjet75_customer_value">Zenith Aviation</string>
    <string name="learjet75_variants_value">2</string>
    <string name="learjet75_numbers_value">145 by end of 2019</string>

    <string name="learjet75_desc1" formatted="false">The Learjet 75 is a mid-sized business jet airplane manufactured by the Learjet division of Canadian aircraft
        manufacturer Bombardier Aerospace. With the end of production in 2021 it will be the last LearJet model. These models feature new avionics, winglets, and
        powerful engines that use less fuel. It has been updated with touchscreen-controlled Garmin G5000 avionics and a modern interior. The combination
        of aerodynamic improvements, which lowered the design\'s drag by 2%, and 200 lbs less weight in the nose section resulted in an increased range of 4%. The
        canted winglet design was incorporated from the Bombardier Global 7500/8000. It is powered by 17.1 kN Honeywell TFE731-40BR turbofans with thrust
        reversers, have a MTOW of 9,800 kg and a fuel capacity of 2,750 kg for a maximum range of 2,050 nmi with four passengers. Typical cruise is Mach .76 and high-speed cruise
        is Mach .79, the ceiling is FL510 where the cabin altitude is 2,400 m. Their flat-floor cabin width is 1.50m by 1.55 m high, the Learjet 70\'s seven-seat cabin
        length is 5.38 and 6.05 m for the nine-seat, double-club Learjet 75. The forward galley facing the entry door is isolated by a pocket door from the seating
        area with a Lufthansa Technik cabin management, and the aft lavatory has a belted seat. The 1.4 m<sup><small><small>3</small></small></sup> external baggage
        hold is heated but not pressurized.\n</string>


    <string name="learjet75_desc2" formatted="false">At FL410, ISA + 3 °C (5 °F) and Mach .78 for 462 kn (856 km/h), its hourly fuel burn is 450 kg and 640 kg at
        Mach .80. Certified to the stricter FAR Part 25, the $13.8 million Learjet 75 competes with the Embraer Phenom 300 and the Citation CJ4, beating them in
        cabin volume, with 10.3 m<sup><small><small>3</small></small></sup> against 9.3 and 8.4 m<sup><small><small>3</small></small></sup> respectively, the Phenom
        having the same cross-section, larger than the 1.45 by 1.47 m CJ4. The Mach .81 capable Learjet is faster than the Mach .78 Phenom and the Mach .77
        CJ4, and the Phenom can fly 1,971 nmi (3,650 km) while the CJ4 can fly 2,165 nmi (4,010 km). The Learjet 75 received its type certificate from the FAA on 14
        November 2013. Deliveries began shortly thereafter. This delay in certification caused order cancellations, and Bombardier\'s overall deliveries fell below
        expectations. By 2016, production of Learjet 70 has been temporarily discontinued due to lack of orders (with Learjet 75 still being produced). The 100th
        Learjet 75 was delivered in June 2017. By January 2019, Bombardier has delivered 132 Learjet 40/40XRs, 454 45/45XRs, and nearly 130 70/75s, including 24 in
        2016 and 14 in 2017. In June, Bombardier launched the sub-$10 million Learjet 75 Liberty to compete with the Cessna CitationJet and Embraer Phenom 300 from
        2020, with six seats down from eight, no standard APU or lavatory sink, but still Part 25 and not FAR Part 23 certified, with a maximum payload of 1,320 kg
        and a range of 2,080 nmi (3,850 km). Bombardier announced the end of the production of Learjet aircraft by the end of 2021.\n</string>

    <string name="learjet75_desc3">\nThe business jet comes in 2 variants, the Learjet 75 and the Learjet 75 Liberty.\n</string>

    <string name="learjet75_specs_constraint">(Learjet 75)\n</string>


    <string name="learjet75_identify">How to identify Learjet 75?</string>
    <string name="learjet75_identify_ans"></string>

    <string name="learjet75_cockpit_value">2</string>
    <string name="learjet75_wingspan_value">15.5 m</string>
    <string name="learjet75_length_value">17.7 m</string>
    <string name="learjet75_height_value">4.31 m</string>
    <string name="learjet75_fuselage_value">1.56 m (W) / 1.50 m (H)</string>
    <string name="learjet75_mtow_value">9.75 t</string>
    <string name="learjet75_cruise_speed_value">861 km/h (typical)</string>
    <string name="learjet75_range_value">2,040 nmi</string>
    <string name="learjet75_thrust_value">17.1 kN</string>
    <!--LEARJET 75-->


    <!--CHALLENGER 650-->
    <string name="challenger650_type_value">Business jet</string>
    <string name="challenger650_engine_value">General Electric CF34-3B (2)</string>
    <string name="challenger650_first_flight_value">8 November 1978</string>
    <string name="challenger650_numbers_value">1066 as of\nOctober 2018</string>
    <string name="challenger650_variants_value">1</string>

    <string name="challenger650_desc1" formatted="false">The Challenger 650 is a member of the Bombardier Challenger 600 series, family of business jets developed by Canadair after a Bill Lear
        concept, and then produced from 1986 by its new owner, Bombardier Aerospace. At the end of 1975, Canadair began funding the development of LearStar 600, and
        then bought the design for a wide-cabin business jet in April 1976. On 29 October, the programme was launched, backed by the Canadian federal government, and
        designed to comply with new FAR part 25 standards. The Challenger is a twin-engined business jet, described by Flight International as being \"miniturised
        twinjet airliner in every respect\". While the Challenger is generally similar in configuration to previous aircraft of its type, some of its features stand
        out; for example, the use of a widened fuselage that allows a \"walk-about cabin\". The Challenger was also one of the first business jets to be designed with a
        supercritical wing. The wing was referred by Canadair as being one of the aircraft\'s most advanced features. In 2021, its price is estimated to be $32.4M.\n\nIt is also capable of performing short takeoffs
        while maintaining the speed and comfort levels normally associated with larger jetliners. The Challenger\'s wing has been referred to as being a modified
        NACA symmetrical aerofoil. Akin to other supercritical wings, it features a rounded leading edge, an inverted camber, a blunt trailing edge and scalloping of
        the underside. The twin-spar wing box structure spans the entire length of the wing and is compartmentalised to form five internal fuel tanks; these tanks can
        accommodate up to 14,661 lb of fuel, nearly half the aircraft\'s empty weight. The skins of the wings are produced via large milling machines, which in 1978 were
        claimed to be in excess of anything else in North America. Many elements, such as the flaps, ailerons and leading edge feature conventional construction; however,
        several parts, including the wing/fuselage fairing, flap shrouds and wingtips are molded out of Kevlar, as are other elements of the aircraft.\n</string>


    <string name="challenger650_desc2" formatted="false">The original CL-600 Challenger was powered by a pair of Lycoming ALF 502L turbofan engines, which was developed
        specifically for the Challenger. Subsequent models would adopt other powerplants, including the General Electric CF34 engine. The engines are mounted on the rear
        fuselage close to the aircraft\'s tail, providing smooth airflow to the engines even when flown at high angles of attack, although this was in a lower position
        than the original Learstar concept had placed them to mitigate against unfavourable pitch control characteristics. The engines are fitted with thrust reversers
        to decrease landing distances. An auxiliary power unit is also present for starting the engines and providing air conditioning within the cabin while on the
        ground. The fuselage comprises three sections – the nose, centre, and tail – which are manufactured separately in their own jigs and joined late on in the
        production process. It has been designed to be pressurised at a maximum differential of 9.3 lb per square inch. Various cutouts are present across the fuselage
        to accommodate various features, such as a large main door on the port side of the aircraft forward of the wing, multiple regulation-compliant emergency exits, a
        baggage hatch on the port side aft of the wing, and numerous windows. The fuselage\'s diameter was designed to accommodate an unobstructed cabin floor, a cabin
        height of 6 ft 1 inch in the centre section, as well as space for the wing box, underfloor integral fuel tanks, air ducts, and various control cabling. It was also
        designed to easily accommodate Canadair\'s early plans to stretch the fuselage, for which equal-length plugs are installed fore and after of the centre section to
        vastly increase the Challenger\'s capacity.\n\nVarious avionics are present upon the Challenger. As standard, the CL-600 is furnished with a dual-channel Sperry
        SPZ-600 automatic flight control system, incorporating a flight director and air data computers; more typical to larger commercial aircraft, this system is
        certifiable for conducting category 3A automatic landings. The flight control system features significant redundancy, including three individual hydraulic
        systems; even with complete failure and the loss of one actuator, a viable level of assisted control over the key flight surfaces remains present. Weather
        radar and Marconi-built solid-state instrument displays are supplied as standard, as well as a Collins-built radio set; optional long range radio-based
        equipment, such as a HF radio set and VHF navigational aids can be installed. In a standard executive aircraft configuration, the cabin is divided between the
        forward galley, and two seating sections, which are typically fitted with a four-chair club section followed by either a conference grouping area or divans,
        along with a lavatory at the aft end. The chairs are fully reclining and can swivel, while the divans can serve as sleeping accommodation. Early examples feature
        luxuries such as telephones, lighting controls, and stereo systems; foldaway tables attached to the cabin walls were also installed, along with a pair of
        wardrobes, one fore and one aft, for storing hand luggage and other small items.\n</string>

    <string name="challenger650_desc3">\nThe Challenger 650 comes in only one variant, the CL-650.\n</string>

    <string name="challenger650_specs_constraint">()\n</string>


    <string name="challenger650_identify">How to identify Challenger 650?</string>
    <string name="challenger650_identify_ans"></string>

    <string name="challenger650_cockpit_value">2</string>
    <string name="challenger650_wingspan_value">19.6 m</string>
    <string name="challenger650_length_value">20.9 m</string>
    <string name="challenger650_height_value">6.3 m</string>
    <string name="challenger650_fuselage_value">2.41 m (W) / 1.83 m (H)</string>
    <string name="challenger650_mtow_value">21.86 t</string>
    <string name="challenger650_cruise_speed_value">854 km/h (typical)</string>
    <string name="challenger650_range_value">4,000 nmi</string>
    <string name="challenger650_thrust_value">41 kN</string>
    <!--CHALLENGER 650-->


    <!--GLOBAL 7500-->
    <string name="global7500_type_value">Business jet</string>
    <string name="global7500_engine_value">General Electric Passport (2)</string>
    <string name="global7500_first_flight_value">4 November 2016</string>
    <string name="global7500_intro_value">20 December 2018</string>
    <string name="global7500_numbers_value">50 as of March 2021</string>
    <string name="global7500_variants_value">1</string>

    <string name="global7500_desc1" formatted="false">The Bombardier Global 7500 are ultra long-range business jets developed by Bombardier Aviation (formerly
        Bombardier Aerospace). Announced in October 2010, the program was delayed by two years by a wing redesign. The 7500, originally named the 7000, made its first
        flight on November 4, 2016, was type certified by Transport Canada on September 28, 2018, and entered service on 20 December 2018. The Global 8000 schedule has
        not yet been determined. Based on the Global 6000 with a new transonic wing, the longer, four-zone cabin 7500 has a range of 7,700 nmi, while the shorter
        three-zone 8000 was to reach 7,900 nmi.\n\nThe first test aircraft underwent taxi testing in October 2016. Dedicated to testing basic system functionality and
        assessing the handling and flying qualities of the aircraft, its maiden flight was performed on November 4, 2016, climbing to 6,096 m and reaching 240 knots
        during the 2 h 27 min flight. The production wing was in final design in February 2017. FTV2 flew on March 6, 2017, \"The Powerhouse\" is designed to test
        aircraft systems, including propulsion, electrical and mechanical systems. FTV1 is used to open the performance envelope and reached Mach 0.995 on March
        29, 2017. FTV3 flew on May 10, 2017, \"The Navigator\" will be used to test the avionics and electrical system performance. By the end of May 2017, the three
        prototypes flew a combined 250 hours. The fourth prototype, used for cabin interior validation, is called \"The Architect\" and the fifth and final, for the
        entry-into-service, is called \"The Masterpiece\". The fifth has a slightly lighter production wing supplied by the Triumph Group, after a dispute over the
        wing weight was resolved.\n\nBy mid-July 2017, the three flight-test aircraft had accumulated 500 hours. On 15 August 2017, after \"high vibration and high
        inter-turbine temperature readings\", the second prototype\'s right GE Passport had an in-flight flameout at FL410 and the aircraft went back to Wichita
        Airport 156 nmi away for a single engine landing. By October 2017, the four flight-test aircraft had flown 900 hours. In April 2018, the flight test campaign
        surpassed 1,800 hours and confirmed a range increase from 7,400 to 7,700 nmi, greater than the competing Gulfstream G650ER\'s 7,500 nmi, but still overshadowed
        by the smaller Global 8000\'s range of 7,900 nmi, 200 nmi more than the Global 7500. As the original Global Express is developed into the Global 5500 and
        6500, it is renamed Global 7500 to reflect this range increase. By the end of May 2018, the five flight-test aircraft had amassed about 2,000 hours towards
        the type\'s planned entry-into-service at year-end. By June 2018, 2,300 flight test hours had been completed by the test fleet towards certification. The
        first production aircraft entered the completion centre in May 2018.\n</string>

    <string name="global7500_desc2" formatted="false">The 7500 is a stretched derivative of the Global 6000 with a new transonic wing. It is powered by the new General
        Electric Passport 73 kN thrust engine with reduced NOx emissions and 8% better fuel efficiency than the Global Express XRS, allowing a Mach 0.90 high-speed
        cruise. As part of its effort to make the long-range aircraft comfortable for the passengers, Bombardier developed a new ergonomic passenger seat, called the
        Nuage. The seat design took seven years to complete. Airbus-owned Stelia supplies the main fuselage. The new, larger and lower-drag wing is optimized for Mach
        0.85 with a 35.3° quarter chord wing sweep, a thinner thickness-to-chord ratio, leaner flap track fairings, improved lift-to-drag performance, more efficient
        winglets and up to 30% better low-speed lift due to double-slotted, inboard Fowler flaps. The new fly-by-wire flight controls with active load alleviation and
        the flexible, relatively highly loaded wing damps turbulence. The metal airframe uses aluminium–lithium alloys to save weight. It shares the same fuselage
        diameter with older Global models, but has thinner frames, which increase the cabin width and height by 25 mm. Additionally the 19 dm<sup><small><small>2</small></small></sup>
        cabin windows are 80% larger, the nose cowl is recontoured, and the aft fuselage and empennage are both new designs. The basic inspection intervals are 850
        hours or 36 months, with C checks are every 12 years or 8,500 cycles and a limit of 17,000 cycles before life extension through intensive maintenance is
        required.\n\nOfficially designated as the BD-700-2A12, the design is marketed as the Global 7500. It is stretched by 3.43 m from the original Global. It is
        planned to have a four-zone 74.67 m<sup><small><small>3</small></small></sup> cabin, 20% more than the previous. It was originally designed to cover a 7,300 nmi
        range at Mach 0.85 with 10 passengers. Its cabin is one-third longer than competing models, providing a fourth seating section up from three, can sleep
        eight passengers and offers an optional shower and a sleeping crew rest area. Bombardier marketing focused on ultra-high-net-worth individuals and the Global
        7500 is the largest, longest range, roomiest and most luxurious purpose-built business aircraft yet built. Despite the wing area being smaller than the
        Gulfstream G650ER and a 11% higher MTOW, it has lower V speeds and better runway performance due to the high-lift system with leading-edge slats and
        double-slotted flaps for a similar power loading. Hourly fuel flow per engine is 230 kg at idle, 2,830 kg at takeoff, 580 to 620 kg in cruise at Mach
        0.85/484 kn (896 km/h) TAS, 780 kg at Mach 0.9/515 kn (954 km/h) TAS and 1,100 kg at Mach 0.925/523 kn (969 km/h) TAS, around 34,000 kg and ISA conditions. An
        even longer range variant could reach 1,000 nmi (1,900 km) more with another 3,600 kg of fuel.\n</string>

    <string name="global7500_desc3">\n</string>

    <string name="global7500_specs_constraint">()\n</string>


    <string name="global7500_identify">How to identify Global 7500?</string>
    <string name="global7500_identify_ans"></string>

    <string name="global7500_cockpit_value">2</string>
    <string name="global7500_wingspan_value">31.7 m</string>
    <string name="global7500_length_value">33.88 m</string>
    <string name="global7500_height_value">8.2 m</string>
    <string name="global7500_fuselage_value">2.44 m (W) / 1.88 m (H)</string>
    <string name="global7500_mtow_value">52.1 t</string>
    <string name="global7500_cruise_speed_value">902 km/h (typical),\n955 km/h (max.)</string>
    <string name="global7500_range_value">7,700 nmi</string>
    <string name="global7500_thrust_value">84.2 kN</string>
    <!--GLOBAL 7500-->


    <!--CRJ 100/200-->
    <string name="crj_100_200_type_value">Regional/Business jet</string>
    <string name="crj_100_200_engine_value">General Electric\nCF34-3A1/3B1 (2)</string>
    <string name="crj_100_200_first_flight_value">10 May 1991</string>
    <string name="crj_100_200_intro_value">19 October 1992\nwith Lufthansa CityLine</string>
    <string name="crj_100_200_customer_value">SkyWest Airlines</string>
    <string name="crj_100_200_variants_value">9</string>

    <string name="crj_100_200_desc1" formatted="false">The Bombardier CRJ100 and CRJ200 (previously Canadair CRJ100 and CRJ200) is a regional jet designed and
        manufactured by Bombardier Aerospace between 1991 and 2006, the first of the Bombardier CRJ family. An initial effort to enlarge the Bombardier Challenger
        600 business jet to 36 seats, the Challenger 610E, ended in 1981. A stretched derivative was studied again after Canadair\'s sale to Bombardier in 1986. The
        Canadair Regional Jet program was launched in early 1989. The first CRJ100 prototype made its maiden flight on 10 May 1991. Canada\'s first jet airliner to enter
        commercial service was introduced by launch customer Lufthansa in 1992. The 50 seat aircraft is powered by two GE CF34 turbofans, mounted on the rear
        fuselage. The CRJ200 has more efficient turbofan engines for lower fuel consumption, increased cruise altitude and speed. During the late 1990s, it was stretched
        into the CRJ700 series. During its production phase from 1991 to 2006, a total of 1021 CRJ100/200s were built.\n\nThe CRJ family has its origins in the design
        of the earlier Canadair Challenger business jet. During the late 1970s, the relatively wide fuselage of the Challenger, which could seat a pair of passengers
        on each side of a central aisle, was observed by some Canadair officials to suggest that it would be somewhat straightforward to produce a stretch of the
        aircraft for the purpose of accommodating more seats. Accordingly, in 1980, the company publicised its proposal for an expanded model of the aircraft, designated
        as the Challenger 610E, which would have had seating for an additional 24 passengers. However, such a lengthening did not occur as a result of work on the
        program being terminated during the following year. Despite the cancellation of the 610E, neither the concept or general interest in the development of an
        enlarged derivative had disappeared. During 1987, the year following Canadair\'s sale to Bombardier, design studies commenced into options for producing a
        substantially more ambitious stretched configuration of the Challenger. In July 1988, Canadair targeted a $13-14 million unit price, for a demand of over 1,000
        by 1999. The 48-seat jet would be stretched over the Challenger by a 3.3 m forward plug and a 2.8 m aft plug. Over 300 mi (480 km) routes, the
        faster climb and cruise gave it a one third time advantage to 50 min compared to similarly sized turboprops. The higher cost per seat of the RJ, of $270,000 each
        compared to $186,600, would be balanced by its higher productivity.\n</string>

    <string name="crj_100_200_desc2" formatted="false">On 10 May 1991, the first of three development aircraft for the initial CRJ100 variant performed its first flight
        from Montréal–Pierre Elliott Trudeau International Airport, starting a 1,000h flight test program with three prototypes. During the following year, the type was
        awarded airworthiness certification; on 29 October 1992, initial deliveries to customers occurred later on that year. On 26 July 1993, the first prototype
        (C-FCRJ) was lost in a spin mishap near the Bombardier test center in Wichita, Kansas. The initial model was followed by the CRJ100 ER subvariant, featuring 20
        per cent greater range, and the CRJ100 LR subvariant, which possessed 40 per cent more range than the standard CRJ100. This sub-variant was developed with
        the purpose of more closely conforming with the requirements of both corporate and executive operators. A cargo door retrofit has been developed for the
        installation of former passenger-configured aircraft to extend the useful life of early-built CRJ100s. The CRJ200 is almost identical to the earlier CRJ100 model,
        except for the adoption of more efficient engines; these new engines have been attributed as having provided the CRJ200 with several improvements in
        performance, such as lower fuel consumption, as well as an increase in cruise altitude and cruise speed. Bombardier had specifically designed the new model to
        provide better performance and efficiencies than any of its nearest competitors at that time. There is also a CRJ200 freighter version, designated as the
        CRJ200 PF (Package Freighter), which was developed in cooperation with Cascade Aerospace on the request of Scandinavian operator West Air Sweden.\n\nThe Bombardier
        CRJ100 and CRJ200 are a family of jet-propelled regional airliners, based upon the design of the Challenger CL-600 business jet. Roughly, the CL-600 was stretched
        5.92 metres, which was achieved using fuselage plugs fore and aft of the wing, and was matched with the adoption of a reinforced and modified wing, an expanded
        fuel capacity, improved landing gear to handle the higher weights, and an additional pair of emergency exit doors. When installed in a typical seating
        configuration, the CRJ100 would accommodate 50 passengers; while in a maximum configuration, 52 passengers could be accommodated. It was powered by a pair of
        General Electric CF34-3A1 turbofan engines, each of which was capable of generating up to 41.0 kN of thrust. The CRJ100 featured a Collins-built ProLine 4
        avionics suite, including a weather radar.\n\nGerman airline Lufthansa CityLine, a subsidiary of the nations flag carrier operator Lufthansa, served as the
        launch customer for the CRJ100. Throughout the type\'s production life, it continued to be a major customer of the CRJ series. During 2001, following
        Lufthansa\'s acquisition of 25 per cent of regional airliner Eurowings, the airline ordered 15 CRJ200s with options for 30 more as part of a strategic move
        towards fleet commonality with Lufthansa Skyline. During the airliner\'s first 100 days of operational service, the CRJ100 performed a total of 1,237 flights,
        during which it reportedly achieved a 99% dispatch reliability while its fuel economy was reportedly 8% superior to the originally projected figure. According
        to aviation author Dean Roberts, the CRJ100 had benefitted greatly from an industry-wide shift towards hub-and-spoke networks in the United States, which had
        resulted from the Airline Deregulation Act of 1978. Considerable demand across the North American market was experienced by both the CRJ100 and the CRJ200. The
        smaller size of the regional jets meant than, unlike traditional narrowbody jets, they could be used at the majority of secondary airports and avoid traditional
        hubs.\n</string>

    <string name="crj_100_200_desc3">\nCRJ100/200 variants include CRJ100, CRJ100SF, CRJ100LR, CRJ100SE, CRJ200, CRJ200PF, CRJ200LR, CRJ200SF, Challenger 800/850.\n</string>

    <string name="crj_100_200_specs_constraint">(CRJ100 and CRJ200 compared in order)\n</string>


    <string name="crj_100_200_identify">How to identify CRJ 100/200?</string>
    <string name="crj_100_200_identify_ans"></string>

    <string name="crj_100_200_cockpit_value">2</string>
    <string name="crj_100_200_wingspan_value">21.21 m </string>
    <string name="crj_100_200_length_value">26.77 m</string>
    <string name="crj_100_200_height_value">6.22 m</string>
    <string name="crj_100_200_fuselage_value">2.69 m (W) / ~2.69 m (H)</string>
    <string name="crj_100_200_mtow_value">24.04 t (LR)</string>
    <string name="crj_100_200_cruise_speed_value">785 km/h (typical),\n860 km/h (max.)</string>
    <string name="crj_100_200_range_value">1,650 (100LR) /\n1,700 nmi (200LR)</string>
    <string name="crj_100_200_thrust_value">38.84 kN</string>
    <!--CRJ 100/200 -->


    <!--ERJ FAMILY-->
    <string name="erj_family_type_value">Regional jet</string>
    <string name="erj_family_engine_value">Rolls-Royce AE 3007-A1/3 /\nAE 3007-A1E (2)</string>
    <string name="erj_family_first_flight_value">11 August 1995</string>
    <string name="erj_family_intro_value">6 April 1997</string>
    <string name="erj_family_customer_value">Envoy Air</string>
    <string name="erj_family_variants_value">22</string>

    <string name="erj_family_desc1" formatted="false">The Embraer ERJ family (for Embraer Regional Jet, model names EMB-135, EMB-140 and EMB-145) are regional jets
        produced by Brazilian aerospace company Embraer. The 45–48 seat EMB145 was launched in 1989 as a turbofan-powered stretch of the EMB 120 Brasilia turboprop.
        It first flew on August 11, 1995 and it received its type certificate on December 10, 1996. The ERJ145 was introduced on April 6, 1997 and the shortened
        ERJ135 and ERJ140 were introduced in 1999. Keeping the three-abreast seating of the Brasilia, the twinjet has a new swept wing and is powered by two
        rear-fuselage-mounted AE3007 turbofans for a range up to 2,000 nmi (3,700 km). The series includes the ERJ135 (37 passengers), ERJ140 (44 passengers), and
        ERJ145 (50 passengers), as well as the Legacy 600 business jet and the R-99 family of military aircraft. The family\'s primary competition comes from the
        Bombardier CRJ regional jets. Production ended in 2020 after 1,231 were built.\n\nThe ERJ145 was designed for a perceived new market for regional jet aircraft,
        where the increased speed, comfort and passenger appeal would outweigh the inherent fuel economy of the turboprop aircraft which were in service and
        in development. The 45–48 seat EMB145 was launched at the Paris Air Show in 1989 as an 5.5 m stretch of the EMB 120 Brasilia developed for $150M plus $50M for
        training and marketing, one third the cost of the cancelled Short Brothers FJX project. Its $11M unit cost would have been $3M less than the Canadair CRJ. The
        400 kn (740 km/h) jet would be powered by GE/Garrett CFE738s, Lycoming ALF 502s or Rolls-Royce plc/Allison Engine AB580s turbofans, to be selected in the summer
        of 1989.\n\nIt was targeted for a late 1992 introduction with six produced then ramping to 60 per year in 1995. It aimed for half of a market for 1000 with
        break-even after twelve years with 400 sold. Keeping 75% of the Brasilia parts and systems, the EMB145 Amazon aimed for a 1991 first flight. The stretch resulted
        from two 3.4 m plugs of the 2.29 m diameter fuselage in the front and behind the redesigned 538 sq ft (50.0 m<sup><small><small>2</small></small></sup>) wing. Its supercritical airfoil with a 14% root
        thickness had its chord extended at the leading edge with a slight sweepback, increased aspect ratio and winglets. The overwing podded engines generated
        28 kN of thrust. Designed for 500–600 nmi stages, up to 1,400 nmi with a reduced payload, it had a 16,500 kg maximum takeoff weight (MTOW) and a 9,546 kg
        operating empty weight.\n</string>

    <string name="erj_family_desc2" formatted="false">In March 1991, a revised configuration started wind tunnel testing: the quarter chord wing sweep increased to 22.3° with underslung
        engines for lower aerodynamic drag. This reduced the span by almost 2 to 20.5 m, reducing its aspect ratio from 9.3 to 8.4 and wing area from 50 to
        47 m<sup><small><small>2</small></small></sup>. The semi-monocoque wing has two main and one auxiliary spar and holds 4,500 kg of fuel, it has double-slotted
        fowler flaps and spoilers. To accommodate the underwing engines, the landing gear is longer, allowing using jetways, and the fuselage was lengthened from 25.8 to
        26 m. In June 1991, the Brazilian Government loaned $600 million to Embraer and in July the programme was re-evaluated while tooling was 80% complete. By
        November 1991, Embraer was still looking for partners to share the risk of the $350 million project, hoping to obtain Government approval by the end of the
        year. Sold at $12 million with an all-digital cockpit and 31.8 kN engines, it had letters of intent for 337 units. First flight slipped to 1992 and
        certification for late 1993.\n\nEmbraer has introduced two shortened versions of the ERJ145. All three aircraft share the same crew type rating,
        allowing pilots to fly any of the three aircraft without the need for further training. The ERJ140 is 1.42 metres shorter, seating 44 passengers, and has 96%
        parts commonality with the ERJ145. The only significant changes are a shorter fuselage, a slightly derated engine and an increased range. The ERJ140 was designed
        with fewer seats in order to meet the needs of some major United States airlines, which have an agreement with the pilots\' union to limit the number of 50-seat
        aircraft that can be flown by their affiliates. At launch, Embraer estimated the cost of an ERJ140 to be approximately US $15.2 million. The estimated cost of
        development of the ERJ140 was US $45 million. The ERJ135 is 3.54 metres shorter, seating 37 passengers, and has 95% parts commonality with the ERJ145. The
        first ERJ135 entered service in 1999.\n\nThe airframe is mainly stretched, machined and chemically milled aluminium, with CFRP for moving parts, GFRP for
        fairings and sidewalls, kevlar for leading edges and Nomex honeycomb-CFRP/GFRP sandwiches for floors. The EMB145 family of aircraft generally comes equipped
        with two Rolls-Royce AE 3007 series turbofan engines. The engines have a bypass ratio of 5:1. The engines are controlled by two FADECs (Full Authority Digital
        Engine Controls). The FADECs control virtually all aspects of the engine and send engine data to be displayed on the EICAS for the pilot. The Embraer ERJ145
        family of aircraft typically comes equipped with the Honeywell Primus 1000 avionics suite. The suite normally consists of five CRT display units (DUs) or screens.
        From left to right, the system consists of a Primary Flight Display (PFD), Multi-Function Display (MFD), Engine Indication and Crew Alerting System (EICAS),
        Multi-Function Display (MFD) (Co-pilot) and Primary Flight Display (PFD) (Co-pilot). The DUs are normally CRTs but can be upgraded to lighter LCD displays. These
        upgraded DUs also have added functionality.\n</string>

    <string name="erj_family_desc3">\nERJ Family variants include ERJ135ER, ERJ135LR, ERJ135KL, ERJ140ER, ERJ140LR, ERJ145STD, ERJ145EU, ERJ145ER, ERJ145EP, ERJ145LR, ERJ145LU, ERJ145MK,
        ERJ145XR, Legacy 600 (EMB135BJ), Legacy 650 (EMB145BJ), Harbin Embraer ERJ145, C-99A, EMB 145SA (R-99A), EMB 145RS (R-99B), EMB 145MP/ASW (P-99), EMB 145H (Hellenic Air Force),
        EMB 145I (Indian Air Force).\n</string>

    <string name="erj_family_specs_constraint">(ERJ135LR, ERJ140LR, ERJ145XR compared in order)\n</string>


    <string name="erj_family_identify">How to identify ERJ Family aircraft?</string>
    <string name="erj_family_identify_ans"></string>

    <string name="erj_family_cockpit_value">2</string>
    <string name="erj_family_wingspan_value">20.04 m</string>
    <string name="erj_family_length_value">26.33 / 28.45 / 29.87 m</string>
    <string name="erj_family_height_value">6.76 m</string>
    <string name="erj_family_fuselage_value">~2.29 m (W) / ~2.32 m (H)</string>
    <string name="erj_family_mtow_value">20 / 21.1 / 24.1 t</string>
    <string name="erj_family_cruise_speed_value">833 km/h (max.),\n854 km/h (max.) (145XR)</string>
    <string name="erj_family_range_value">1,750 / 1,650 / 2,000 nmi</string>
    <string name="erj_family_thrust_value">33.71 kN / 39.67 kN (145XR)</string>
    <!--ERJ FAMILY-->


    <!--EMBRAER E-JET E2-->
    <string name="ejet_e2_type_value">Narrow-body\nairliner</string>
    <string name="ejet_e2_engine_value">Pratt &amp; Whitney PW1715G /\n PW1919G/21G/22G/23G (2)</string>
    <string name="ejet_e2_first_flight_value">23 May 2016</string>
    <string name="ejet_e2_intro_value">24 April 2018\nwith Widerøe</string>
    <string name="ejet_e2_customer_value">Azul Brazilian Airlines</string>
    <string name="ejet_e2_variants_value">3</string>

    <string name="ejet_e2_desc1" formatted="false">The Embraer E-Jet E2 family, comprised of E175-E2, E190-E2, E195-E2, are medium-range jet airliners developed by Embraer, succeeding the original E-Jet. The
        program was launched at the Paris Air Show in 2013. The first variant, the E190-E2, took its first flight on 23 May 2016 and was certified on 28 February 2018
        before entering service with Widerøe on 24 April. The three twinjet variants share the same four-abreast narrow-body fuselage with different lengths and
        three different new wings, Pratt &amp; Whitney PW1000G turbofans in two sizes, fly-by-wire controls with new avionics, and an updated cabin. As of 6 November 2020, 1 E175-E2, 19 E190-E2s and 10 E195-E2s
        have been built.\n\nIn 2010, it appeared possible that Embraer could directly challenge the Bombardier CSeries (now A220) with a clean-sheet five-abreast design for 100 to 150 passengers. However,
        Airbus launched the A320neo in December 2010, including the 124-seat A319neo, and Boeing launched the re-engined 737 MAX the following year. Accordingly,
        Embraer continued to focus on large regional jets, and launched an extensive revamp of the E-Jet family at the November 2011 Dubai Air Show. The new variants
        would be better positioned to compete with the CSeries and would be powered by new engines with larger diameter fans that would offer improvements in specific
        fuel consumption, as well as slightly taller landing gear and possibly a new aluminum or carbon fiber-based wing. Embraer named this new development \"the E-jets
        second generation\". The $1.7 billion program was launched at the Paris Air Show in 2013.\n\nThe first E-Jet E2, an E190-E2, was rolled out on 25 February
        2016 and made its maiden flight on 23 May in São José dos Campos. It flew for three hours and twenty minutes to Mach 0.82, climbed to 41,000 feet, retracted the
        landing gear and flaps, and engaged the fly-by-wire in normal mode. It flew earlier than the previously anticipated second half of 2016. The program had fewer
        challenges than expected and introduction was then planned in the first quarter of 2018. The airplane was slightly below expected weight and the other two E190-E2
        prototypes should fly within a year. The second prototype made its maiden flight on 8 July 2016. The flight lasted 2 hr 55 min without any incidents. The first
        E-Jet E2 flew from Brazil to Farnborough Airshow just 45 days after its maiden flight, demonstrating maturity and confidence in the design. In April 2017, as
        650 hr of flight tests have been completed and the program is on schedule, Embraer wants to guarantee a 99% schedule reliability in the first year of service. Half
        of the flight testing was done by June 2017, the aerodynamics were better than predicted and the E190-E2 hot and high performance was better than expected.
        The E195-E2\'s MTOW is increased to 61,500 kg and its range to 2,600 nmi (4,800 km). In June 2017, the four E190-E2s and the single E195-E2 - which is presented
        at the 2017 Paris Air Show - have made more than 900 flight-test hours, mostly by the E190-E2s.\n\nIn July 2017, the five aircraft have flown 1,000 flight-test
        hours while the E190-E2 has accomplished 55% of its test campaign. In January 2018, 98% of the test campaign was done with 2,000 flight hours. Fuel burn is
        17.3% lower than for the E190 up from 16% predicted, range increased by 750 nmi (1,390 km) from hot-and-high or short runways: 1,600 or 2,200 nmi (3,000 or
        4,100 km) from Mexico City or London City, and noise margin to Stage 4 is 3 EPNdB better than specification at 20 EPNdB. The E190-E2 received its type certificate
        from the ANAC, FAA and EASA on 28 February 2018. The first production engines for the larger variant were delivered in February 2019 and should deliver a 24%
        reduction in per-seat fuel burn compared with the E195. The E195-E2 obtained its type certification in April 2019.\n</string>

    <string name="ejet_e2_desc2" formatted="false">Embraer targets 16 to 24% lower fuel burn and 15–25% lower maintenance cost per seat. In the E190-E2, of the 17.3%
        better fuel burn, 11% comes from the geared turbofan, 4.8% from the improved aerodynamics of the new high aspect ratio wing and 1.5% from the fly-by-wire\'s
        15% smaller tail surfaces. Over a 600 nmi (1,100 km) trip and with a US$72 fuel barrel, Embraer estimates a 97-seat E190-E2 trip cost is 7% lower for a 1% higher
        seat cost than a 106-seat A220-100, a 120-seat E195-E2 has a 2% higher trip cost but a 10% lower seat cost and 10% lower trip cost and 3% lower seat cost than
        a 129-seat A220-300; and while a 97-seat E190 had an 18% higher seat cost than a 150-seat A320 and a 23% lower trip cost, an E190-E2 has a 30% lower trip cost for
        an 8% higher seat cost than a 150-seat A320neo, while an E195-E2 has the same seat cost but 20% lower trip cost. By October, Embraer raised its E190/E195-E2 seat
        or trip costs claim to roughly 10% better than the A220.\n\nBuilt on the first generation E-Jet, its wing is redesigned, and it introduces new pylons, landing
        gear, horizontal stabilizers, cabin, cabin air system, air cycle machine, bleed air system, and a new fly-by-wire system. The switch to a composite wing was not
        yet justified economically for a similar shape, the less draggy flaps are single-slotted instead of the more complex double-slotted on the E1, and the engine
        pylon is shorter. The raised, 11:1 aspect ratio gull-wing partially accommodate the 2.01m diameter GTF (Geared Turbofan), larger than the CF34 by 66 cm, while the trailing arm
        landing gear is taller for 23–25 cm higher door sills, giving a 5 cm lower nacelles than the E1. GE Aviation, Pratt &amp; Whitney, and Rolls-Royce were all
        possible engine suppliers. In January 2013, Embraer selected the Pratt &amp; Whitney PW1000G Geared Turbofan engine as the exclusive powerplant. Honeywell Primus
        Epic 2 was selected as the avionics package. In 2014, Alta Precision was selected to produce main landing gear components for the E190/E195 E2.\n\nMoog Inc was
        selected to supply the Primary Flight Control System. The E2 features a closed loop fly-by-wire control which reduces weight, increases fuel efficiency,
        enhances control and increases safety by full envelope protection in all flight phases compared to the first E-Jet. The fuel savings of the now closed loop
        fly-by-wire control come from the enhanced flight stability and the resulting increased lift (lower tail downward force) and weight savings and drag reductions
        related to the 26% reduction in the horizontal tail (tailplane) size. The wing structure was lightened by 200 kg thanks to FBW ailerons, also used when
        braking, avoiding larger wheels and brakes. A 250 ft<sup><small><small>2</small></small></sup> horizontal stabilizer is sufficient from 280 ft<sup><small><small>2</small></small></sup> on the E190/195.\n</string>

    <string name="ejet_e2_desc3">\nE-Jet E2 family variants include E175-E2, E190-E2, E195-E2.\n</string>

    <string name="ejet_e2_specs_constraint">(E175-E2, E190-E2, E195-E2 compared in order)\n</string>


    <string name="ejet_e2_identify">How to identify Embraer E-Jet E2?</string>
    <string name="ejet_e2_identify_ans"></string>

    <string name="ejet_e2_cockpit_value">2</string>
    <string name="ejet_e2_wingspan_value">31.0 / 33.72 / 35.12 m</string>
    <string name="ejet_e2_length_value">32.4 / 36.24 / 41.5 m</string>
    <string name="ejet_e2_height_value">9.98 / 10.95 / 10.9 m</string>
    <string name="ejet_e2_fuselage_value">3.01 m (W) / ~3.1 m (H)</string>
    <string name="ejet_e2_mtow_value">44.8 / 56.4 /	61.5 t</string>
    <string name="ejet_e2_cruise_speed_value">833 km/h (typical),\n876 km/h (max.)</string>
    <string name="ejet_e2_range_value">2,017 / 2,850 / 2,655 nmi</string>
    <string name="ejet_e2_thrust_value">67 kN (E175) / 85–102 kN</string>
    <!--EMBRAER E-JET E2-->


    <!--LINEAGE 1000-->
    <string name="lineage_1000_type_value">Business jet</string>
    <string name="lineage_1000_engine_value">General Electric\nCF34-10E (2)</string>
    <string name="lineage_1000_first_flight_value">26 October 2007</string>
    <string name="lineage_1000_intro_value">7 May 2009 with HE Aamer\nAbdul Jalil Al Fahim</string>
    <string name="lineage_1000_customer_value">AirX Charter</string>
    <string name="lineage_1000_variants_value">2</string>

    <string name="lineage_1000_desc1" formatted="false">The Embraer Lineage 1000 is a variant of the Embraer 190 regional jet airliner, launched as a private jet on May
        2, 2006. Manufactured by the Brazilian aerospace firm Embraer, the Lineage is advertised as an \"ultra-large\" business jet with comfortable seating
        for 19. The Lineage 1000 received its certification from Brazil\'s ANAC and from EASA in December 2008. It was certified by the USA Federal Aviation
        Administration on 7 January 2009. The first Lineage 1000 was delivered to Aamer Abdul Jalil Al Fahim on May 7, 2009. As of 31 December 2018, only 28 Lineage
        1000s have been built.\n\nIn October 2013, Embraer introduced the Lineage 1000E, which delivers greater range - 4,600 nm (8,519 km). In addition, the new Lineage
        1000E features new in-flight entertainment and cockpit options. In August 2020 Embraer announced that it was stopping sales of the Lineage 1000.\n</string>

    <string name="lineage_1000_desc2" formatted="false">On 6 October 2020, the Pakistan Navy announced the selection of the Lineage 1000 to replace its P-3C Orion in
        the maritime patrol role, with 10 converted commercial jets, the first of which has been ordered. It was unclear whether the aircraft is being acquired directly
        from the manufacturer or another party. In-service aircraft may not be available due to low production numbers, while existing operators may be selling their
        aircraft due to COVID restrictions on air travel.\n\nThe Lineage 1000 is based on the Embraer 190 airliner, with added fuel tanks in the lower deck cargo hold
        space, nearly doubling the jet\'s range. It boasts a lavish interior, divided into up to 5 sections including an optional bedroom, washroom with running water,
        and a walk-in cargo area at the rear. Its fuselage cross-section is larger than similarly priced business jets like the $50.4M Global 5000, $53.8M Falcon 7X or
        $54.5M Gulfstream G600, but smaller than other airliner conversions : the Sukhoi Superjet 100, B737-based $71.4M Boeing Business Jet-1 or A320-based $87.0M Airbus
        Corporate Jets.\n</string>

    <string name="lineage_1000_desc3">\nThe Lineage 1000 comes in 2 variants - Lineage 1000 and Lineage 1000E.\n</string>

    <string name="lineage_1000_specs_constraint">()\n</string>


    <string name="lineage_1000_identify">How to identify Lineage 1000?</string>
    <string name="lineage_1000_identify_ans"></string>

    <string name="lineage_1000_cockpit_value">2</string>
    <string name="lineage_1000_wingspan_value">28.72 m</string>
    <string name="lineage_1000_length_value">36.24 m</string>
    <string name="lineage_1000_height_value">10.57 m</string>
    <string name="lineage_1000_fuselage_value">2.67 m (W) / ~2.2 m (H)</string>
    <string name="lineage_1000_mtow_value">54.5 t</string>
    <string name="lineage_1000_cruise_speed_value">850 km/h (typical),\n874 km/h (max.)</string>
    <string name="lineage_1000_range_value">4,600 nmi</string>
    <string name="lineage_1000_thrust_value">82 kN</string>
    <!--LINEAGE 1000-->


    <!--PHENOM 300-->
    <string name="phenom_300_type_value">Light business jet</string>
    <string name="phenom_300_engine_value">Pratt &amp; Whitney Canada\nPW535E1 (2)</string>
    <string name="phenom_300_first_flight_value">2008</string>
    <string name="phenom_300_intro_value">2009</string>
    <string name="phenom_300_numbers_value">600 (May 2021)</string>
    <string name="phenom_300_variants_value">4</string>

    <string name="phenom_300_desc1" formatted="false">The Embraer EMB-505 Phenom 300 is a single pilot certified light business jet developed by the Brazilian aerospace
        manufacturer Embraer. It can carry up to 11 occupants. Embraer began designing the Phenom 300 after finding that potential customers of the Phenom 100 would also
        like a bigger aircraft. It was a new design with the aim of allowing operation to smaller airports such as London City and Telluride Regional Airport. It first
        flew on 29 April 2008, and received its type certification on 3 December 2009. On 29 December 2009 Embraer delivered the first Phenom 300 to Executive Flight
        Services at the company\'s headquarters at São José dos Campos, Brazil. On 31 January 2020, Embraer announced significant upgrades to the Phenom 300, with
        maximum speed increased from Mach 0.78 to 0.80 (446 to 464 kn, 826 to 859 km/h), and range increased from 1,992 to 2,010 nmi (3,689 to 3,723 km). Rated engine
        thrust was increased from 3,360 to 3,478 lbf (14.95 to 15.47 kN) on upgraded PW535E1 turbofans. In 2021, its equipped price was $9.65M.\n</string>

    <string name="phenom_300_desc2" formatted="false">The Phenom 300 is a twin-engined cantilever monoplane with low-positioned, swept wings. It has a horizontal
        stabiliser in a T-tail configuration and a retractable tricycle landing gear. It has two rear-pylon-mounted Pratt &amp; Whitney Canada PW535E turbofan engines. The
        flight deck is based on Garmin G1000 (G3000 on the later variants). The enclosed cabin has room for nine passengers and a two-pilot crew; during single-pilot operation an additional passenger can be carried. Access to the cockpit and
        cabin is via an airstair on the left-hand side. Its structural life is 28,000 flight cycles or 35,000 hours. It is built of 18% composite materials; it has
        winglets, but not thrust reversers. The Phenom 300 has single-point refueling and an externally serviced private rear lavatory.\n\nThe Phenom 300 became the most
        delivered business jet with 60 units in 2013. This was also the case in 2014 and 2015. All Phenom assembly was moved to the Melbourne, Florida line after July
        2016, with a capability of assembling 96 Phenoms and 72 Embraer Legacy 450/Embraer Legacy 500 annually. More than 170 Phenom jets had been produced at the site
        by June 2016, mainly for the US market. In March 2019, Embraer delivered the 500th Phenom 300, claiming more than half of the light jet market share since
        2012. It was being used in over 30 countries and had carried 2.5 million passengers in 600,000 flights and 800,000 hours. The 600th unit was delivered in
        May 2021.\n</string>

    <string name="phenom_300_desc3">\nThe light business jet comes in 4 variants - Phenom 300, Phenom 300E, 2020 Phenom 300E, 2020 Phenom 300MED.\n</string>

    <string name="phenom_300_specs_constraint">(2020 Phenom 300E)\n</string>


    <string name="phenom_300_identify">How to identify Phenom 300?</string>
    <string name="phenom_300_identify_ans"></string>

    <string name="phenom_300_cockpit_value">1 / 2</string>
    <string name="phenom_300_wingspan_value">16.20 m</string>
    <string name="phenom_300_length_value">15.90 m</string>
    <string name="phenom_300_height_value">5 m</string>
    <string name="phenom_300_fuselage_value">1.55 m (W) / 1.49 m (H)</string>
    <string name="phenom_300_mtow_value">8.15 t</string>
    <string name="phenom_300_cruise_speed_value">834 km/h (max.)</string>
    <string name="phenom_300_range_value">2,010 nmi with IFR reserves,\n5 occupants</string>
    <string name="phenom_300_thrust_value">15.47 kN</string>
    <!--PHENOM 300-->


    <!--CITATION LONGITUDE-->
    <string name="citation_longitude_type_value">Corporate Jet</string>
    <string name="citation_longitude_engine_value">Honeywell HTF7700L (2)</string>
    <string name="citation_longitude_first_flight_value">8 October 2016</string>
    <string name="citation_longitude_intro_value">October 2019</string>
    <string name="citation_longitude_numbers_value">33 (Feb 2021)</string>
    <string name="citation_longitude_variants_value">1</string>

    <string name="citation_longitude_desc1" formatted="false">The Cessna Citation Longitude is a business jet produced by Cessna, part of the Cessna Citation family.
        Announced at the May 2012 EBACE, the Model 700 made its first flight on October 8, 2016, with certification obtained in September 2019. The aluminum airframe has
        the fuselage cross-section of the Citation Latitude, stretched by a seat row. Powered by Honeywell HTF7000 turbofans, it has a new ~28° swept wing and a T-tail for
        a 3,500 nmi (6,500 km) range.\n\nAnnounced at the May 2012 EBACE and scheduled for introduction in 2017. The first flight-test aircraft completed its first flight
        on October 8, 2016. The second flew in November, and in March 2017 the third, used to develop avionics and systems and to collect flight simulator data before
        two others will join the test program. The two aircraft completed 125 flights for more than 250 hours as production of the aircraft commenced at Textron Aviation\'s
        Wichita, Kansas facility. Less than eight months after the first flight and after more than 200 missions for nearly 400 hours, on track for certification later
        in 2017, the fourth prototype joined the flight-test program on May 6, fully outfitted for interior, environmental control system, pressurization and cabin
        technologies evaluation. The first production unit was rolled out on June 13, 2017 as the four test aircraft have flown 550 hours and a fifth aircraft will join
        in summer 2017.\n\nIn October 2017, test aircraft have completed more than 1,200 flight hours over 600 flights, for a certification expected by the end of 2017 or
        in early 2018. In February 2018, as the five aircraft accumulated over 1,000 flights and 2,000 hours, US approval and customer deliveries of the US$27 million
        jet were expected before the end of the second quarter before European validation six months later. After 3,000 hours on five aircraft, flight testing will
        conclude by early June 2018, and 200,000 pages of documentation will be completed after a month. As testing has doubled for certification, expanding related
        documentation, it is expected in the third quarter of 2018 with deliveries from late in this quarter or early in the fourth, less than a year after originally
        planned. It received a partial exemption for fuel tank flammability requirements applicable through January 2020 to keep its third-quarter approval goal, but
        a compliance plan had to be submitted by October 1, 2018.\n\nOn October 15, 2018, fractional operator NetJets announced the purchase of up to 175 Longitudes,
        sold for $26 million each, along 150 Citation Hemispheres, priced at $35 million. After 4,050 hours in 1,650 test flights, the Longitude received a provisional FAA
        type certification on December 20, allowing deliveries in early 2019. The fuel tank flammability requirements were addressed on December 5, with airplanes to be
        delivered having the definitive installation but limiting it for high elevation airport or RVSM operations, and restricting maintenance. The provisional type
        certification allowed to begin customer training flights and Textron expects certification in February 2019, while deliveries to NetJets should begin in the third
        quarter. On September 23, 2019, Textron Aviation announced its FAA Type Certification, after 6,000 flight hours, 11,000 test points and a 31,000 nmi (57,000 km)
        world tour. The first was shipped in early October. On December 31, 2019, NetJets took delivery of its first Longitude from its order for 150, expecting to
        enter service early in the first quarter of 2020. Textron Aviation announced EASA certification of the Citation Longitude on July 13, 2021. In 2021, its equipped
        price was $29.8M.\n</string>

    <string name="citation_longitude_desc2" formatted="false">The project is perceived as the follow-on development to the now-canceled Cessna Citation Columbus. Its
        fuselage cross-section is the same as the Cessna Citation Latitude. The aircraft has a T-tail empennage and area rule fuselage contouring. The aluminum wings
        incorporate moderate winglets. Construction is aluminum for both wing and fuselage. The cabin is 7 inches shorter and 6 inches narrower than the Columbus
        design. Initially, the Snecma Silvercrest engine was selected to power the aircraft, however the production model is powered by Honeywell HTF7000 turbofans. The
        Silvercrest was planned for the larger Citation Hemisphere, but Textron suspended its development in July 2019 as the turbofan did not meet objectives.\n\nIts
        wings and empennage are similar to the Hawker 4000 with winglets leading to a 5.3 ft. larger wingspan. The moderately super-critical wing have a quarter-chord
        sweep of 26.8° for its inner section and 28.6° for the outer section. The six-passenger Latitude fuselage has been reinforced and stretched by another row of
        seats to accommodate eight people in double club. After a takeoff at 14,130–3,790 kg below the 17,900 kg MTOW, the climb rate is 2,550 13.0 m/s at FL200. At its
        Mach 0.83, 473 kn (876 km/h) TAS max cruise, fuel flow per side is 390–400 kg per hour at FL430 and ISA -4.A M0.79 long range cruise would burn 830
        kg per hour at a 451 kn (835 km/h) true airspeed for a 17,237 kg aircraft, and 963 kg per hour at its M0.84 MMO - 477 kn (883 km/h) TAS. For the
        Avionics, Garmin G5000 was chosen for the Citation Longitude.\n</string>

    <string name="citation_longitude_desc3">\n</string>

    <string name="citation_longitude_specs_constraint">()\n</string>


    <string name="citation_longitude_identify">How to identify Citation Longitude?</string>
    <string name="citation_longitude_identify_ans"></string>

    <string name="citation_longitude_cockpit_value">2</string>
    <string name="citation_longitude_wingspan_value">21.01 m</string>
    <string name="citation_longitude_length_value">22.30 m</string>
    <string name="citation_longitude_height_value">5.92 m</string>
    <string name="citation_longitude_fuselage_value">1.96 m (W) / ~1.83 m (H)</string>
    <string name="citation_longitude_mtow_value">17.91 t</string>
    <string name="citation_longitude_cruise_speed_value">895 km/h (max.)</string>
    <string name="citation_longitude_range_value">3,500 nmi</string>
    <string name="citation_longitude_thrust_value">34.10 kN</string>
    <!--CITATION LONGITUDE-->


    <!--CITATION LATITUDE-->
    <string name="citation_latitude_type_value">Corporate Jet</string>
    <string name="citation_latitude_engine_value">Pratt &amp; Whitney Canada\nPW306D1 (2)</string>
    <string name="citation_latitude_first_flight_value">18 February 2014</string>
    <string name="citation_latitude_numbers_value">200 (April 2019)</string>
    <string name="citation_latitude_variants_value">1</string>

    <string name="citation_latitude_desc1" formatted="false">The Model 680A was announced at the 2011 NBAA convention, the prototype first flew on 18 February 2014, it
        achieved FAA certification on June 5, 2015, and first deliveries began on August 27. It keeps the Model 680 Sovereign wing, twin P&amp;WC PW306D turbofans and
        cruciform tail for a 2,700 nmi (5,000 km) range. Its new stand-up circular fuselage has a flat floor and was kept in the later Cessna Citation Longitude.\n\nThe
        $14.9 million Citation Latitude was announced by Cessna at the annual NBAA convention in October 2011, between the $12.6 million Citation XLS+ and the $17.5
        million Citation Sovereign. The prototype first flew on 18 February 2014 in Wichita, Kansas. Cessna announced on June 5, 2015, that it had achieved FAA
        certification for the type. On August 27, 2015, Cessna announced the first deliveries had begun. In 2021, its equipped price was $19.1M.\n</string>

    <string name="citation_latitude_desc2" formatted="false">It keeps the Citation Sovereign wing, twin Pratt &amp; Whitney Canada PW306D turbofans and cruciform tail. For the
        Avionics, Garmin G5000 was chosen for the Citation Latitude. Its newly-designed all-metal stand-up circular fuselage has a flat floor and seats nine. Typical missions are 2.0–2.7 hours and with 400 kn (740 km/h) block speeds
        and most operators can fly 5–6 hours at Mach 0.72–0.76 for a 2,000–2,400 nmi range, with short takeoff requirements and good hot and high performance. A first
        hour fuel burn of 910–1,130 kg followed by 730–860 kg the second hour and fuel burn can reach 1,500 kg for a 2-hour trip with favorable conditions. It lists for
        $17.5–18 million typically equipped, the same as the Embraer Legacy 450 with a similar flat floor cabin for club four plus two chairs and over 200 miles more
        range, 25–30 kn (46–56 km/h) higher cruise and fly-by-wire controls. Embraer is firm on list price while Textron discounts the Latitude by up to 20% for
        $13.5–14 million to sell three times as many aircraft.\n\nDeliveries to customers began in the third quarter of 2015 and sixteen had been handed over by the end
        of the year. By May 2018, almost three years since introduction, 124 were delivered and logged 80,000 flight hours. In June 2018, of 129 delivered, 104 were
        in the US, three in Mexico, two each are based in China, France and Turkey, and there was one in Chile, Paraguay, the Philippines, Poland, Scotland and
        Switzerland. It is used by medium-size corporations, typically flying 200–300 hours per year, and large fleet operators, the largest being NetJets which booked
        25 firm orders and 125 options in 2012 and received 44 aircraft for its U.S. operations and 10 for Europe by June 2018, flying theirs over 1,000 hours per
        year. By mid-September, the 136 delivered have logged 115,000 flight hours, and Textron claims it outsells the competition by four to one.\n</string>

    <string name="citation_latitude_desc3">\n</string>

    <string name="citation_latitude_specs_constraint">()\n</string>


    <string name="citation_latitude_identify">How to identify Citation Latitude?</string>
    <string name="citation_latitude_identify_ans"></string>

    <string name="citation_latitude_cockpit_value">2</string>
    <string name="citation_latitude_wingspan_value">22.05 m</string>
    <string name="citation_latitude_length_value">18.97 m</string>
    <string name="citation_latitude_height_value">6.38 m</string>
    <string name="citation_latitude_fuselage_value">1.96 m (W) / 1.83 m (H)</string>
    <string name="citation_latitude_mtow_value">13.97 t</string>
    <string name="citation_latitude_cruise_speed_value">826 km/h (max.)</string>
    <string name="citation_latitude_range_value">2,700 nmi with 4\npassengers</string>
    <string name="citation_latitude_thrust_value">26.28 kN</string>
    <!--CITATION LATITUDE-->


    <!--CESSNA CARAVAN-->
    <string name="caravan_type_value">Utility aircraft</string>
    <string name="caravan_engine_value">Pratt &amp; Whitney\nCanada PT6A-114A (2)</string>
    <string name="caravan_first_flight_value">9 December 1982</string>
    <string name="caravan_intro_value">1984</string>
    <string name="caravan_customer_value">FedEx</string>
    <string name="caravan_variants_value">19</string>

    <string name="caravan_desc1" formatted="false">The project was commenced on November 20, 1981, and the prototype first flew on December 9, 1982. The production model
        was certified by the FAA in October 1984 and its Cargomaster freighter variant was developed for FedEx. The 1.2 m longer 208B Super Cargomaster first flew in
        1986 and was developed into the passenger 208B Grand Caravan. The strutted, high wing 208 typically seats nine passengers in its unpressurized cabin, is powered
        by a single Pratt &amp; Whitney Canada PT6A tractor turboprop and has a fixed tricycle landing gear, floats or skis. By November 2017, 2,600 have been delivered
        and 20 million flight hours logged. Caravans are used for flight training, commuter airlines, VIP transport, air cargo and humanitarian missions. As
        of November 2007, a total of 2,600 Caravans have been built.\n\nOn November 20, 1981, the project was given a go-ahead by Cessna for its Pawnee engineering
        facility. John Berwick, chief engineer at Pawnee, came with a concept of a single engine, high-wing airplane with a large payload. Berwick had originally
        approached VP Bill Boettger with the idea and once Dwane Wallace approved it, Berwick told Russ Meyer he would design it. The prototype first flew on December
        9, 1982. The production model was certified by the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) in October 1984. A freighter variant without cabin windows was developed
        at the request of Federal Express as the Cargomaster. Another cargo variant for Federal Express, with a longer fuselage and a cargo pod under the belly, was
        developed as the 208B Super Cargomaster and flew for the first time in 1986. FedEx was initially planning to build twin-engine piston-powered airplanes with
        Piper Aircraft, but picked the Caravan after surveying it and having flown the prototype, becoming its standard carrier. A passenger model, the 208B Grand Caravan,
        was derived from the Super Cargomaster. Since then, the Caravan has undergone a number of design evolutions, including upgrading the avionics in 2008 to provide
        a glass cockpit with the Garmin G1000 system. In January 2013 a higher-powered (867 shp from P&amp;WC PT6A-140) version, the Grand Caravan EX, received FAA
        certification.\n</string>

    <string name="caravan_desc2" formatted="false">In August 2016, Textron announced that it would move the Cessna 208 production line from its Wichita headquarters to
        its Independence, Kansas production facility, for manufacture alongside along the piston-powered 172, 182, 206 and TTx; and the Citation M2 light jet. The move
        was made to make room for production of the Citation Longitude and Denali in Wichita. In 2021, the 208 Caravan unit cost was US$2.45 million and US$2.845
        million for the 208B Grand Caravan EX.\n\nThe Cessna 208 is a high-wing braced cabin monoplane powered by a single Pratt &amp; Whitney Canada PT6A turboprop in
        tractor configuration. The cabin has room for nine passengers and two crew when used as a passenger aircraft with four doors: one for each crew member, an
        airstair door on the right side of the cabin and a cargo door on the left. The aircraft can be optionally fitted with an underslung cargo pod. The basic 208
        airframe has a fixed tricycle landing gear but can also be fitted with various types of landing gear, allowing it to operate in a wide variety of environments. Some
        common adaptations include floats with retractable landing gear on the Caravan Amphibian model, and skis. The Caravan interior can be outfitted with seats or as a
        cargo compartment. The standard high-density airline configuration has four rows of 1-2 seating behind the two seats in the cockpit. This variant is capable of
        holding up to thirteen passengers, although it is marketed as being able to make a profit carrying just four. The cabin can be configured in a low density
        passenger configuration, with 1-1 seating, as a combination of passengers and cargo, or as a strictly cargo aircraft.\n\nMany variants include an underbelly cargo
        pod, which can be used for additional freight capacity, or for passenger baggage. A number of Caravans are operated as skydiving aircraft with the left-side cargo
        hatch converted to a roll-up door. The airplane typically seats nine passengers with a single pilot, although with a FAR Part 23 waiver it can seat up to fourteen
        passengers. The aircraft is also used for cargo operations. The short-fuselage Caravan burns 180 L of fuel per hour at 170 kn (310 km/h) for 200 nmi (370 km)
        stages.\n</string>

    <string name="caravan_desc3">\nThe Cessna aircraft variants include 208 Caravan, 208 Caravan 675, 208A Cargomaster, 208B Grand Caravan, 208B Grand Caravan
        EX, 208B Super Cargomaster, Caravan Amphibian. Aftermarket variants are comprised of Soloy Pathfinder 21, 850 Caravan, 950 Grand Caravan, Blackhawk
        Caravan, Supervan 900, XP42A Upgrade; experimentals include the all electric eCaravan and military variants include U-27A, C-16, C-98, AC-208 Combat
        Caravan, MC-208 Guardian.\n</string>

    <string name="caravan_specs_constraint">(208 Caravan)\n</string>


    <string name="caravan_identify">How to identify 208 Caravan?</string>
    <string name="caravan_identify_ans">The standard Cessna Caravan has unequally sized air intakes on each side of the prop spinner and a large exhaust on the right
        side.</string>

    <string name="caravan_cockpit_value">1 / 2</string>
    <string name="caravan_wingspan_value">15.87 m</string>
    <string name="caravan_length_value">11.46 m</string>
    <string name="caravan_height_value">4.53 m</string>
    <string name="caravan_fuselage_value">1.63 m (W) / 1.37 m (H)</string>
    <string name="caravan_mtow_value">3.63 t</string>
    <string name="caravan_cruise_speed_value">344 km/h (max.)</string>
    <string name="caravan_range_value">1,070 nmi</string>
    <string name="caravan_thrust_value">675 shp (503 kW)</string>
    <!--CESSNA CARAVAN-->


    <!--SKYLANE-->
    <string name="skylane_type_value">Light utility aircraft</string>
    <string name="skylane_engine_value">Lycoming\nIO-540-AB1A5 (2)</string>
    <string name="skylane_intro_value">1956</string>
    <string name="skylane_variants_value">25</string>

    <string name="skylane_desc1" formatted="false">The Cessna 182 Skylane is an American four-seat, single-engined light airplane, built by Cessna of Wichita, Kansas. It
        has the option of adding two child seats, installed in the baggage area. Introduced in 1956, the 182 has been produced in a number of variants, including a
        version with retractable landing gear, and is the second most popular Cessna model still in production, after the 172. So far, a total of over
        23,237 Skylanes have been built.\n\nThe Cessna 182 was introduced in 1956 as a tricycle gear variant of the 180. In 1957, the 182A variant was introduced along
        with the name Skylane. As production continued, later models were improved regularly with features such as a wider fuselage, swept tailfin with
        rear \"omni-vision\" window, enlarged baggage compartment, higher gross weights, landing gear changes, etc. The \"restart\" aircraft built after 1996 were
        different in many other details including a different engine, new seating design, etc. By mid-2013, Cessna planned to introduce the next model of the 182T, the
        JT-A, using the 227 hp (169 kW) SMA SR305-230 diesel engine running on Jet-A with a burn rate of 42 L per hour and cruise at 155
        kn (287 km/h). Cessna has no timeline for the JT-A and the diesel 172. The normally aspirated, avgas fueled 182 went out of production in 2012, but came back
        in 2015. Cessna 182s were also built in Argentina by DINFIA (called A182), and by Reims Aviation, France, as the F182.\n</string>

    <string name="skylane_desc2" formatted="false">The Cessna 182 is an all-metal (mostly aluminum alloy) aircraft, although some parts – such as engine cowling nosebowl
        and wingtips – are made of fiberglass or thermoplastic material. Its wing has the same planform as the smaller Cessna 172 and the larger 205/206 series; however,
        some wing details such as flap and aileron design are the same as the 172 and are not like the 205/206 components. The retractable gear R182 and TR182 were
        offered from 1978 to 1986, without and with engine turbocharging respectively. The model designation nomenclature differs from some other Cessna models with
        optional retractable gear. For instance the retractable version of the Cessna 172 was designated as the 172RG, whereas the retractable gear version of the Cessna
        182 is the R182. Cessna gave the R182 the marketing name of \"Skylane RG\".\n\nThe R182 and TR182 offer 10-15% improvement in climb and cruise speeds over their
        fixed gear counterparts or, alternatively, 10-15% better fuel economy at the same speeds at the expense of increased maintenance costs and decreased gear
        robustness. The 1978 R182 has a sea level climb rate of 1140 fpm and cruising speed (75% BHP) at 2,300 m of 156 KTAS at standard temperature. The landing gear
        retraction system in the Skylane RG uses hydraulic actuators powered by an electrically driven pump. The system includes a gear position warning that emits an
        intermittent tone through the cabin speaker when the gear is in the retracted position and either the throttle is reduced below approximately 12\" MAP (manifold
        pressure) or the flaps are extended beyond 20 degrees. In the event of a hydraulic pump failure, the landing gear may be lowered using a hand pump to pressurize
        the hydraulic system. The system does not, however, allow the landing gear to be manually retracted.\n</string>

    <string name="skylane_desc3">\nSkylane variants include 182, 182A Skylane, 182B Skylane, 182C Skylane, 182D Skylane, 182E Skylane, 182F Skylane, 182G Skylane,
        182H Skylane, 182J Skylane, 182K Skylane, 182L Skylane, 182M Skylane, 182N Skylane, 182P Skylane, 182Q Skylane, 182R, 182S Skylane, 182T Skylane, R182 Skylane RG,
        T182, T182T Skylane, TR182 Turbo Skylane RG, T182JT-A Turbo Skylane JT-A, Robertson STOL 182.\n</string>

    <string name="skylane_specs_constraint">(Cessna 182T)\n</string>


    <string name="skylane_identify">How to identify Skylane?</string>
    <string name="skylane_identify_ans"></string>

    <string name="skylane_cockpit_value">1</string>
    <string name="skylane_wingspan_value">10.97 m</string>
    <string name="skylane_length_value">8.84 m</string>
    <string name="skylane_height_value">2.84 m</string>
    <string name="skylane_fuselage_value">1.07 m (W) / 1.2 m (H)</string>
    <string name="skylane_mtow_value">1.41 t</string>
    <string name="skylane_cruise_speed_value">269 km/h (typical),\n280 km/h (max.)</string>
    <string name="skylane_range_value">930 nmi</string>
    <string name="skylane_thrust_value">230 hp (170 kW)</string>
    <!--SKYLANE-->


    <!--GULFSTREAM G650-->
    <string name="gulfstream_g650_type_value">Business jet</string>
    <string name="gulfstream_g650_engine_value">Rolls-Royce BR725\nA1-12 / Pearl 700 (2)</string>
    <string name="gulfstream_g650_first_flight_value">25 November 2009</string>
    <string name="gulfstream_g650_customer_value">Qatar Executive as of juillet 2016</string>
    <string name="gulfstream_g650_variants_value">2 (active)</string>

    <string name="gulfstream_g650_desc1" formatted="false">The Gulfstream G650 was formally launched as an internal company project in May 2005, and publicly unveiled
        on March 13, 2008. At the public announcement occasion, company executives stated the new model would become Gulfstream\'s largest, fastest and most expensive
        business jet on entry to the market. The wing design was completed in 2006. A total of 1,400 hours of wind tunnel testing was completed by 2008. A pressure-test
        fuselage was built and tested, including an ultimate-pressure test of 18.37 psi (1,267 hPa). The G650 taxied under its own power for the first time on September
        26, 2009. A public rollout ceremony was later held on September 29, 2009. The G650 had its maiden flight on November 25, 2009. Flight testing for the maximum
        operating speed of Mach 0.925 was announced as completed on May 4, 2010. Gulfstream reported on August 26, 2010 that the G650 hit a maximum speed of Mach 0.995
        during a dive as part of its 1,800-hour flight test program. In April 2011, a G650 crashed shortly after lift off. The cause was determined to be related to the
        speeds carried out for the single engine take off run. The G650 test aircraft were grounded until May 28, 2011, when the remaining test aircraft were allowed to
        return to flight testing. On September 7, 2012, the G650 received its type certificate from the US Federal Aviation Administration (FAA). Its first delivery was
        to an American customer, Preston Henn, on December 27, 2012.\n\nThe G650 had a nominal list price of $64.5 million in 2013, but there was a three-year waiting
        list. Some aircraft produced for delivery in 2013 sold for more than $70 million to buyers that wanted to take immediate delivery. After rising to $71-73 million
        in 2014, initial enthusiasm dissipated and the value of pre-owned G650s stabilized at $50 million after the competing Bombardier Global 7500 was certified in
        2018. On May 18, 2014, Gulfstream announced at the annual European Business Aviation Association exhibition, that it had developed an extended range version
        called the G650ER. The G650ER is capable of flying 7,500 nautical miles (13,900 km; 8,600 mi) at Mach 0.85, due to its 1,814 kg increase in fuel
        capacity. Gulfstream stated that in March a G650ER development aircraft had flown non-stop from Hong Kong to Teterboro, New Jersey in the United States,a
        distance of 7,494 nautical miles (13,879 km; 8,624 mi).\n\nIt had also flown non-stop from Los Angeles to Melbourne in Australia. The extra fuel is housed in
        existing space inside the G650\'s wings and aircraft already built may be quickly upgraded to the ER version. The G650ER received its certification in October
        2014 and began deliveries in late 2014 ahead of its 2015 target. The G650ER attempted two world records from New York to Beijing to Savannah in February
        2015. The same year, a G650ER set a new record for the longest non-stop flight by a purpose-built business jet, flying 8,010 nautical miles (14,835 km; 9,218 mi)
        from Singapore to Las Vegas with four passengers and crew. The record was surpassed by a Bombardier Global 7500 in March 2019, before the G650ER retook the record
        in April 2019 by flying 8,379 nmi (15,518 km) from Singapore to Tucson.\n</string>

    <string name="gulfstream_g650_desc2" formatted="false">In 2021, its equipped price was $68.5M for the G650, and $70.5M for the G650ER. On the eve of the
        October 2019 NBAA Convention &amp; Exhibition in Las Vegas, Gulfstream announced its new flagship, the G700, showing a video of the aircraft taxiing under its own
        power in Savannah. It should fly 7,500 nmi/13,890 km at Mach 0.85 or 6,400 nmi/11,853 km at Mach 0.90. Its longer cabin can accommodate up to five areas. It is powered
        by Rolls-Royce Pearl 700 engines and has new winglets. Customer deliveries should start in 2022. The $75 million jet is a 3.0 m stretch of the G650. The
        aircraft completed its first flight on February 14, 2020.\n\nThe G650 has a cruise speed of Mach 0.85 to 0.90, with maximum speed of Mach 0.925 and a range of up to 7,000
        nmi (13,000 km). It can be equipped with a full kitchen and bar and may be equipped with a variety of entertainment features including satellite telephones and
        wireless Internet. The jet uses two Rolls-Royce BR725 engines, each producing a maximum thrust of 75.6 kN. Gulfstream states that with a
        weight of less than 45,400 kg, it is able to land at small airports avoiding the busy airports around the world. To provide better usage of the internal volume,
        Gulfstream designers rejected the usual circular fuselage cross-section in favor of an oval which uses a flatter lower portion. The cabin is 2.59 m wide and 1.96 m
        high, allowing the craft to be configured to carry between 11 and 18 passengers. The fuselage is of metal construction; composite materials are used for
        empennage, winglets, rear pressure bulkhead, engine cowlings, cabin floor structure and many fairings. The elliptical cabin windows, eight on each side of the
        fuselage, are 71 cm wide. Panels are bonded rather than riveted, reducing parts count compared to the G550.\n\nThe wing uses greater sweep (36 degrees) than
        previous Gulfstream aircraft (for example, the G550 wing has 27 degrees of sweep). It does not use leading-edge high-lift devices, and tracks for rear-mounted
        flaps are completely enclosed within the airfoil contour. The wing\'s leading edge is a continuously-changing curve, and the airfoil varies continuously from
        root to tip, which incorporates winglets. The aircraft controls are completely fly-by-wire, with no mechanical control between pilot and flight surfaces. The
        surfaces are moved by dual hydraulic systems. The G650 shares its yokes and column with the G550 in an effort to receive a common type rating. While most newer
        airliners now employ fly-by-wire technology, the G650 was only the second fly-by-wire business jet, after the Dassault Falcon 7X and before the Embraer Legacy
        500. At FL 470 and ISA-7°C, it cruises at Mach 0.85 or 480 kn (890 km/h) TAS and burns 1,100 kg per hour at a weight of 30,600 kg, raising to 1,400 kg per hour at
        Mach 0.90 or 506 kn (937 km/h) TAS. The G700\'s flight deck is upgraded to the Symmetry flight deck from the G500/G600.\n</string>

    <string name="gulfstream_g650_desc3">\nThe G650 variants include the initial production version G650, G650ER, G700.\n</string>

    <string name="gulfstream_g650_specs_constraint">(G650, G650ER, G700 compared in order)\n</string>


    <string name="gulfstream_g650_identify">How to identify Gulfstream G650?</string>
    <string name="gulfstream_g650_identify_ans"></string>

    <string name="gulfstream_g650_cockpit_value">2</string>
    <string name="gulfstream_g650_wingspan_value">30.36 m / 31.39 m (G700)</string>
    <string name="gulfstream_g650_length_value">30.41 m / 33.48 m (G700)</string>
    <string name="gulfstream_g650_height_value">7.72 m / 7.75 m (G700)</string>
    <string name="gulfstream_g650_fuselage_value">2.49 m (W) / 1.91 m (H)</string>
    <string name="gulfstream_g650_mtow_value">45.18 / 46.99 / 48.81 t</string>
    <string name="gulfstream_g650_cruise_speed_value">904 km/h (typical),\n956 km/h (max.)</string>
    <string name="gulfstream_g650_range_value">7,000 nmi (G650) / 7,500 nmi</string>
    <string name="gulfstream_g650_thrust_value">75.2 kN / 81.2 kN (G700)</string>
    <!--GULFSTREAM G650-->


    <!--GULFSTREAM G280-->
    <string name="gulfstream_g280_type_value">Business jet</string>
    <string name="gulfstream_g280_engine_value">Honeywell HTF7250G (2)</string>
    <string name="gulfstream_g280_first_flight_value">11 December 2009</string>
    <string name="gulfstream_g280_numbers_value">~200 (May 2020)</string>
    <string name="gulfstream_g280_variants_value">1</string>

    <string name="gulfstream_g280_desc1" formatted="false">The Gulfstream G280 is a twin-engine business jet built by Israel Aerospace Industries (IAI) for Gulfstream
        Aerospace. In 2005, Gulfstream and IAI began designing a follow-on aircraft to the Gulfstream G200. The new model, named G250, was launched in 2008. Planned
        improvements included new glass cockpit and engines, larger wing, and heated leading edges. The G250 took its maiden flight on December 11, 2009 in Tel Aviv,
        Israel. In July 2011, the G250 was renamed G280, as the company had \"determined that G280 is a more amenable number sequence (than G250) in certain cultures.\"
        In Mandarin, the number 250 can be translated as \"stupid\" or \"idiotic\".\n\nAfter the flight test program, the G280 demonstrated a range of 3,600 nmi (6,667 km)
        at Mach 0.80 with four passengers and NBAA IFR reserves in 2011. It can fly from London to New York or Singapore to Dubai. Its balanced field length has been
        reduced to 1,448 m from the G200\'s 1,512 m. The G280 was provisionally certified in December 2011 by Israel. In July 2012, the US FAA released a report with
        conditions to ensure no security gaps in the G280\'s electronic systems. It received full certification from Israel and the US on September 4, 2012. In 2021, its
        equipped price was $24.5M.\n</string>

    <string name="gulfstream_g280_desc2" formatted="false">The aerodynamic design of its wing and empennage, and design of the interior were performed by Gulfstream;
        detailed design was performed by IAI to Gulfstream\'s requirements. It is a Gulfstream designed aircraft under a new type certificate. The aircraft has several
        improvements, among them increased cabin length (external fuselage dimensions remain unchanged; the rear fuselage fuel tank was eliminated to add 43 cm of usable
        interior area). It has a new HTF7250G engine, new T-tail (with larger horizontal and vertical stabilizers), wing anti-ice provided by engine bleed air, cabin
        with four more windows and access from the cabin to the baggage compartment.\n\nIt competes against the Bombardier Challenger 300 and the Cessna Citation X+. The
        fuselage, empennage and landing gear are manufactured by IAI, the wing by Spirit AeroSystems (now by Triumph Group), and the aircraft is assembled in Israel. It
        is then ferried to Dallas, Texas, for interior finishing and painting. Its wing is a new design, using the Gulfstream G550 airfoil, and has a larger area of
        495 ft<sup><small><small>2</small></small></sup> vs. 369 ft<sup><small><small>2</small></small></sup> of the G200. This allows the business jet to climb directly to 13,000 m. Design cruise for the new airfoil is Mach 0.80, vs. Mach 0.75 for the G200
        wing. Flying at an altitude of 12,000 m and Mach 0.82 (467 kn or 865 km/h), each engine burns 410 kg of fuel per hour.\n</string>

    <string name="gulfstream_g280_desc3">\n</string>

    <string name="gulfstream_g280_specs_constraint">()\n</string>


    <string name="gulfstream_g280_identify">How to identify Gulfstream G280?</string>
    <string name="gulfstream_g280_identify_ans"></string>

    <string name="gulfstream_g280_cockpit_value">2</string>
    <string name="gulfstream_g280_wingspan_value">19.2 m</string>
    <string name="gulfstream_g280_length_value">20.3 m</string>
    <string name="gulfstream_g280_height_value">6.5 m</string>
    <string name="gulfstream_g280_fuselage_value">2.11 m (W) / 1.85 m (H)</string>
    <string name="gulfstream_g280_mtow_value">17.96 t</string>
    <string name="gulfstream_g280_cruise_speed_value">850 km/h (typical),\n~871 km/h (max.)</string>
    <string name="gulfstream_g280_range_value">3,600 nmi with\n4 passengers</string>
    <string name="gulfstream_g280_thrust_value">33.91 kN</string>
    <!--GULFSTREAM G280-->


    <!--GULFSTREAM IV-->
    <string name="gulfstream_iv_type_value">Business jet</string>
    <string name="gulfstream_iv_engine_value">Rolls-Royce Tay 611-8 /\nTay 611-8C (2)</string>
    <string name="gulfstream_iv_first_flight_value">19 September 1985</string>
    <string name="gulfstream_iv_customer_value">United States Air Force</string>
    <string name="gulfstream_iv_variants_value">7</string>

    <string name="gulfstream_iv_desc1" formatted="false">The Gulfstream IV (or G-IV or GIV) and derivatives are a family of twinjet aircraft, mainly for private or business
        use. They were designed and built by Gulfstream Aerospace, a General Dynamics company based in Savannah, Georgia, United States, from 1985 until 2018. Aircraft
        power is provided by two Rolls-Royce RB.183 Tay turbofans. Upon delivery of the last G450, over 900 GIV/GIV-SP/G450 units had been produced. The last G450 was
        delivered on 19 January 2018 after 365 deliveries over 12 years, ending a 30-year production run, to be replaced by the G500. During its production phase from 1985
        to 2018, more than 900 G-IVs have been built.\n\nGulfstream, in collaboration with Grumman, began work on the Gulfstream IV in March 1983 as a re-engined,
        stretched fuselage derivative of the Gulfstream III. The first GIV made its maiden flight on September 19, 1985. The model received type certification from the
        FAA on April 22, 1987. The G-IV entered into service with serial number 1000 in 1987 and was upgraded to the special purpose GIV-SP version at serial number 1214
        in 1993. It was later redesignated G400 at serial number 1500. A shorter range variant was created based on the GIV and given the G300 designation in 2002. In
        2001, Gulfstream began work on an improved version of the GIV-SP, originally designated GIV-X. It was later renamed G450. The G450 is lengthened 0.305 m over the
        G400 and shares the forward fuselage and larger cockpit of the G550. Production of the G450 began in October 2004, replacing the G400. The G450 has better
        performance and comes with the PlaneView cockpit with four 14-inch (355 mm) liquid crystal displays and a Head up display (HUD). The shorter range G350 version
        of the G450 was developed and received certification in 2004.\n</string>

    <string name="gulfstream_iv_desc2" formatted="false">By 2018, 1990 to 1992 GIVs were for sale at $1.6-4.4 million, 1992 to 1999 GIVSPs were listed for $1.25-5.2
        million, 15-year-old G300s and G400s were available for $4.5-7 million and 2006 to 2016 G450s at $9.95-23.75 million.\n\nCompared to the Gulfstream III, a decision
        to redesign the wing structure for weight reduction presented an opportunity for an aerodynamic redesign of the wing to reduce cruise drag and increase range. Wing
        contour modifications had to be restricted to the forward 65% of wing chord so that no redesign of the control surfaces would be necessary. Modification of the
        inboard wing would have entailed a redesign of the fuselage floor structure, consequently this region of the wing was not modified. Outboard wing modifications
        were aimed at reducing the peak subcritical pressure coefficient and moving it aft in an effort to reduce shock strength and increase shock sweep.\n\nThe
        Gulfstream IV wing has a weaker, more swept outboard shock resulting in a lower cruise drag. Other benefits arising from this design are a lower root bending
        moment due to the more inboard center of pressure, a lower stall speed due to washout and a larger fuel volume due to increased chord. These aerodynamic
        improvements result in an increase in range of over 300 nautical miles. In addition to the wing redesign, the Gulfstream IV also became the first business jet
        to have an entire glass cockpit. The G400 has a large cabin, long range of 4,350 nautical miles (8,060 km) and the same comfort and design that characterize the
        G series. Maximum cruise height and speed are 45,000 ft and Mach 0.77. Earlier models were fitted with Honeywell\'s SPZ 8000 Avionics package. The SPZ 8400
        Avionics Package was an option, becoming standard on later models. Its second-hand price was below $15 million in 2009.\n\nThe National Oceanic and Atmospheric
        Administration (NOAA) operates a GIV-SP (N49RF) modified to fly scientists and crew members at 45,000 feet around tropical cyclones. The aircraft was modified to
        drop instruments called \"dropsondes\" to measure windspeed, barometric pressure, humidity, and temperature as they fall to the surface of the ocean. By sampling the
        cyclone with these dropsondes over a 4,000 mile track around the storm, the forecasters at NOAA\'s National Hurricane Center and Hurricane Research Division can
        better predict where the hurricane will be \"steered\" by the upper level winds. They also predict wind shear that will either increase or decrease a hurricane\'s
        strength. The GIV-SP is suited for this mission since it is fast, and can fly long distances with ample cabin space for the crew and instruments. In 2009, the
        NOAA GIV-SP was further modified by the addition of a side-scanning Doppler radar to the rear fuselage. This radar is used for storm cloud profiling. In June
        1987 a Gulfstream IV set 22 world records in its class in flying west around the world in 45 hr 25 min. The next year another GIV set 11 world records flying east
        around the world. In 1990, Gulfstream CEO Allen Paulson and a Gulfstream flight crew set 35 international records for around-the-world flight in a GIV.\n</string>

    <string name="gulfstream_iv_desc3">\nG-IV variants include G-IV, C-20F/G/H/J military aircraft, G350/G450 - a designation for the model GIV-X, approved by the FAA on August 12, 2004, as is the G350, which has a reduced
        fuel capacity.\n</string>

    <string name="gulfstream_iv_specs_constraint">(GIV, GIV-SP, G350, G450 compared in order)\n</string>


    <string name="gulfstream_iv_identify">How to identify Gulfstream IV?</string>
    <string name="gulfstream_iv_identify_ans"></string>

    <string name="gulfstream_iv_cockpit_value">2</string>
    <string name="gulfstream_iv_wingspan_value">23.72m</string>
    <string name="gulfstream_iv_length_value">26.92 m / 27.23 m (G350 / G450)</string>
    <string name="gulfstream_iv_height_value">7.45 m / 7.67 m (G350 / G450)</string>
    <string name="gulfstream_iv_mtow_value">33.2 / 33.8 / 32.2 / 33.8 t</string>
    <string name="gulfstream_iv_cruise_speed_value">850–903 km/h (typical),\n935 km/h (max.)</string>
    <string name="gulfstream_iv_range_value">4,220 nmi / 3,800 nmi (G350) /\n4,350 nmi (G450)</string>
    <string name="gulfstream_iv_thrust_value">61.6 kN</string>
    <!--GULFSTREAM IV-->

    <string name="status_listening">LISTENING…</string>
    <string name="status_processing">PROCESSING…</string>
    <string name="status_speaking">SPEAKING…</string>
    <string name="fragment_action_send_audio">Send Audio</string>
    <string name="action_send_audio_description">Press the microphone to start recording. Recording will end either when pressed again or end of speech detected.\n\n\nSending audio can be very efficient if using the DataRequestBody option, since it can write to the POST while the audio is still being recorded, giving the impression of a very fast response. This can also be used to prepend or append audio to a recorded stream, if you wanted to limit the control to a single skill: "Open Hey Dad and ask for a joke about…" followed by the joke type..</string>


    <string name="login">Login with Amazon</string>
    <string name="instruction">Press Alexa button and start talking. The recorder will stop automatically or press the button again to manually stop it</string>
    <string name="close">Got it</string>
    <string name="title_activity_maps">Map</string>

    <string name="map_loading1">Pushback</string>
    <string name="map_loading2">Taxiing</string>
    <string name="map_loading3">Buckle up, taking off soon</string>
    <string name="connection_timed_out">Oops connection timed out</string>
    <string name="retry">Retry</string>

    <string name="loading">Loading</string>

    <string name="aircraft">Aircraft</string>
    <string name="airline">Airline</string>
    <string name="engine_type">Engine type</string>
    <string name="country">Country of reg.</string>
    <string name="callsign">Callsign</string>
    <string name="icao">ICAO 24-bit address</string>
    <string name="geo_altitude">Geometric altitude</string>
    <string name="baro_altitude">Barometric altitude</string>
    <string name="velocity">Velocity</string>
    <string name="vertical_rate">Vertical speed</string>
    <string name="latitude">Latitude</string>
    <string name="longitude">Longitude</string>
    <string name="on_ground">On Ground</string>
    <string name="track">Track</string>
    <string name="squawk">Squawk</string>
    <string name="pos_source">Position source</string>
    <string name="spi">Special Purpose Indicator</string>
    <string name="live">LIVE</string>
    <string name="not_true">False</string>
    <string name="_true">True</string>


    <string name="drawer_airplane">&#xe902;</string>
    <string name="drawer_radar">&#xe903;</string>
    <string name="drawer_alexa">&#xe900;</string>
    <string name="drawer_tail">&#xe904;</string>
    <string name="drawer_manufacturer">&#xe901;</string>
    <string name="drawer_firebase">&#xe905;</string>


    <string name="snackbar">No internet connection</string>

    <string name="not_available">N/A</string>

    <string name="aircraft_gallery">Aircraft Gallery</string>
    <string name="tracker_menu">Real Time Flight Tracker</string>
    <string name="alexa_menu">Ask Alexa</string>
    <string name="community">Community</string>
    <string name="next_button">&#10095;</string>
    <string name="finish_button">Finish</string>




</resources>