<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Aeropedia</string>
    <string name="manufacturers">Manufacturers</string>
    <string name="ask_alexa">Ask Alexa</string>
    <string name="flight_tracker">Flight Tracker</string>
    <string name="firebase">My Aircraft</string>
    <string name="airbus">Airbus</string>
    <string name="boeing">Boeing</string>
    <string name="embraer">Embraer</string>
    <string name="bombardier">Bombardier</string>
    <string name="cessna">Cessna</string>
    <string name="gulfstream">Gulfstream</string>
    <string name="antonov">Antonov</string>
    <string name="a350">A350</string>
    <string name="a380">A380</string>
    <string name="a320">A320</string>
    <string name="a319">A319</string>
    <string name="a318">A318</string>
    <string name="a300">A300</string>
    <string name="a310">A310</string>
    <string name="a340">A340</string>
    <string name="a321">A321</string>
    <string name="a330">A330</string>
    <string name="a330neo">A330neo</string>
    <string name="a320neofamily">A320neo Family</string>
    <string name="a220">A220</string>
    <string name="beluga">Beluga</string>
    <string name="an124">An-124 Ruslan</string>
    <string name="an72">An-72 Cheburashka</string>
    <string name="language"><b>FR</b></string>


    <!--BASICS-->
    <string name="type">Type</string>
    <string name="engine">Engine</string>
    <string name="first_flight">First flight</string>
    <string name="intro">Introduction</string>
    <string name="customer">Largest operator</string>
    <string name="variants">Variants</string>

    <string name="specs">Specifications</string>
    <string name="cockpit_crew">Cockpit crew</string>
    <string name="wingspan">Wing span</string>
    <string name="length">Length</string>
    <string name="height">Height</string>
    <string name="fuselage">Fuselage</string>
    <string name="gross_weight">Gross weight</string>
    <string name="mtow">MTOW</string>
    <string name="cruise_speed">Cruise speed</string>
    <string name="range">Range</string>
    <string name="thrust2">Thrust (2x)</string>
    <string name="thrust4">Thrust (4x)</string>
    <!--BASICS-->

    <!--AIRBUS A350-->
    <string name="a350_type_value">Wide-body</string>
    <string name="a350_engine_value">Rolls-Royce Trent XWB (2)</string>
    <string name="a350_first_flight_value">14 June 2013</string>
    <string name="a350_intro_value">15 January 2015\nwith Qatar Airways</string>
    <string name="a350_customer_value">Singapore Airlines</string>
    <string name="a350_variants_value">2 (active)</string>


    <string name="a350_desc1">The Airbus A350 is a long-range, wide-body jet airliner. The first A350 design proposed by Airbus in 2004,
        in response to Boeing\'s 787 Dreamliner, would have been a development of the A330 (hence A330-Lite) with composite wings and new engines. However,
        market support was inadequate at the time and in 2006, Airbus switched to a clean-sheet XWB (eXtra Wide Body) design, powered by Rolls-Royce Trent XWB
        turbofan engines. The A350 is the first aircraft of the Airbus family that is largely made of carbon fibre reinforced polymer. It features a new fuselage designed around a
        nine-abreast economy cross-section, up from the eight-abreast A330/A340. The A350 has been in production since 2010 and in total 425 A350s have been built as of
        31 May 2021.\n\nThe A350 XWB airframe is made out of 53% composites: carbon fibre reinforced plastic for the outer and centre wing box (covers, stringers, spars),
        fuselage (skin, frame, keel beam, and rear fuselage) and the empennage (horizontal and vertical tailplanes); 19% aluminium and aluminium–lithium alloy for ribs,
        floor beams, and gear bays; 14% titanium for landing gears, pylons, and attachments; 6% steel; and 8% miscellaneous. For the wings, those mark a 31.9° sweep angle for a
        Mach 0.85 cruise speed and has a maximum operating speed of Mach 0.89, with the wingtip device curving upwards over the final 4.4 m (14 ft) - reducing air resistance and
        subsequently increasing the aircraft’s range whilst restricting fuel consumption to minimum.\n</string>

    <string name="a350_desc2" formatted="false">For the deck and avionics design,
        the design strategy for Airbus\' own A380 was used as a base. The focus of the company was to evolve technology for A350 further than the advances already made
        by the A380. It is one of three aircraft to feature avionics manufacturer Honeywell\’s Aircraft Environmental Surveillance System (AESS) which integrates weather, traffic and
        terrain awareness capabilities reducing as many as eight avionics boxes down to just two. It also features On-Board Airport Navigation System (OANS) which first debuted with
        the A380. This system provides real-time directions around airports and improves navigation on the ground. The system is especially useful in poor visibility conditions
        and helps to reduce errors in airport navigation by warning the pilots if they are going the wrong way. To help the pilots further, Airbus equipped the aircraft
        with External and Taxiing Aid Camera System (ETACS) for better navigation and aircraft positioning on the ground. digital cameras provide the pilots with views
        from outside with one positioned behind the nose wheel and the other in the vertical tail. The views from the cameras can be displayed in the A350 cockpit on displays
        and as well as on the passenger in-flight entertainment screens.\n\nThe Airbus A350 consumes 25% less fuel and emits 25% less emissions than previous generations and according to Airbus it is the quietest two aisle plane
        on the planet. Australia\'s Qantas chose A350 over Boeing\'s 787 Dreamliner for "Project Sunrise" – a codename for proposed nonstop flights between Australia
        and several international destinations that include London, New York and Paris.\n
    </string>

    <string name="a350_desc3">\nAirbus A350\'s variants include A350-800, A350-900, A350-ULR, ACJ350, A350 Regional, A350-950 F, A350-1000, although some of
        these were discontinued or did not make it past the early stages.\n</string>

    <string name="a350_specs_constraint">(-900 and -1000 variants compared in order)\n</string>

    <string name="a350_wingspan_value">64.75 m</string>
    <string name="a350_length_value">66.8 / 73.79 m</string>
    <string name="a350_height_value">17.05 / 17.08 m</string>
    <string name="a350_fuselage_value">5.96 m (W) / 6.09 m (H)</string>
    <string name="a350_mtow_value">280 / 316 t</string>
    <string name="a350_cruise_speed_value">903 km/h (typical),\n950 km/h (max.)</string>
    <string name="a350_range_value">8100 / 8700 nmi</string>
    <string name="a350_thrust_value">374.5 / 431.5 kN</string>

    <string name="a350_identify">How to identify Airbus A350?</string>
    <string name="a350_identify_ans">The unique 6-piece round-edged windscreen configuration with black border, distinctive nose, smoothly curved sharklets like those on A330neo.</string>
    <!--AIRBUS A350-->

    <!--AIRBUS A380-->
    <string name="a380_type_value">Wide-body</string>
    <string name="a380_engine_value">Rolls-Royce Trent 900 (4)/\nEngine Alliance GP7000(4)</string>
    <string name="a380_first_flight_value">27 April 2005</string>
    <string name="a380_intro_value">25 October 2007\nwith Singapore Airlines</string>
    <string name="a380_customer_value">Emirates</string>
    <string name="a380_variants_value">4 (active)</string>

    <string name="a380_desc1" formatted="false">The Airbus A380 is the world\'s largest passenger airliner. Airbus studies started in 1988, and the project was announced in
        1990 to challenge the dominance of the Boeing 747 in the long haul market. The then-designated A3XX project was presented in 1994. Airbus launched
        the €9.5 billion ($10.7 billion) A380 programme on 19 December 2000. As of 31 December 2020, 246 A380s have been built, most of which went to
        the fleet family of Emirates. The aircraft still remains in service for many airlines but is no longer in production on Airbus\' side.\n\nThe A380\'s upper and
        lower decks are connected by two stairways, one fore and one aft, with both being wide enough to accommodate two passengers side by side. This cabin arrangement
        allows multiple seat configurations. The maximum certified carrying capacity is 853 passengers in an all-economy-class layout, Airbus lists the "typical"
        three-class layout as accommodating 525 passengers, with 10 first, 76 business, and 439 economy class seats. Airline configurations range from Korean Air\'s
        407 passengers to Emirates\' two-class 615 seats and average around 480–490 seats.
        \n\nWhile most of
        the fuselage is made of aluminium alloys, composite materials comprise more than 20% of the A380\'s airframe. Carbon-fibre reinforced plastic, glass-fibre
        reinforced plastic and quartz-fibre reinforced plastic are used extensively in wings, fuselage sections (such as the undercarriage and rear end of fuselage),
        tail surfaces, and doors. The A380, often nicknamed the superjumbo, is the first commercial airliner to have a central wing box made of carbon–fibre reinforced plastic. It is
        also the first to have a smoothly contoured wing cross–section. The wings of other commercial airliners are partitioned span-wise into sections. This flowing
        continuous cross section reduces aerodynamic drag. Thermoplastics are used in the leading edges of the slats. The hybrid fibre metal laminate material GLARE
        (glass laminate aluminium reinforced epoxy) is used in the upper fuselage and on the stabilisers\' leading edges. This aluminium-glass-fibre laminate is
        lighter and has better corrosion and impact resistance than conventional aluminium alloys used in aviation. Unlike earlier composite materials, GLARE can be
        repaired using conventional aluminium repair techniques.\n</string>

    <string name="a380_desc2" formatted="false">Due to its modern engines and aerodynamic improvements, Lufthansa\'s A380s produce half the noise of the
        Boeing 747-200 while carrying 160 more passengers. In 2012, the A380 received an award from the Noise Abatement Society.\nThe A380 employs an integrated
        modular avionics (IMA) architecture, first used in advanced military aircraft, such as the Lockheed Martin F-22 Raptor, Lockheed Martin F-35 Lightning II,
        and Dassault Rafale. Designed and developed by Airbus, Thales and Diehl Aerospace, the IMA suite was first used on the A380. The suite is a technological
        innovation, with networked computing modules to support different applications.The data networks use Avionics Full-Duplex Switched Ethernet. These are switched,
        full-duplex, star-topology and based on 100baseTX fast-Ethernet. This reduces the amount of wiring required and minimises latency.\n\nThe Network Systems Server (NSS) is
        the heart of A380\'s paperless cockpit; it eliminates bulky manuals and traditional charts. The NSS has enough inbuilt robustness to eliminate onboard backup
        paper documents. The A380s network and server system stores data and offers electronic documentation, providing a required equipment list, navigation charts,
        performance calculations, and an aircraft logbook.\n\nIn February 2019, Airbus announced it would end A380 production by 2021, after its main customer,
        Emirates, agreed to drop an order for 39 of the aircraft, replacing it with 40 A330-900s and 30 A350-900s. At the time of the announcement, Airbus had 17
        more A380s on its order book to complete before closing the production line – 14 for Emirates and 3 for All Nippon Airways – taking the total number of
        expected deliveries of the aircraft type to 251.\n
    </string>

    <string name="a380_desc3">\nAirbus A380\'s active variants include A380-800, A380-841, A380-842, A380-861. Airbus also proposed a handful of new variants that included
    a cargo variant of the A380, the A380F. The freighter would have been a rival for Boeing 747 and Antonov An-225 Mriya. A380F was postponed after 2005 and was
        never built. Other proposed variants included A380plus, A380neo, A380 Stretch with improvements regarding efficiency, capacity, and engine tweaks.\n</string>

    <string name="a380_specs_constraint">(-800, Trent engines)\n</string>

    <string name="a380_identify">How to identify Airbus A380?</string>
    <string name="a380_identify_ans">A380 is an aircraft that is easily recognizable. The characteristic ovoid fuselage, 4 engines, distinctive "bulbous" nose, and of course,
        2 passenger decks stretching across the length of the fuselage.</string>

    <string name="a380_cockpit_value">2</string>
    <string name="a380_wingspan_value">79.75 m</string>
    <string name="a380_length_value">72.72 m</string>
    <string name="a380_height_value">24.09 m</string>
    <string name="a380_fuselage_value">7.1 m (W) / ~7 m (H)</string>
    <string name="a380_mtow_value">575 t</string>
    <string name="a380_cruise_speed_value">903 km/h (typical),\n945 km/h (max.)</string>
    <string name="a380_range_value">8,000 nmi</string>
    <string name="a380_thrust_value">348 kN</string>
    <!--AIRBUS A380-->

    <!--AIRBUS A340-->
    <string name="a340_type_value">Wide-body</string>
    <string name="a340_engine_value">CFM56-5C/\nRR Trent 553/556 (4)</string>
    <string name="a340_first_flight_value">25 October 1991</string>
    <string name="a340_intro_value">15 March 1993 with\nLufthansa &amp; Air France</string>
    <string name="a340_customer_value">Lufthansa</string>
    <string name="a340_variants_value">4</string>

    <string name="a340_desc1" formatted="false">In the mid-1970s, Airbus conceived several derivatives of the A300, its first airliner, and developed the A340 quadjet
        in parallel with the A330 twinjet. Keeping the eight-abreast economy cross-section of the A300, the early A340-200/300 has a similar airframe to the A330.
        Differences include four 151 kN (34,000 lbf) CFM56s instead of two high-thrust turbofans to bypass ETOPS restrictions on trans-oceanic routes, and a three-leg
        main landing gear instead of two for a heavier 276 t (608,000 lb) MTOW. Both airliners have fly-by-wire controls, which was first introduced on the A320, as well
        as a similar glass cockpit. A total of 380 A340s have been built before its production ended in 2011.\n\nIts features and improvements were usually shared with the A330.
        The four engines configuration avoided the ETOPS constraints such as more frequent inspections. The A340 has a low cantilever wing; the A340-200/300 wing is virtually
        identical to that of the A330, with both engine pylons used while only the inboard one is used on the A330. The two engines for each wing provide a more distributed
        weight; and a more outboard engine weight for a lower wing root bending moment at equal TOW, allowing a higher wing limited MTOW for more range. The wings were
        designed and manufactured by BAe, which developed a long slender wing with a high aspect ratio for a higher aerodynamic efficiency. The wing is swept back at
        30 degrees, allowing a maximum operating Mach number of 0.86. To reach a long span and high aspect ratio without a large weight penalty, the wing has
        relatively high Thickness-to-chord ratio of 11.8% or 12.8%. Each wing also has a 2.74 m tall winglet instead of the wingtip fences found on earlier Airbus aircraft. The failure
        of the ultra-high-bypass IAE SuperFan, promising around 15% better fuel burn, led to wing upgrades to compensate. Originally designed with a 56 m
        span, the wing was later extended to 58.6 m and finally to 60.3 m. This wingspan is similar to that of the larger Boeing 747-200, but with
        35% less wing area.\n</string>

    <string name="a340_desc2" formatted="false">The A340 uses a modified A320 glass cockpit, with side-stick controls instead of a conventional yoke. The main instrument
        panel is dominated by six displays, cathode ray tube monitors initially then liquid crystal displays. Flight information is directed via the Electronic Flight
        Instrument System (EFIS) and systems information through the Electronic Centralised Aircraft Monitor (ECAM). The aircraft monitors various sensors and
        automatically alerts the crew to any parameters outside of their normal range; pilots can also inspect individual systems. Electronic manuals are used
        instead of paper ones, with optional web-based updates. Maintenance difficulty and cost were reduced to half of that of the earlier and smaller Airbus A310.
        Improved engine control and monitoring improved time on wing. The centralised maintenance computer can transmit real-time information to ground facilities via
        the onboard satellite-based ACARS datalink. Heavy maintenance like structural changes remained unchanged, while cabin sophistications, like the in-flight
        entertainment, were increased over preceding airliners.\n\nOn 16 June 1993, an A340-200 dubbed the World Ranger flew from the Paris Air Show to Auckland,
        New Zealand in 21 hours 32 minutes and back in 21 hours 46 minutes after a five-hour stop; this was the first non-stop flight between Europe and New Zealand
        and the longest non-stop flight by an airliner at the time. The 19,277 km (10,409 nmi) flight from Paris to Auckland broke six world records with 22 persons
        and five center tanks. Taking off at 11:58 local time, it arrived back in Paris 48 hours and 22 minutes later, at 12:20. This record held until
        1997 when a Boeing 777-200ER flew 20,044 km (10,823 nmi) from Seattle to Kuala Lumpur. The McDonnell Douglas MD-11 and the Boeing 777 were
        its main competitors. The A340 was coping up well with its competitors and in some cases, even better as Singapore Airlines cancelled its 20-aircraft MD-11
        order on 2 August 1991, and ordered 20 A340-300s instead. However, as improving engine reliability allowed ETOPS operations for almost all routes,
        more economical twin-jets have replaced quad-jets on many routes. On 10 November 2011, Airbus announced that the production reached its end, after 380
        orders had been placed and 377 delivered from Toulouse, France. Later, the A350 XWB was announced its successor.\n</string>

    <string name="a340_desc3">\nAirbus A340\'s variants include A340-200, A340-300, A340-500, A340-600. The -600 variant is the longest in the A340 family. It is even
        longer than most Boeing 747s and the A380.\n</string>

    <string name="a340_specs_constraint">(-200, -300, -500, -600 variants compared in order)\n</string>

    <string name="a340_identify">How to identify Airbus A340?</string>
    <string name="a340_identify_ans">The A340 is one of the few quad-jets in the world. The single passenger deck stretching the length of the fuselage with
        4 engines, centre-line wheel bogie, wings with straight, sharp-angled, short wingtips like A330\'s should catch the eyes of most aviation enthusiasts.</string>

    <string name="a340_cockpit_value">2</string>
    <string name="a340_wingspan_value">60.3 m (-200 &amp; -300) /\n63.45 m (-500 &amp; -600)</string>
    <string name="a340_length_value">59.39 / 63.69 /\n67.93 / 75.36 m</string>
    <string name="a340_height_value">17.03 / 16.99 /\n17.53 / 17.93 m</string>
    <string name="a340_fuselage_value">5.29 m (W) / ~5.5 m (H)</string>
    <string name="a340_mtow_value">275 t (-200) / 276.5 t (-300) / 380 t (-500 &amp; -600)</string>
    <string name="a340_cruise_speed_value">871 km/h (typical),\n914 km/h (max.)</string>
    <string name="a340_range_value">6,700 / 7,300 / 9,000 / 7,800 nmi</string>
    <string name="a340_thrust_value">138.78–151.24 kN\n(-200 &amp; -300) /\n248.12–275.35 kN\n(-500 &amp; -600)</string>
    <!--AIRBUS A340-->

    <!--AIRBUS A330-->
    <string name="a330_type_value">Wide-body</string>
    <string name="a330_engine_value">GE CF6 /\nPratt &amp; Whitney PW4000 /\nRR Trent 700 (2)</string>
    <string name="a330_first_flight_value">2 November 1992</string>
    <string name="a330_intro_value">17 January 1994\nwith Air Inter</string>
    <string name="a330_customer_value">Turkish Airlines</string>
    <string name="a330_variants_value">11 (active)</string>

    <string name="a330_desc1" formatted="false">Airbus began development on the A330 (now known as A330ceo - \"ceo\" for \"Current Engine Option\" - after the introduction of A330neo - \"neo\" for "New Engine Option" in 2014) twin-jet in parallel with the A340 quad-jet and launched both designs with their first
        orders in June 1987. The A330 shares its airframe with the early A340 variants, having two main landing gear legs instead of three, lower weights, and slightly
        different lengths. Both airliners have fly-by-wire controls as well as a similar glass cockpit to increase the commonality. The A330 was Airbus\'s first
        airliner to offer a choice of three engines: the General Electric CF6, Pratt &amp; Whitney PW4000, or the Rolls-Royce Trent 700. The A330 was the
        first Airbus aircraft for which Rolls-Royce supplied engines. It is the third most delivered wide-body airliner after the Boeing 777 and Boeing 747. As of 30 June 2021,
        1518 A330s have been built and this figure will continue to increase as the aircraft is still in production.\n\nThe A330 is a medium-size, wide-body aircraft,
        with two engines suspended on pylons under the wings. A two-wheel nose undercarriage and two four-wheel bogie main legs built by Messier-Dowty support the
        aeroplane on the ground. The airframe of the A330 features a low-wing lever monoplane with a wing virtually identical to that of the A340-200/300. On the
        A330-300, one engine is installed at the inboard pylon while the outboard pylon position is not used; for the A340-300, both engine pylons are used, which
        allows the A340-300 wing to sustain a higher (wing limited) MTOW. This is as the A340\'s two engines at each wing provide a more equal force distribution
        (engine weight) over the wing, while also the total engine weight counteracting moment is located more outboard with more engine weight located further
        outboard on the wing, hence the wing root bending moment with equal TOW is less on the A340-300 than on the A330-300. The wings were designed and manufactured
        by BAe, which developed a long slender wing with a very high aspect ratio to provide high aerodynamic efficiency. The wing is swept back at 30 degrees and,
        along with other design features, allows a maximum operating Mach number of 0.86.\n</string>

    <string name="a330_desc2" formatted="false">The A330 and A340 fuselage is based on that of the Airbus A300-600, with many common parts, and has the same external
        and cabin width: 5.64 m and 5.26 m. Typical seating arrangements are 2–2–2 six-abreast in business class and 2–4–2 eight-abreast in economy class. The fin, rudder,
        elevators, horizontal tail plane are used as fuel tank, flaps, ailerons and spoilers; they are made of composite materials, making 10% of the structure weight.
        When necessary, the A330 uses the Honeywell 331–350C auxiliary power unit (APU) to provide pneumatics and electrical power.\n\nThe A330 shares the same glass
        cockpit flight deck layout as the A320 and the A340, featuring electronic instrument
        displays rather than mechanical gauges. Instead of a conventional control yoke, the flight deck features side-stick controls, six main displays, and the
        Electronic Flight Instrument System (EFIS), which covers navigation and flight displays, as well as the Electronic Centralised Aircraft Monitor (ECAM).
        Apart from the flight deck, the A330 also has the fly-by-wire system common to the A320 family, the A340, the A350, and the A380. It also features three
        primary and two secondary flight control systems, as well as a flight envelope limit protection system which prevents maneuvers from exceeding the aircraft\'s
        aerodynamic and structural limits.\n</string>


    <string name="a330_desc3">\nAirbus A330\'s variants include A330-300, A330-300HGW, A330 Regional, A330-200, A330-200F, A330P2F, A330neo equipped with new engines, Beluga XL (large cargo freighter), ACJ330 (corporate jet),
        Airbus A330 MRTT and EADS/Northrop Grumman KC-45 (military jets). Many other variants
    such as A330-400/600, A330-100/-500, A330-200Lite were proposed. However, in the end these variants did not make it into the production phase.\n</string>

    <string name="a330_specs_constraint">(-200, -200F, and -300 variants compared in order)\n</string>


    <string name="a330_identify">How to identify Airbus A330?</string>
    <string name="a330_identify_ans">Bulged central section of the lower fuselage, 2 engines attached to wings with straight, sharp-angled, short wingtips like A340\'s.</string>

    <string name="a330_cockpit_value">2</string>
    <string name="a330_wingspan_value">60.3 m</string>
    <string name="a330_length_value">58.82 m (-200 &amp; -200F) / 63.67 m (-300)</string>
    <string name="a330_height_value">17.39 / 16.9 / 16.79 m</string>
    <string name="a330_fuselage_value">5.64 m (W) / 5.64 m (H)</string>
    <string name="a330_mtow_value">242 / 233 / 242 t</string>
    <string name="a330_cruise_speed_value">871 km/h (typical)</string>
    <string name="a330_range_value">7,250 / 4,000 / 6,350 nmi</string>
    <string name="a330_thrust_value">287–316 kN</string>
    <!--AIRBUS A330-->


    <!--AIRBUS A330neo-->
    <string name="a330neo_type_value">Wide-body</string>
    <string name="a330neo_engine_value">Rolls-Royce Trent 7000</string>
    <string name="a330neo_first_flight_value">19 October 2017</string>
    <string name="a330neo_intro_value">15 December 2018\nwith TAP Air Portugal</string>
    <string name="a330neo_customer_value">TAP Air Portugal</string>
    <string name="a330neo_variants_value">2</string>

    <string name="a330neo_desc1" formatted="false">The A330neo, \"neo\" for "New Engine Option", is a development comprising A330-800/900 from the initial A330 (-200/200F freighter/300/MRTT military tanker), now A330ceo — \"Current Engine Option\". A new
        version with modern engines developed for the Boeing 787 was called for by owners of the current A330. It was launched in July 2014 at the Farnborough Airshow,
        promising 14% better fuel economy per seat, thanks to Airbus\' decision that lead to the aircraft being exclusively powered by the Rolls-Royce Trent 7000 (as opposed to Trent 700 of A330ceo) with double bypass ratio, as opposed to its predecessor and other aerodynamic improvements including
        A350 inspired sharklets. Its two versions are based on the A330-200 and -300: Its two versions are based on the A330-200 and -300: the -800 has a range of 8,150 nmi
        (15,090 km) with 257 passengers while the -900 covers 7,200 nmi (13,330 km) with 287 passengers. The -900 made its maiden flight on 19 October 2017 and received its EASA type certificate on 26 September 2018; it was first delivered to TAP
        Air Portugal on 26 November 2018 and entered service on 15 December. The -800 made its first flight on 6 November 2018 and received EASA type certification on 13
        February 2020; the first two -800s were delivered to Kuwait Airways on 29 October 2020. As of 30 June 2021, 63 A330neos have been built.\n</string>

    <string name="a330neo_desc2" formatted="false">The larger 112-inch Trent 7000 is 11% more efficient than the 97.5-inch Trent 700 engine, with a 2% loss due to
        increased weight and 1% due to additional drag from the larger engine, but the sharklets and aero optimization regains 4% for a 12% fuel advantage per trip.
        Furthermore, fuel consumption per seat is improved by 2% due to the rearranged cabin (Space-Flex and Smart-Lav) with increased seating, offering a 14% fuel
        burn reduction per seat for the new −900 compared to the previous 235-tonne −300 version.\n\nThe A330neo offers a distinctive cockpit windscreen, similar to that on the A350, and a new interior concept focusing on
        better passenger experience. Since the fan is enlarged from 97 to 112 in (250 to 280 cm), the nacelles are mounted higher, necessitating extensive
        CFD analysis to avoid supersonic shock wave interference drag, as is the first slat\'s dog-tooth. The wing twist and belly fairings are tweaked to
        approach the lowest drag elliptical span-wise pressure distribution changed by the larger sharklets, like the flap track fairings shape to lower form drag.\n\nAs
        far the as the engine is concerned, the Rolls-Royce Trent 7000 is an electronic controlled bleed air variant of the Trent
        1000 used on the Boeing 787-10. It has a 112 inch (284 cm) diameter fan and a 10:1 bypass ratio delivering a thrust of 68,000 to 72,000 pounds-force
        (300 to 320 kN). The decision to offer the aircraft with only one engine option is not unique to Airbus; the Boeing 777X is also expected to come equipped
        exclusively with General Electric GE9X engines.
        \n</string>


    <string name="a330neo_desc3">\nThe A330neo is comprised of 2 variants, the A330-800 and the A330-900.\n</string>

    <string name="a330neo_specs_constraint">(-800 and -900 variants compared in order)\n</string>


    <string name="a330neo_identify">How to identify Airbus A330neo?</string>
    <string name="a330neo_identify_ans">The A330neo has a different 6-piece window design, with black border (\‘raccoon\’ style) and has bulged central section of the lower fuselage. It
        also has smoothly curved wing-tips, often referred to as sharklets, similar to those on the A350 but with less curvature.</string>

    <string name="a330neo_cockpit_value">2</string>
    <string name="a330neo_wingspan_value">64 m</string>
    <string name="a330neo_length_value">58.82 / 63.66 m</string>
    <string name="a330neo_height_value">17.39 / 16.79 m</string>
    <string name="a330neo_fuselage_value">5.64 m (W) / ~5.7 m (H)</string>
    <string name="a330neo_mtow_value">251 t</string>
    <string name="a330neo_cruise_speed_value">918 km/h (max.)</string>
    <string name="a330neo_range_value">8,150 / 7,200 nmi</string>
    <string name="a330neo_thrust_value">324 kN</string>
    <!--AIRBUS A330neo-->


    <!--AIRBUS A321-->
    <string name="a321_type_value">Narrow-body</string>
    <string name="a321_engine_value">CFM56 /\nIAE V2500</string>
    <string name="a321_first_flight_value">11 March 1993</string>
    <string name="a321_intro_value">1994 with\nLufthansa</string>
    <string name="a321_customer_value">American Airlines</string>
    <string name="a321_variants_value">3</string>

    <string name="a321_desc1" formatted="false">The Airbus A321 is a member of the Airbus A320 family of short to medium range, narrow-body, commercial passenger
        twin engine jet airliners. This Airbus A320 family was renamed to A320ceo, for \"current engine option\" after the introduction of A320neo (neo for new engine option) in 2014. It has a stretched fuselage which was the first derivative of the baseline A320 and entered service in 1994 about six years after
        the original A320. The aircraft shares a common type rating with all other Airbus A320-family variants, allowing previous A320-family pilots to fly the aircraft
        without the need for further training. As of 30 June 2021, 2,340 A321s have been built.\n\nThe Airbus A321 was the first derivative of the A320, also known
        as the Stretched A320, A320-500 and A325. Its launch came on 24 November 1988, around the same time as the A320 entered service, after commitments for 183
        aircraft from 10 customers were secured. The maiden flight of the Airbus A321 came on 11 March 1993, when the prototype, registration F-WWIA, flew with IAE
        V2500 engines; the second prototype, equipped with CFM56-5B turbofans, flew in May 1993. Lufthansa and Alitalia were the first to order the stretched
        Airbuses, with 20 and 40 aircraft requested, respectively. The first of Lufthansa\'s V2500-A5-powered A321s arrived on 27 January 1994, while Alitalia
        received its first CFM56-5B-powered aircraft on 22 March 1994. The A321-100 entered service in January 1994 with Lufthansa.\n</string>

    <string name="a321_desc2" formatted="false">The A321 is the largest variant of the A320 family. The A321-200\'s length exceeds 44.5m, increasing maximum takeoff
        weight to 93,000 kg (205,000 lb). Wingspan remained unchanged, supplementing various wingtip devices. Two suppliers provided turbofan engines for the A321:
        CFM International with its CFM56 and International Aero Engines with the V2500 engine, both in the thrust range of 133–147 kN (30,000–33,000 lbf). Over 30
        years since launch, the A321 Maximum takeoff weight (MTOW) grew by 20% from the 83t -100 until the 101t A321XLR, seating is 10% more dense with 244 seats,
        up by 24, and range doubled from 2,300 nmi to 4,700 nmi. By 2019, 4,200 have been ordered—one-quarter of all Airbus single-aisles—including 2,400 neos,
        one-third of all A320neo orders.\n\nThe narrow-body (single-aisle) aircraft from Airbus is a low-wing cantilever monoplane with a conventional tail unit having a single vertical stabilizer and rudder.
        Changes from the A320 include a fuselage stretch and some modifications to the wing. The fuselage was lengthened by a 4.27 m plug ahead of the wing and a
        2.67 m plug behind it, so that the A321 is 6.94 metres longer than the A320. The length increase required the overwing window exits of the A320 to be
        converted into door exits and repositioned in front of and behind the wings. To maintain performance, double-slotted flaps and minor trailing edge
        modifications were included, increasing the wing area from 124 m<sup><small><small>2</small></small></sup> (1,330 sq ft) to 128 m<sup><small><small>2</small></small></sup> (1,380 sq ft). The centre fuselage and undercarriage were
        reinforced to accommodate the increase in maximum takeoff weight of 9,600 kg (21,200 lb), taking it to 83,000 kg (183,000 lb).\n</string>


    <string name="a321_desc3">\nAirbus A321 variants include A321-100, A321-200 and A321neo equipped with new engines.\n</string>

    <string name="a321_specs_constraint">(-100 and -200 variants compared in order)\n</string>


    <string name="a321_identify">How to identify Airbus A321?</string>
    <string name="a321_identify_ans">\"Notched\" window design, \"bulbous\" nose, 2 dual-wheel main landing gears, engine nacelle with no trailing extensions,
        4 exits spread evenly across the fuselage, and either small triangular wingtips (wingtip fence) similar to those on A380 or large L-shaped sharklets.</string>

    <string name="a321_cockpit_value">2</string>
    <string name="a321_wingspan_value">35.80 m</string>
    <string name="a321_length_value">44.51 m</string>
    <string name="a321_height_value">11.76 m</string>
    <string name="a321_fuselage_value">3.95 m (W) / 4.14 m (H)</string>
    <string name="a321_mtow_value">83 / 93.5 t</string>
    <string name="a321_cruise_speed_value">829 km/h (typical),\n871 km/h (max.)</string>
    <string name="a321_range_value">2,350 / 3,200 nmi</string>
    <string name="a321_thrust_value">133–147 kN</string>
    <!--AIRBUS A321-->


    <!--AIRBUS A320-->
    <string name="a320_type_value">Narrow-body</string>
    <string name="a320_engine_value">CFM56 /\nIAE V2500</string>
    <string name="a320_first_flight_value">22 February 1987</string>
    <string name="a320_intro_value">18 April 1988\nwith Air France</string>
    <string name="a320_customer_value">China Eastern Airlines</string>
    <string name="a320_variants_value">2</string>

    <string name="a320_desc1" formatted="false">The Airbus A320 is a member of the Airbus A320 family of short to medium range, narrow-body, commercial passenger
        twin engine jet airliners. This Airbus A320 family was renamed to A320ceo, for \"current engine option\" after the introduction of A320neo (neo for new engine option) in 2014.
        It is a narrow-body (single-aisle) aircraft with a retractable tricycle landing gear and are powered by two wing pylon-mounted turbofan engines. After the oil
        price rises of the 1970s, Airbus needed to minimise the trip fuel costs of the A320. To that end, it adopted composite primary structures, centre-of-gravity
        control using fuel, glass cockpit (EFIS) and a two-crew flight deck. Airbus claimed the 737-300 burns 35% more fuel and has a 16% higher operating cost per
        seat than the V2500-powered A320. A 150-seat A320 burns 11,608 kg (25,591 lb) of jet fuel over 3,984 km (2,151 nmi) (between Los Angeles and New York City),
        or 2.43 L/100 km (97 mpg‑US) per seat with a 0.8 kg/L fuel. Its wing is long and thin, offering better aerodynamic efficiency because of the higher aspect
        ratio than the competing 737 and MD-80.\n\nThe A320 is a low-wing cantilever monoplane with a conventional empennage with a single vertical stabilizer and
        rudder. Its wing sweep is 25 degrees. Compared to other airliners of the same class, the A320 features a wider single-aisle cabin of 3.95 metres (156 in)
        outside diameter, compared to 3.8 m (148 in) of the Boeing 737 or 757, and larger overhead bins. The A320 airframe includes composite materials and aluminium
        alloys to save weight and reduce the total number of parts to decrease the maintenance costs. Its tail assembly is made almost entirely of such composites by
        CASA, who also builds the elevators, main landing gear doors, and rear fuselage parts. \n</string>

    <string name="a320_desc2" formatted="false">It includes a full glass cockpit rather than the hybrid versions found in previous airliners. The A320\'s flight deck
        is equipped with Electronic Flight Instrument System (EFIS) with side-stick controllers. The A320 features an Electronic Centralised Aircraft Monitor (ECAM)
        which gives the flight crew information about all the systems of the aircraft. The only analogue instruments were the radio-magnetic indicator and brake
        pressure indicator. Since 2003, the A320 features liquid crystal display (LCD) units in its flight deck instead of the original cathode ray tube (CRT)
        displays. These include the main displays and the backup artificial horizon, which was previously an analog display. Airbus offers an avionics upgrade for
        older A320 aircraft, the In-Service Enhancement Package, to keep them updated.\n\nThe A320 is the world\'s first airliner with digital fly-by-wire (FBW)
        flight control system: input commands through the side-stick are interpreted by flight control computers and transmitted to flight control surfaces within
        the flight envelope protection; in the 1980s the computer-controlled dynamic system of the Dassault Mirage 2000 fighter cross-fertilised the Airbus team
        which tested FBW on an A300. At its introduction, fly-by-wire and flight envelope protection was a new experience for many pilots.\n</string>

    <string name="a320_desc3">\nThe A320 series has two variants, the A320-100 and A320-200. Only 21 A320-100s were produced. The primary changes of the -200 over the
        -100 are wingtip fences and increased fuel capacity for increased range.\n</string>

    <string name="a320_specs_constraint">()\n</string>


    <string name="a320_identify">How to identify Airbus A320?</string>
    <string name="a320_identify_ans">\"Notched\" window design, \"bulbous\" nose, 2 dual-wheel main landing gears, engine nacelle with no trailing extensions,
        4 exits - 2 over the wing and 2 near either ends of the fuselage, and either small triangular wingtips (wingtip fence) similar to those on A380 or large L-shaped sharklets.</string>

    <string name="a320_cockpit_value">2</string>
    <string name="a320_wingspan_value">35.80 m</string>
    <string name="a320_length_value">37.57 m</string>
    <string name="a320_height_value">11.76 m</string>
    <string name="a320_fuselage_value">3.95 m (W) / 4.14 m (H)</string>
    <string name="a320_mtow_value">78 t</string>
    <string name="a320_cruise_speed_value">829 km/h (typical),\n871 km/h (max.)</string>
    <string name="a320_range_value">3,300 nmi</string>
    <string name="a320_thrust_value">98–120 kN</string>
    <!--AIRBUS A320-->


    <!--AIRBUS A319-->
    <string name="a319_type_value">Narrow-body</string>
    <string name="a319_engine_value">CFM56 /\nIAE V2500</string>
    <string name="a319_first_flight_value">25 August 1995</string>
    <string name="a319_intro_value">1996 with\nSwissair</string>
    <string name="a319_customer_value">American Airlines</string>
    <string name="a319_variants_value">4</string>

    <string name="a319_desc1" formatted="false">The Airbus A319 is a member of the Airbus A320 family of short- to medium-range, narrow-body, commercial
        passenger twin-engine jet airliners. This Airbus A320 family was renamed to A320ceo, for \"current engine option\" after the introduction of A320neo
        (neo for new engine option) in 2014. It is a shortened-fuselage variant of the Airbus A320 and entered service in April 1996 with Swissair, around
        two years after the stretched Airbus A321 and eight years after the original A320. The aircraft shares a common type rating with all other Airbus A320
        family variants, allowing existing A320 family pilots to fly the aircraft without the need for further training. As of August 2019, a total of 1,480
        Airbus A319 aircraft have been delivered, of which 1,436 are in service.\n\nThe first member of the A320 family was the A320 which was launched in March
        1984 and first flew on 22 February 1987. The family was extended to include the stretched A321 (first delivered 1994), the shortened A319 (1996), and
        the further shortened A318 (2003). The A320 family pioneered the use of digital fly-by-wire flight control systems, as well as side stick controls,
        in commercial aircraft. The A319 was developed at the request of Steven Udvar-Hazy, the former president and CEO of ILFC according to The New York Times.\n</string>

    <string name="a319_desc2" formatted="false">The A319 design is a shortened fuselage, minimum change derivative of the A320 with its origins in the 130- to 140-seat
        SA1, part of the Single-Aisle studies. The SA1 was shelved as the consortium concentrated on its bigger siblings. After healthy sales of the A320/A321,
        Airbus re-focused on what was then known as the A320M-7, meaning A320 minus seven fuselage frames. It would provide direct competition for the 737-300/-700.
        The shrink was achieved through the removal of four fuselage frames fore and three aft the wing, cutting the overall length by 3.73 metres (12 ft 3 in).
        Consequently, the number of overwing exits was reduced from four to two.\n\nHigh-density A319s, such as 156-seat aircraft used by easyJet, retain four overwing exits. The bulk-cargo door was replaced by an aft container door, which
        can take in reduced height LD3-45 containers. Minor software changes were made to accommodate the different handling characteristics; otherwise the aircraft
        is largely unchanged. Power is provided by the CFM56-5A or V2500-A5, derated to 98 kN (22,000 lbf), with option for 105 kN (24,000 lbf) thrust. With virtually
        the same fuel capacity as the A320-200 and fewer passengers, the range with 124 passengers in a two-class configuration extends to 6,650 km (3,590 nmi), or
        6,850 km (3,700 nmi) with the \"Sharklets\". The A319\'s wingspan is wider than the aircraft\'s overall length.\n</string>

    <string name="a319_desc3">\nThe A319 variants include the corporate jet version A319CJ (rebranded ACJ319), A319neo equipped with new engines,
        A319 MPA (Maritime Patrol Aircraft) - military derivative of the A319, and A319LR - the longer-range version of the A319.\n</string>

    <string name="a319_specs_constraint">()\n</string>


    <string name="a319_identify">How to identify Airbus A319?</string>
    <string name="a319_identify_ans">\"Notched\" window design, \"bulbous\" nose, 2 dual-wheel main landing gears, engine nacelle with no trailing extensions,
        3 exits - 1 over the wing and 2 near either ends of the fuselage, and either small triangular wingtips (wingtip fence) similar to those on A380 or large L-shaped sharklets.</string>

    <string name="a319_cockpit_value">2</string>
    <string name="a319_wingspan_value">35.80 m</string>
    <string name="a319_length_value">33.84 m</string>
    <string name="a319_height_value">11.76 m</string>
    <string name="a319_fuselage_value">3.95 m (W) / 4.14 m (H)</string>
    <string name="a319_mtow_value">75.5 t</string>
    <string name="a319_cruise_speed_value">829 km/h (typical),\n871 km/h (max.)</string>
    <string name="a319_range_value">3,750 nmi</string>
    <string name="a319_thrust_value">98–120 kN</string>
    <!--AIRBUS A319-->


    <!--AIRBUS A318-->
    <string name="a318_type_value">Narrow-body</string>
    <string name="a318_engine_value">CFM56 /\nP&amp;W PW6000</string>
    <string name="a318_first_flight_value">15 January 2002</string>
    <string name="a318_intro_value">2003 with\nFrontier Airlines</string>
    <string name="a318_customer_value">Air France</string>
    <string name="a318_variants_value">1</string>

    <string name="a318_desc1" formatted="false">The Airbus A318 is the smallest and least numerous variant airliner of the Airbus A320 family. The A318 carries
        107 to 132 passengers and has a maximum range of 5,700 km (3,100 nmi). It is intended primarily for short-range service. The aircraft shares a common type rating
        with all other Airbus A320 family variants, allowing existing A320 family pilots to fly the aircraft without the need for further training. It is the largest
        commercial aircraft certified by the European Aviation Safety Agency for steep approach operations, allowing flights at airports such as London City. A total of 80
        A318s were been built during its production phase from 2001 to 2013.\n\nDuring the design process, the A318 encountered several problems. The first one was the
        decline in demand for new aircraft following the September 11 attacks.
        Another was the new Pratt &amp; Whitney turbofan engines, which burned more fuel than expected. By the time CFM International (CFM) had a more efficient engine
        ready for market, many A318 customers had already backed out, including Air China and British Airways. America West Airlines, which had selected the Pratt &amp;
        Whitney engines, amended its A318 orders, opting instead for A319 or A320 aircraft. Trans World Airlines cancelled a significant order for fifty A318s after being
        acquired by American Airlines, which did not operate any A320 family aircraft at the time (although neither did TWA when the order was originally placed).
        While Airbus was hoping to market the A318 as a regional jet alternative, laws in both the U.S. and Europe have kept it in the same class as larger aircraft
        for calculating charges such as landing fees, limiting the type\'s market potential.\n</string>

    <string name="a318_desc2" formatted="false">Orders for the A318 have been relatively slow, but slightly better than for its direct competitor the Boeing 737-600. By
        30 September 2017, Airbus had received 80 orders for this model compared to 69 for the 737-600. The sales pace has been influenced by the strong sales of
        the Bombardier CRJ900 and Embraer E-Jets series.\n\nThe narrow-body (single-aisle) aircraft is a low-wing cantilever monoplane with a conventional tail unit
        having a single vertical stabilizer and rudder. Overall, the A318 is over six metres shorter and around 3 t (6,600 lb) lighter than the A320. To compensate
        for the reduced moment arm, it has a larger vertical stabiliser. While initial concepts depicted the aircraft with a Boeing 737-300-style dorsal fin extension,
        the final design incorporated a fin tip extension, making it 75 centimetres (30 in) taller than the other A320 variants. Pilots who are trained on the other
        variants may fly the A318 with no further certification, since it features a common flight deck and the same type rating as its sister aircraft.\n\nIn March 2006, the European Aviation Safety Agency (EASA) certified a modified control software enhancement to the Airbus A318 designed to allow the aircraft
        to perform steep approaches. The aircraft is the largest commercial aircraft certified by EASA for steep approach operations. The software modifies the
        control laws of the aircraft when the steep approach function is selected by the crew, by automatically deploying some of the spoiler panels to provide
        additional drag when the aircraft is in the landing configuration. It also provides alternative aural alerts to the crew and modifies spoiler deployment
        automatically below 120 feet (37 m) on landing. The A318 steep approach procedure allows the aircraft to perform approaches at descent angles of up to
        5.5°, as opposed to the standard 3° for a normal approach.\n</string>

    <string name="a318_desc3">\nThe A318 comes in only one variant, A318-100. Unlike the other aircraft in the family (A319, A320, A321), A318 does not
        have A318neo variant. Thus, it is not included in the Airbus A320neo family.\n</string>

    <string name="a318_specs_constraint">()\n</string>


    <string name="a318_identify">How to identify Airbus A318?</string>
    <string name="a318_identify_ans">Stubby, tall tail, \"notched\" window design, \"bulbous\" nose, 2 dual-wheel main landing gears, engine nacelle with no trailing extensions,
        3 exits - 1 over the wing and 2 near either ends of the fuselage, 11 windows between fore cabin door and emergency exit over the wing, and small triangular wingtips (wingtip fence) similar to those on A380.</string>

    <string name="a318_cockpit_value">2</string>
    <string name="a318_wingspan_value">34.10 m</string>
    <string name="a318_length_value">31.44 m</string>
    <string name="a318_height_value">12.56 m</string>
    <string name="a318_fuselage_value">3.95 m (W) / 4.14 m (H)</string>
    <string name="a318_mtow_value">68 t</string>
    <string name="a318_cruise_speed_value">829 km/h (typical),\n871 km/h (max.)</string>
    <string name="a318_range_value">3,100 nmi</string>
    <string name="a318_thrust_value">96–106 kN</string>
    <!--AIRBUS A318-->

    <!--AIRBUS A310-->
    <string name="a310_type_value">Wide-body</string>
    <string name="a310_engine_value">GE CF6 /\nP&amp;W JT9D / PW4000</string>
    <string name="a310_first_flight_value">3 April 1982</string>
    <string name="a310_intro_value">April 1983\nwith Swissair</string>
    <string name="a310_customer_value">FedEx Express</string>
    <string name="a310_variants_value">4</string>

    <string name="a310_desc1" formatted="false">Airbus had demand for an aircraft smaller than the A300, the first twin-jet wide-body. On 7 July 1978, the A310
        (initially the A300B10) was launched with orders from Swissair and Lufthansa. On 3 April 1982, the first prototype conducted its maiden flight, and it
        received its type certification on 11 March 1983. Keeping the same eight-abreast cross-section, the A310 is 6.95 m (22.8 ft) shorter than the initial A300
        variants, and has a smaller wing, down from 260 to 219 m<sup><small><small>2</small></small></sup> (2,800 to 2,360 sq ft). The A310 introduced a two-crew glass cockpit, later adopted for the A300-600
        with a common type rating. It was powered by the same General Electric CF6-80 or Pratt &amp; Whitney JT9D then PW4000 turbofan jet engines. During its production phase
        from 1981 to 1998, a total of 255 A310s were built.\n\nIn April 1983, the aircraft entered revenue service with Swissair, and competed with the Boeing 767-200,
        introduced six months before. Its longer range and ETOPS regulations allowed it to be operated on transatlantic flights. Until the last delivery in June 1998,
        255 aircraft were produced, as it was succeeded by the larger Airbus A330-200. It was available as a cargo aircraft version, and was also developed into a
        military variant, the A310 MRTT multi-role transport, then tanker.\n</string>

    <string name="a310_desc2" formatted="false">The Airbus A310 was a medium- to long-range twin-engined wide-body jet airliner. Initially a derivative of the A300,
        the aircraft had originally been designated the A300B10. It was essentially a shortened variant of the A300; however, there were considerable differences
        between the two aircraft. Specifically, the fuselage possessed the same cross-section, but being shorter than the A300, it provided capacity for a typical
        maximum of 200 passengers. The rear fuselage was heavily re-designed, featuring altered tapering, while involved a move aft of the rear bulkhead to create
        additional capacity; this same design change was later transferred back to later variants of the A300, such as the A300-600 and A330/A340 fuselages.\n\nThe
        wing of the A310 was redesigned, possessing a reduced span and wing area, and incorporating simpler single-slotted Fowler flaps designed by British Aerospace
        shortly following its decision to join the Airbus consortium. Other changes to the wing included the elimination of the outer ailerons, which were occasionally
        referred to by the manufacturer as being \"low speed ailerons\", and the addition of electrically actuated spoilers. The wing also featured common pylons,
        which were able to support all types of engines that were offered to customers to power the airliner. From 1985 onwards, later-built production A310s were
        equipped with wingtip fences for the purpose of reducing lift-induced drag. A limited number of alternations were also performed to the airliner\'s tail unit,
        such as the adoption of smaller horizontal tail surfaces. The A310 was furnished with a two-crew glass cockpit configuration as standard, removing the
        requirement for a flight engineer; Airbus referred to this concept as the Forward-Facing Crew Cockpit. The A310 was equipped with a modified undercarriage,
        derived from the A300; the landing gear were outfitted with carbon brakes, which were fitted as standard. The structure of the airliner featured a high
        level of composite materials throughout both primary and secondary structures, increased beyond that of the earlier A300. The A310 is outfitted with integrated
        drive electrical generators along with auxiliary power unit, which were improved versions of those used on the A300.\n</string>

    <string name="a310_desc3">\nThe A310 is available in two basic versions, the medium range −200 and the longer range −300. The first version of the aircraft to be
        developed was the −200, but this was later joined by the −300, which then became the standard production version of the aircraft. The short range −100 variant
        was never developed due to low demand. Other variants include A310 MRT/MRTT (Multi-Role Tanker Transport), A310 Zero G, the reduced-gravity aircraft used to
        realise parabolas, allowing performance of twenty-two seconds of weightlessness.\n</string>

    <string name="a310_specs_constraint">(-200 and -300 variants compared in order)\n</string>


    <string name="a310_identify">How to identify Airbus A310?</string>
    <string name="a310_identify_ans">Flat central section of the lower fuselage, \"notched\" window design, 3 exits - 1 overwing and 2 near either ends of the fuselage, with/without wingtip fences.</string>

    <string name="a310_cockpit_value">2</string>
    <string name="a310_wingspan_value">43.9 m</string>
    <string name="a310_length_value">46.66 m</string>
    <string name="a310_height_value">15.8 m</string>
    <string name="a310_fuselage_value">5.64 m (W) / ~6 m (H)</string>
    <string name="a310_mtow_value">144 / 164 t</string>
    <string name="a310_cruise_speed_value">850 km/h (typical),\n892 km/h (max.)</string>
    <string name="a310_range_value">3,500 / 5,150 nmi</string>
    <string name="a310_thrust_value">203.8–257.4 kN</string>
    <!--AIRBUS A310-->


    <!--AIRBUS A300-->
    <string name="a300_type_value">Wide-body</string>
    <string name="a300_engine_value">GE CF6 / P&amp;W JT9D (-B4-200),\nGE CF6 / P&amp;W PW4158 (-600R/F)</string>
    <string name="a300_first_flight_value">28 October 1972</string>
    <string name="a300_intro_value">23 May 1974 with Air France</string>
    <string name="a300_customer_value">FedEx Express</string>
    <string name="a300_variants_value">6</string>

    <string name="a300_desc1" formatted="false">The Airbus A300 is a wide-body airliner developed and manufactured by Airbus. In September 1967, aircraft manufacturers
        in the United Kingdom, France, and West Germany signed a memorandum of understanding to develop a large airliner. West Germany and France reached an agreement
        on 29 May 1969 after the British withdrew from the project on 10 April 1969. European collaborative aerospace manufacturer Airbus Industrie was formally created
        on 18 December 1970 to develop and produce it. The prototype first flew on 28 October 1972. During its production phase from 1971 to 2007, a total of 561 A300s were built.\n\nThe wide-body medium-to-long range airliner has the distinction of
        being the first twin-engine wide-body aircraft in the world. In 1977, the A300 became the first Extended Range Twin Operations
        (ETOPS)-compliant aircraft, due to its high performance and safety standards. Another world-first of the A300 is the use of composite materials on a
        commercial aircraft, which was used on both secondary and later primary airframe structures, decreasing overall weight and improving cost-effectiveness. Other
        firsts included the pioneering use of center-of-gravity control, achieved by transferring fuel between various locations across the aircraft, and electrically
        signaled secondary flight controls.\n\nThe A300 is powered by a pair of underwing turbofan engines, either General Electric CF6 or Pratt &amp; Whitney JT9D
        engines; the sole use of underwing engine pods allowed for any suitable turbofan engine to be more readily used. The lack of a third tail-mounted engine,
        as per the trijet configuration used by some competing airliners, allowed for the wings to be located further forwards and to reduce the size of the vertical
        stabilizer and elevator, which had the effect of increasing the aircraft\'s flight performance and fuel efficiency. Airbus partners had employed the latest
        technology, some of which having been derived from Concorde, on the A300. According to Airbus, new technologies adopted for the airliner were selected
        principally for increased safety, operational capability, and profitability.\n\nUpon entry into service in 1974, the A300 was a very advanced plane, which
        went on to influence later airliner designs. The technological highlights include advanced wings by de Havilland (later BAE Systems) with supercritical airfoil
        sections for economical performance and advanced aerodynamically efficient flight control surfaces. The 5.64 m (222 in) diameter circular fuselage section allows
        an eight-abreast passenger seating and is wide enough for 2 LD3 cargo containers side by side. Structures are made from metal billets, reducing weight. It is
        the first airliner to be fitted with wind shear protection. Its advanced autopilots are capable of flying the aircraft from climb-out to landing, and it has an
        electrically controlled braking system.\n</string>

    <string name="a300_desc2" formatted="false">Later A300s incorporated other advanced features such as the Forward-Facing Crew Cockpit, which enabled a
        two-pilot flight crew to fly the aircraft alone without the need for a flight engineer, the functions of which were automated; this two-man cockpit concept
        was a world-first for a wide-body aircraft. Glass cockpit flight instrumentation, which used cathode ray tube (CRT) monitors to display flight, navigation,
        and warning information, along with fully digital dual autopilots and digital flight control computers for controlling the spoilers, flaps, and leading-edge
        slats, were also adopted upon later-built models. Additional composites were also made use of, such as carbon-fiber-reinforced polymer (CFRP), as well
        as their presence in an increasing proportion of the aircraft\'s components, including the spoilers, rudder, air brakes, and landing gear doors.\n\nAnother
        feature of later aircraft were the addition of wingtip fences, which generated greater aerodynamic performance (first introduced on the A310-300). In addition
        to passenger duties, the A300 became widely used by air freight operators; according to Airbus, it is the best selling freight aircraft of all time. Various
        variants of the A300 were built to meet customer demands, often for diverse roles such as aerial refueling tankers, freighter models (new-build and
        conversions), combi aircraft, military airlifter, and VIP transport. Perhaps the most visually unique of the variants is the A300-600ST Beluga, an oversize
        cargo-carrying model operated by Airbus to carry aircraft sections between their manufacturing facilities. The A300 was the basis for, and retained a high
        level of commonality with, the second airliner produced by Airbus, the smaller Airbus A310.\n</string>

    <string name="a300_desc3">\nAirbus A300 variants include A300B1, A300B2, A300B4, A300-600, A300B10 (A310), A300-600ST (often referred to as Airbus Beluga
        or Airbus Super Transporter)\n</string>

    <string name="a300_specs_constraint">(-B4-200, -600R, and -600F variants compared in order)\n</string>


    <string name="a300_identify">How to identify Airbus A300?</string>
    <string name="a300_identify_ans"></string>

    <string name="a300_cockpit_value">3 / 2 / 2</string>
    <string name="a300_wingspan_value">44.84 m</string>
    <string name="a300_length_value">53.61 m (-B4-200) /\n54.1 m (-600R / -600F)</string>
    <string name="a300_height_value">16.72 m (-B4-200) /\n16.66 m (-600R / -600F)</string>
    <string name="a300_fuselage_value">5.64 m (W) / ~6 m (H)</string>
    <string name="a300_mtow_value">165 / 171.7 / 170.5 t</string>
    <string name="a300_cruise_speed_value">833 km/h (typical),\n871 km/h (max.)</string>
    <string name="a300_range_value">2,900 nmi (-B4-200) /\n4,050 m (-600R / -600F)</string>
    <string name="a300_thrust_value">230 kN(-B4-200) /\n249–270 kN (-600R / -600F)</string>
    <!--AIRBUS A300-->


    <!--AIRBUS A220-->
    <string name="a220_type_value">Narrow-body</string>
    <string name="a220_engine_value">Pratt &amp; Whitney\nPW1500G</string>
    <string name="a220_first_flight_value">16 September 2013</string>
    <string name="a220_intro_value">15 July 2016 with\nSwiss International Air Lines</string>
    <string name="a220_customer_value">Delta Air Lines</string>
    <string name="a220_variants_value">3</string>

    <string name="a220_desc1" formatted="false">The Airbus A220 is a family of narrow-body airliner designed by Bombardier Aerospace as the Bombardier CSeries. In
        July 2018, the aircraft was rebranded as the A220 after Airbus acquired 50.01% of the program through a joint venture with Bombardier, which was later renamed Airbus Canada
        Limited Partnership. The Bombardier CSeries was meant to be a game-changing aircraft. Produced by the Canadian aircraft manufacturer Bombardier, it was its first foray in
        the 100-to-150-seat market. Though initially successful with sales to major airlines, the program was turned upside following a trade dispute with Boeing. The
        aircraft program was taken over by Airbus as a result, with the aircraft renamed. Bombardier pulled out of the venture entirely, leaving it
        to Airbus. Thus, in February 2020, Airbus increased its share to 75%, while the provincial government\'s Investissement Québec held the 25% balance. Powered by Pratt
        &amp; Whitney PW1500G geared turbofans, the twinjet has fly-by-wire flight controls, a carbon composite wing and an aluminium-lithium fuselage. Early operators,
        Swiss and airBaltic, recorded better-than-expected fuel burn and dispatch reliability, as well as positive feedback from passengers and crew. Delta Air Lines is
        currently the largest operator with 50 airplanes in its fleet. As of June 2021, a total of 648 aircraft had been ordered of which 164 had been delivered. The
        A220 family complements the A319neo in the Airbus range and competes with the largest variants of the Embraer E-Jet E2 family and the smaller Boeing 737 MAX-7
        variant. As of 30 June 2021, a total of 164 A220s have been built.\n\nThe Airbus A220 family of narrow-body aircraft was originally designed by Bombardier
        under the CSeries programme. The high efficient engines and extensive use of composite materials, like the wide-body Boeing 787 Dreamliner and Airbus A350 XWB,
        contribute together to the 12–15% better cash operating costs. Bombardier claimed at the time that the engine and the wings would save up to 20% fuel,
        a 25% reduction in maintenance costs and four-fold reduction in the noise footprint compared with the Airbus A320neo and the Boeing 737NG with which it competed.
        The larger CS300 (now A220-300), was 6 tonnes lighter than the Airbus A319neo and nearly 8 tons lighter than the Boeing 737 MAX 7, helping it to achieve up
        to 12% operating costs savings and 15% with the current models. The cabin cross section of the aircraft family was designed to give enhanced seating comfort
        for passengers, with features like broader seats and armrests for the middle passenger and larger windows at every seat to give every passenger the physical
        and psychological advantages of ample natural light. The cabin featured large, rotating overhead storage bins, allowing each passenger to stow a sizeable
        carry-on bag overhead. Bombardier claimed that compared to the cabins of current in-service narrow-body aircraft, the aircraft family would provide airlines
        with the highest overhead bin volume per passenger and a wider aisle that allows for faster boarding and disembarkation of passengers.\n</string>

    <string name="a220_desc2" formatted="false">The cockpit features the Rockwell Collins Pro Line Fusion avionics suite, which incorporates 15 in (380 mm) displays
        along with comprehensive navigation, communications, surveillance, engine-indicating and crew-alerting system (EICAS), and aircraft maintenance systems.
        Other elements of the avionics and other subsystems include Parker Hannifin\'s flight control, fuel and hydraulics systems; Liebherr Aerospace\'s air
        management system; and United Technologies Corporation\'s air data system, flap and slat actuation systems. The centre fuselage of the A220-300 is 3.4
        meter longer than the -100 and structurally reinforced for higher loads. The fuselage and many components incorporate a high proportion of composite
        materials. The overall aircraft consists of 70% advanced lightweight materials, comprising 46% composite materials and 24% aluminium–lithium. Bombardier
        has claimed that the type can achieve an overall 15% lower seat-mile cost, 20% lower fuel burn and a CO<sub><small><small>2</small></small></sub> emissions advantage.
        The new Pratt &amp; Whitney PW1000G engine yields 12% better fuel economy than existing jets while being quieter, with further efficiency stemming from
        enhanced aerodynamics and advanced lightweight materials.\n\nThe composite wings were manufactured and assembled at a purpose built factory at the Bombardier Aerostructures
        and Engineering Services (BAES) site in Belfast, Northern Ireland. Meanwhile, the aft fuselage and cockpit were built in Bombardier\'s Manufacturing Centre in
        Saint-Laurent, Quebec, with final assembly occurring at Mirabel, Quebec. While several major elements of the aircraft, such as the centre wing box and doors,
        were manufactured internally, many other components have been contracted out, namely: Liebherr for the landing gear and pneumatics; UTC Aerospace for the
        electrical system and lighting; Goodrich for the nacelle; Meggitt for the wheels and brakes, Michelin for the tires; Spirit for the pylons; Honeywell
        for the APU; and PPG supplies the windows. In 2010, Ghafari Associates was retained to develop the Montreal manufacturing site to accommodate the aircraft production.\n</string>

    <string name="a220_desc3">\nAirbus A220 variants include A220-100, A220-300, and ACJ TwoTwenty business jet. Their commonality over 99% allows a common spare part
        inventory, reducing investment and maintenance costs.\n</string>

    <string name="a220_specs_constraint">(-100 and -300 variants compared in order)\n</string>


    <string name="a220_identify">How to identify Airbus A220?</string>
    <string name="a220_identify_ans"></string>

    <string name="a220_cockpit_value">2</string>
    <string name="a220_wingspan_value">35.10 m</string>
    <string name="a220_length_value">35.0 / 38.70 m</string>
    <string name="a220_height_value">11.50 m</string>
    <string name="a220_fuselage_value">3.5 m (W) / ~3.7 m (H)</string>
    <string name="a220_mtow_value">63.1 / 70.9 t</string>
    <string name="a220_cruise_speed_value">829 km/h (typical),\n871 km/h (max.)</string>
    <string name="a220_range_value">3,450 / 3,600 nmi</string>
    <string name="a220_thrust_value">84.1–103.6 kN /\n93.4–103.6 kN</string>
    <!--AIRBUS A220-->


    <!--AIRBUS BELUGA-->
    <string name="beluga_type_value">Outsize cargo freight</string>
    <string name="beluga_engine_value">General Electric CF6</string>
    <string name="beluga_first_flight_value">13 September 1994</string>
    <string name="beluga_intro_value">September 1995</string>
    <string name="beluga_variants_value">1</string>

    <string name="beluga_desc1" formatted="false">The Airbus A300-600ST (Super Transporter), or Beluga, is a version of the standard A300-600 wide-body airliner
        modified to carry aircraft parts and outsize cargo. It received the official name of Super Transporter early on; however, the name Beluga, a whale it
        resembles, gained popularity and has since been officially adopted. During its production phase from 1992 to 1998, only 5 Belugas were built in order to meet demands for transportation. Several major aircraft manufacturers are multinational, and it is not unusual for them to
        have plants in widely separated locations. Airbus is unique in that although it is today a standalone multinational corporation, it was originally a consortium
        formed by the major British, French, German, and Spanish aerospace companies. The geographic location of Airbus manufacturing is not only influenced by cost
        and convenience; it is also a matter of aviation history and national interest.\n\nHistorically, each of the Airbus partners makes an entire aircraft section,
        which would then be transported to a central location for final assembly; even after the integration of Airbus into a single firm, the arrangement remained
        largely the same, with Airbus partners becoming subsidiaries or contractors of the multinational pan-European company. The details vary from one model to
        another, but the general arrangement is for the wings and landing gear to be made in the UK, the tail and doors in Spain, the fuselage in Germany, and the
        nose and centre-section in France, with final assembly in either Toulouse, France; Hamburg, Germany; or Seville, Spain.\n\nWhen Airbus started in 1970, road vehicles were initially used for the movement of components and sections; however, growth in production volume soon
        necessitated a switch to air transport. From 1972 onwards, a fleet of four highly modified \"Super Guppies\" took over. These were former Boeing Stratocruisers
        from the 1940s that had been converted with custom fuselages and the adoption of turbine engines to carry large volume loads for NASA\'s space program in the
        1960s. Airbus\' use of the Super Guppies led to the jest that \"every Airbus is delivered on the wings of a Boeing\". As time went on, the Super Guppies grew
        increasingly unsatisfactory for Airbus\'s ferrying needs: their age meant that operating expenses were high and ever-increasing, and growing Airbus production
        required greater capacity than could be provided by the existing fleet.\n\nVarious options were studied to serve as a replacement transport medium for the Super
        Guppies, including methods of surface transportation by road, rail, and sea; these alternatives were discarded in favor of a principally air-based solution
        as they were considered to have reliability concerns and were time-consuming in operation; in addition, the assembly line in Toulouse was not conveniently
        accessible by any of the surface methods.[6] A key requirement of the new air transporter was the need to accommodate every major component being manufactured
        by Airbus, including the then-heaviest planned part, that being the wing of the larger variants of the Airbus A340.\n\nSeveral different types of aircraft were examined for potential use, including the Antonov An-124, Antonov An-225, Ilyushin Il-86, Boeing 747, Boeing 767,
        Lockheed C-5 Galaxy, and McDonnell Douglas C-17 Globemaster III; the use of any existing aircraft was eventually discounted due to a lack of internal space
        to accommodate the desired components, the use of a piggyback arrangement was also dismissed as impractical. Boeing made their own offer to convert several
        Boeing 767s for the requirement, but this was viewed as inferior to developing a purpose-built aircraft using Airbus\' existing wide-body twin-engined Airbus
        A300-600R instead. In August 1991, Aérospatiale and DASA, two of the major Airbus partners, formed a 50/50 joint venture company, Super Airbus Transport International (SATIC),
        based in Toulouse, France, to develop a new-build replacement for the Super Guppy fleet which eventually led to the development of the Airbus Beluga.\n</string>

    <string name="beluga_desc2" formatted="false">The A300-600ST Beluga shares many design similarities, although substantially differing in appearance, to the Airbus
        A300 upon which it was based. The wings, engines, landing gear, and the lower part of the fuselage remain identical to those used on the conventional A300,
        while the upper part of the fuselage forms an enormous horseshoe-shaped structure 7.7 m in diameter. In comparison with the Super Guppy, the
        payload was more than doubled and the volume increased by more than 30% The General Electric CF6-80C2 turbofan engines used are slightly uprated from
        those used on the standard A300 as well. The vertical stabilizer uses a modified Airbus A340 fin with a 1.12 m base extension while the tailplane was
        strengthened and fitted with auxiliary fins to maintain directional stability. The tailplane trim tank was also deleted.\n\nTo provide access to the cargo area
        from the front without having to disconnect all electrical, hydraulic and flight control connections (and also avoiding the lengthy recalibrations before
        each flight that reconnection entailed), the standard A300 cockpit was relocated down below the cargo-floor level. By relocating the cockpit in this
        manner, loading times were reportedly halved from those encountered using the Super Guppy, which had needed to disconnect and reconnect such systems. Another
        reason for faster loading times was the adoption of a roll-on/roll-off loading system, as well as the ability to unload the aircraft in
        winds of up to 40 knots.\n\nThe cockpit of the Beluga is pressurized but the cargo deck is not, making it inaccessible during flight and unsuitable for cargoes that require a
        pressurized environment, such as live animals. However, the cargo deck is fitted with a heating module to keep the cargo within an appropriate temperature
        range. On at least one occasion, a pressurized container has been used for cargo. The aircraft is operated by a crew of three – two
        pilots and a loadmaster. The main deck cargo volume of the Beluga is greater than that of the C-5 Galaxy or the Antonov An-124 but still smaller
        than Antonov An-225. However, it is restricted by cargo-weight capacity of 47 tonnes, compared to 122.5 tonnes for the C-5 Galaxy and 150 tonnes for
        the An-124. Despite this width, the Beluga cannot carry most fuselage parts of the Airbus A380, which are instead normally transported by ship and road. The
        Beluga has been used to transport some A380 components.\n</string>


    <string name="beluga_specs_constraint">(A300-600ST)\n</string>


    <string name="beluga_identify">How to identify Airbus Beluga?</string>
    <string name="beluga_identify_ans">The Beluga does not need bells and whistles to get attention, it is one of its kind. The Airbus livery gives it away too.</string>

    <string name="beluga_cockpit_value">2</string>
    <string name="beluga_wingspan_value">44.84 m</string>
    <string name="beluga_length_value">56.15 m</string>
    <string name="beluga_height_value">17.24 m</string>
    <string name="beluga_fuselage_value">7.31 m (W) / ~7.5 m (H)</string>
    <string name="beluga_mtow_value">155 t</string>
    <string name="beluga_cruise_speed_value">778 km/h (typical)</string>
    <string name="beluga_range_value">1,501 nmi with 40 t payload /\n2,501 nmi with 26 t payload</string>
    <string name="beluga_thrust_value">257 kN</string>
    <!--AIRBUS BELUGA-->


    <!--AIRBUS A320neo FAMILY-->
    <string name="a320neo_type_value">Narrow-body</string>
    <string name="a320neo_engine_value">CFM LEAP-1A /\nPratt &amp; Whitney PW1100G</string>
    <string name="a320neo_first_flight_value">25 September 2014</string>
    <string name="a320neo_intro_value">25 January 2016\nwith Lufthansa</string>
    <string name="a320neo_customer_value">IndiGo</string>
    <string name="a320neo_variants_value">6 (active)</string>

    <string name="a320neo_desc1" formatted="false">The Airbus A320neo family (neo for new engine option) is a development of the A320 family of narrow-body airliners.
        The A320neo family is based on the previous A319, A320 and A321, which was renamed to A320ceo, for \"current engine option\". Re-engined with CFM LEAP-1A or
        Pratt &amp; Whitney PW1000G engines and fitted with sharklets as standard, it is 15% to 20% more fuel efficient than the A320ceo family. It was launched on
        1 December 2010, made its first flight on 25 September 2014 and was introduced by Lufthansa on 25 January 2016. By 2019, the A320neo had a 60% market share
        against the competing Boeing 737 MAX. As of June 2021, a total of 7,469 A320neo family aircraft had been ordered by more than 115 airlines,
        of which 1,838 aircraft had been delivered.\n\nAirbus launched the sharklet blended wingtip device during the November 2009 Dubai Airshow. The installation
        adds 200 kilograms (440 lb) but offers a 3.5% fuel burn reduction on flights over 2,800 km (1,500 nmi). The neo is 1.8 t heavier than the ceo, but take-off
        and landing performance is the same with a modified rotation law, adjusted wing flap and wing slat angles and rudder deflection increased by 5° to cope with
        the higher thrust. It is also is half as loud as an A320 at take-off, with an 85 decibel noise footprint. The LEAP-powered A321neo has 83.3 dB flyover noise,
        substantially lower than the older CFM56 and V2500 used for most A320ceo family aircraft.\n</string>


    <string name="a320neo_desc2" formatted="false">Compared to the re-engine improvement of 15%, an all-new single-aisle would have brought only 3% more gain while
        high volume manufacturing in carbon fibre could be much more expensive. At the February 2010 Singapore Air Show, Airbus said its decision to launch was scheduled
        for the July 2010 Farnborough Air Show. The decision had still not been taken by August, but the engine choice included the CFM International LEAP-1A and the
        Pratt &amp; Whitney PW1000G, with 20% lower maintenance cost than current A320 engines. The new engines burn 16% less fuel, though the actual gain is slightly less
        as 1–2% is typically lost when installed on an existing aircraft.\n\nThe aircraft family features new "Space-Flex" optional cabin configuration increases
        space-efficiency with a new rear galley configuration and a "Smart-Lav" modular lavatory design – allowing an in-flight change of two lavatories into one
        accessible toilet. The rearranged cabin allows up to 20 more passengers for the A321neo without "putting more sardines in the can" with the larger "Cabin-Flex"
        modified exits described below. Total fuel consumption per seat is reduced by over 20%, while the rearranged cabin allows up to nine more passengers
        for the A320neo. After a year in service, Lufthansa confirmed the 20% efficiency gain per passenger with up to 180 seats, along with reduced noise and CO<sub><small><small>2</small></small></sub>
        emissions. Operators confirm the 15% per seat fuel-burn savings even counterbalanced by the added weight on short sectors, which can rise to 16–17% on longer
        routes and to 20% or more for Lufthansa with 180 passengers up from 168 with two more seat rows. It was Lufthansa again that confirmed the 16% fuel savings
        but had to block the last seating row due to centre-of-gravity concerns.\n</string>

    <string name="a320neo_desc3">\nAirbus offers three variants of the A320neo family: the A319neo, A320neo and A321neo. A neo variant for the Airbus A318 was not
        proposed but could be developed should demand arise. Other variants include A321LR, A321XLR (officially launched at the Paris Air Show on 17 June 2019,
        with deliveries expected from 2023), ACJ319neo and the ACJ320neo as the corporate variants.\n</string>

    <string name="a320neo_specs_constraint">(A319neo, A320neo, A321neo compared in order)\n</string>


    <string name="a320neo_identify">How to identify Airbus A320neo family aircraft?</string>
    <string name="a320neo_identify_ans">\"Notched\" window design, \"bulbous\" nose, 2 dual-wheel main landing gears, engine nacelle with small top/bottom trailing extensions, large L-shaped sharklets.</string>

    <string name="a320neo_cockpit_value">2</string>
    <string name="a320neo_wingspan_value">35.80 m</string>
    <string name="a320neo_length_value">33.84 / 37.57 / 44.51 m</string>
    <string name="a320neo_height_value">11.76 m</string>
    <string name="a320neo_fuselage_value">3.95 m (W) / 4.14 m (H)</string>
    <string name="a320neo_mtow_value">75.5 / 79 / 97 t</string>
    <string name="a320neo_cruise_speed_value">833 km/h (typical),\n876 km/h (max.)</string>
    <string name="a320neo_range_value">3,750 / 3,500 / 4,000 nmi</string>
    <string name="a320neo_thrust_value">107 / 120.6 / 147.3 kN</string>
    <!--AIRBUS A320neo FAMILY-->


    <!--ANTONOV AN-124 RUSLAN-->
    <string name="an124_type_value">Heavy transport</string>
    <string name="an124_engine_value">Progress D-18T</string>
    <string name="an124_first_flight_value">24 December 1982</string>
    <string name="an124_intro_value">1986</string>
    <string name="an124_customer_value">Russian Air Force</string>
    <string name="an124_variants_value">8 (active)</string>

    <string name="an124_desc1" formatted="false">The Antonov An-124 Ruslan is a large, strategic airlift, four-engined aircraft that was designed in the 1980s by
        the Antonov design bureau in the Ukrainian SSR, then part of the Soviet Union (USSR). Until the Boeing 747-8F, the An-124 was, for thirty years, the world\'s
        heaviest gross weight production cargo airplane and second heaviest operating cargo aircraft, behind the one-off Antonov An-225 Mriya (a greatly enlarged
        design based on the An-124). The An-124 remains the largest military transport aircraft in service. During development it was known as Izdeliye 400 (Product #400)
        in house, and An-40 in the West. First flown in 1982, civil certification was issued on 30 December 1992. In July 2013, 26 An-124s were in commercial service with 10 on order. During its production phase from 1982 to 2004, 55 An-124s were built.\n\nDuring the 1970s, the Military Transport Aviation Command
        (Komandovaniye voyenno-transportnoy aviatsii or VTA) arm of the Soviet Air Forces had a shortfall in strategic heavy airlift capacity. Its largest planes
        consisted of about 50 Antonov An-22 turboprops, which were used heavily for tactical roles. A declassified 1975 CIA analysis concluded that the USSR
        did \"…not match the US in ability to provide long-range heavy lift support.\" The An-124 was manufactured in parallel by two plants: the company Aviastar-SP
        (ex. Ulyanovsk Aviation Industrial Complex) in Ulyanovsk, Russia and by the Kyiv Aviation Plant AVIANT, in Ukraine. Design work started in 1971 and construction
        of facilities began in 1973. Manufacturing on the first airframe began in 1979. Ultimately this project brought together over 100 factories contracted to
        produce systems and parts. In the early 2000s, Volga-Dnepr upgraded its freighters with engine improvements to meet Chapter 4 noise regulations, structural
        improvements to increase service life, and avionics and systems changes for four persons operations down from six or seven.\n</string>

    <string name="an124_desc2" formatted="false">Externally, the An-124 is similar to the American Lockheed C-5 Galaxy, having a double fuselage to allow for a rear
        cargo door (on the lower fuselage) that can open in flight without affecting structural integrity. It is slightly shorter, with a slightly greater wingspan,
        and a 17% larger payload. Instead of the Galaxy\'s T-tail, the An-124 uses a conventional empennage, similar in design to that of the Boeing 747.
        The An-124\'s main engine is the Lotarev D-18 (238–250 kN). The aircraft uses oleo strut suspension for its 24 wheels. The suspension has been calibrated to
        allow landing on rough terrain and is able to kneel to allow easier front loading. The plane has an onboard overhead crane capable of lifting up to 30
        tonnes of cargo, and items up to 120 tonnes can be winched on board.\n\nUp to 150 tonnes (150 long tons; 170 short tons) of cargo can be carried in a military
        An-124; it can also carry 88 passengers in an upper deck behind the wing centre section. The cargo compartment of An-124 is 36×6.4×4.4 m (118×21×14 ft), ca.
        20% larger than the main cargo compartment of the C-5 Galaxy, which is 36.91×5.79×4.09 m (121.1×19.0×13.4 ft). Due to limited pressurisation in the
        main cargo compartment (24.6 kPa, 3.57 psi), it seldom carries paratroopers. Pilots have stated that the An-124 is light on the controls and easy to
        handle for an aircraft of its size. Some airports require pavement protection from the heat and blast effects of the An-124\'s 2 TA18-200-124
        auxiliary power units.\n\nAt MAKS Air Show in 2017, the TsAGI announced its An-124-102 Slon (elephant) design to replace the similar An-124-100. The design was
        detailed in January 2019 before wind tunnel testing scheduled for August–September. It is intended to be produced at the Aviastar-SP factory in Ulyanovsk. It
        should transport 150 t (330,000 lb) over 3,800 nmi (7,000 km) (up from 1,675 nmi, 3,102 km), or 180 t (400,000 lb) over 2,650 nmi (4,910 km) at 460 kn (850 km/h). The
        Russian MoD wants a range of 4,100 nmi (7,600 km) with five Sprut-SDM-1 light tanks, their 100 crew and 300 armed soldiers. The planned An-124-102 is larger at
        82.3 m (270 ft) long from 69 m (227 ft), with a 87–88 m (286–290 ft) span versus 73.3 m (240.5 ft) and 24.0 m (78.7 ft) high compared with 21.0 m (68.9 ft).\n\nA
        new higher aspect ratio, composite wing and a 214–222 t (472,000–489,000 lb) airframe would allow a 490–500 t (1,080,000–1,100,000 lb) gross weight. It should
        be powered by Russian PD-35s developed for the CR929 widebody, producing 35 tf (77,000 lbf) up from 23 tf (51,000 lbf). Two fuselages are planned, one for
        Volga-Dnepr with a width of 5.3 m (17.4 ft) from the An-124\'s 4.4 m (14.4 ft), and one for the Russian MoD of 6.4 m (21 ft) wide to carry vehicles in two lines. By
        November 2019, the TsAGI had shown a 1.63 m (5 ft 4 in) long and 1.75 m (5 ft 9 in) wide model, ahead of windtunnel testing.\n</string>

    <string name="an124_desc3">\nAntonov An-124 variants include An-124 Ruslan (strategic heavy airlift transport aircraft), An-124-100 (commercial transport aircraft),
        An-124-100M-150, An-124-102, An-124-115M, An-124-130 (proposed), An-124-135, An-124-150, An-124-200 (proposed), An-124-210 (joint proposal with Air Foyle), and
        An-124-300\n</string>

    <string name="an124_specs_constraint">(-100M variant)\n</string>


    <string name="an124_identify">How to identify Antonov An-124 Ruslan?</string>
    <string name="an124_identify_ans"></string>

    <string name="an124_cockpit_value">6</string>
    <string name="an124_wingspan_value">73.3 m</string>
    <string name="an124_length_value">69.1 m</string>
    <string name="an124_height_value">21.08 m</string>
    <string name="an124_gross_weight_value">214 t with max. fuel</string>
    <string name="an124_mtow_value">402 t</string>
    <string name="an124_cruise_speed_value">800–850 km/h (typical),\n865 km/h (max.)</string>
    <string name="an124_range_value">2,000 nmi (max. payload) /\n6,200 nmi (40 t payload)</string>
    <string name="an124_thrust_value">229 kN</string>
    <!--ANTONOV AN-124 RUSLAN-->


    <string name="status_listening">LISTENING…</string>
    <string name="status_processing">PROCESSING…</string>
    <string name="status_speaking">SPEAKING…</string>
    <string name="fragment_action_send_audio">Send Audio</string>
    <string name="action_send_audio_description">Press the microphone to start recording. Recording will end either when pressed again or end of speech detected.\n\n\nSending audio can be very efficient if using the DataRequestBody option, since it can write to the POST while the audio is still being recorded, giving the impression of a very fast response. This can also be used to prepend or append audio to a recorded stream, if you wanted to limit the control to a single skill: "Open Hey Dad and ask for a joke about…" followed by the joke type..</string>


    <string name="login">Login with Amazon</string>
    <string name="instruction">Press Alexa button and start talking. The recorder will stop automatically or press the button again to manually stop it</string>
    <string name="close">Got it</string>
    <string name="title_activity_maps">Map</string>

    <string name="map_loading1">Pushback</string>
    <string name="map_loading2">Taxiing</string>
    <string name="map_loading3">Buckle up, taking off soon</string>
    <string name="connection_timed_out">Oops connection timed out</string>
    <string name="retry">Retry</string>

    <string name="loading">Loading</string>

    <string name="aircraft">Aircraft</string>
    <string name="airline">Airline</string>
    <string name="engine_type">Engine type</string>
    <string name="country">Country of reg.</string>
    <string name="callsign">Callsign</string>
    <string name="icao">ICAO 24-bit address</string>
    <string name="geo_altitude">Geometric altitude</string>
    <string name="baro_altitude">Barometric altitude</string>
    <string name="velocity">Velocity</string>
    <string name="vertical_rate">Vertical speed</string>
    <string name="latitude">Latitude</string>
    <string name="longitude">Longitude</string>
    <string name="on_ground">On Ground</string>
    <string name="track">Track</string>
    <string name="squawk">Squawk</string>
    <string name="pos_source">Position source</string>
    <string name="spi">Special Purpose Indicator</string>
    <string name="live">LIVE</string>
    <string name="not_true">False</string>
    <string name="_true">True</string>


    <string name="drawer_airplane">&#xe902;</string>
    <string name="drawer_radar">&#xe901;</string>
    <string name="drawer_alexa">&#xe904;</string>
    <string name="drawer_tail">&#xe900;</string>
    <string name="drawer_manufacturer">&#xe907;</string>
    <string name="drawer_firebase">&#xe907;</string>

</resources>